<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-06-27T00:36:48.178Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-06-27T00:36:48.178Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to photograph a full moon on your phone or camera with the best settings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/strawberry-moon-2021-june-australia-how-to-photograph-full-super-moon-with-phone-tonight-take-picture-supermoon-photography-what-time-when-thursday-night-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/strawberry-moon-2021-june-australia-how-to-photograph-full-super-moon-with-phone-tonight-take-picture-supermoon-photography-what-time-when-thursday-night-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T23:53:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Australia picture editor Carly Earl explains the dos and don’ts of taking pictures of the moon
When a full moon rises, many people will pull out their mobile phones to try and get an Instagram-worthy photograph, but unfortunately it’s really challenging to take a great picture of the moon.
Two reasons: it is very far away and unless you have a telephoto lens (which makes the moon appear closer than it is) it will always appear as a very small glowing dot in the frame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carly Earl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom 3D Printer Cart Hides Clever Features]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=483636</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/06/26/custom-3d-printer-cart-hides-clever-features/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T23:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even if you’ve got a decent sized workshop, there’s only so much stuff you can have sitting on the bench at one time. That’s why [Eric Strebel], ever the prolific …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Nardi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[LoRa Messenger in Nokia’s Shell]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=483468</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/06/26/lora-messenger-in-nokias-shell/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The arrival of LoRa a few years ago gave  us at last an accessible licence-free UHF communication protocol with significant range. It’s closed-source, but there are plenty of modules available …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenny List</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Pico Oscilloscope]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=483675</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/06/26/raspberry-pi-pico-oscilloscope/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T17:01:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As you dive deeper into the world of electronics, a good oscilloscope quickly is an indispensable tool. However, for many use cases where you’re debugging low voltage, low speed circuits, …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Danie Conradie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memo to corporate leaders post-Covid: the disruption to businesses has only just begun | John Naughton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/memo-to-corporate-leaders-post-covid-the-disruption-to-businesses-has-only-just-begun</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/memo-to-corporate-leaders-post-covid-the-disruption-to-businesses-has-only-just-begun"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Managerial hierarchies must learn the true lessons of the pandemic if they are to survive and thrive
Pandemics, the historian Yuval Noah Harari has observed, have a way of accelerating history. Just ask the founders of Zoom. Only two years ago, we were all thinking that it would take at least another decade before video-conferencing became an integral part of the way we work in organisations. Then along comes Covid and in three weeks we’re all happily Zooming (or unhappily in the case of Handforth parish council). And now we’re more or less acclimatised or, at any rate, resigned to the idea that remote meetings might be here to stay.
The problem with having had the fast-forward button suddenly propel us into an unexpected place, though, is that we find ourselves unmoored. We start wondering about what lies ahead as the immediate threat of the virus recedes. What will our post-pandemic future be like? In relation to work, three main possibilities are currently taking up all the airtime: continuing to work from home (WFH); a hybrid mode in which we spend some time in the office but also two or three days WFH; and a return to ye olde days commuting to the office to gather round the water cooler and pretend to be doing something useful.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Did I Live Without a Microscope?]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=484370</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/06/26/how-did-i-live-without-a-microscope/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T14:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Get yourself a decent stereo inspection microscope, preferably optical. Something that can magnify from maybe 4x to 40x is fine, anything outside this range is icing on the cake. Some …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elliot Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plant These Hay-Fever-Friendly Flowers to Cut Down on Summer Sneezing]]></title>
        <id>1847170969</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/plant-these-hay-fever-friendly-flowers-to-cut-down-on-s-1847170969"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Allergies are, quite literally, irritating. They turn what’s supposed to be your serene outdoor space into a sneeze-inducing hellscape. In the United States, approximately 19.2 million adults and 5.2 million children have allergic rhinitis—better known as hay fever, according to the Asthma and Allergy Foundation of…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use This Site to Find the Cheapest and Fastest Way to Send a Package]]></title>
        <id>1847170955</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/use-this-site-to-find-the-cheapest-and-fastest-way-to-s-1847170955"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Unless your job involves a lot of shipping, it can be hard to know which service best suits your needs—and your budget. Maybe UPS is cheaper in some parts of the country than others for the type of package you need to send. Or perhaps FedEx has better rates on overnight shipping to your destination. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Paid $1,000 for Submitting a Photo of Your Most Impressive DIY Creation]]></title>
        <id>1847170943</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/get-paid-1-000-for-submitting-a-photo-of-your-most-imp-1847170943"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now that we’re out and about again, we may be spending less time on home improvement projects—especially compared to the past year-and-a-half. Being stuck at home all the time with very few socialization options gave us the time to devote to our living spaces, and get some of those tasks that had been hanging over our…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can the Solenoid Engine Power a Car?]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=483592</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/06/26/can-the-solenoid-engine-power-a-car/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T11:01:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[[Emiel] aka [The Practical Engineer] makes all kinds of fun projects in his fully-featured shop, and one of his tangents has been building a series of solenoid engines. These engines …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bryan Cockfield</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Numbers From A Smoke Detector]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=483535</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/06/26/random-numbers-from-a-smoke-detector/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T08:01:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The quest for truly random numbers is something to which scientists and engineers have devoted a lot of time and effort. The trick is to find an unpredictable source of …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenny List</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I spy: are smart doorbells creating a global surveillance network?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/i-spy-are-smart-doorbells-creating-a-global-surveillance-network</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/26/i-spy-are-smart-doorbells-creating-a-global-surveillance-network"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T07:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[They were sold as gadgets that meant you would never miss a delivery. But now doorbell cameras – from Amazon’s Ring to Google’s Nest – are recording our every move
I have got a new doorbell. It’s brilliant. It should be; it cost £89. It’s a Ring video doorbell; you’ll have seen them around. There are others available, made by other companies, with other four-letter names such as Nest and Arlo. When someone rings my doorbell, I’m alerted on my smartphone. I can see who is there, and speak to them.
My phone is ringing! C major first inversion chord, arpeggiated, repeated, for the musically trained – you’ll recognise it if you’ve heard it. It’s a delivery. Amazon, as it happens; Amazon acquired Ring in 2018, reportedly for more than $1bn.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Wollaston</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[PiNet — One Small Project Grows Unexpectedly]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=483617</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/06/25/pinet-one-small-project-grows-unexpectedly/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T05:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few years ago, [Gregory Sanders] aka [Dr Gerg] had one simple wish in mind when he started what is now the PiNet project — to know whether his garage …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Chris Lott</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Difference Between Terracotta, Ceramic, and Plastic Pots, and Why It Matters to Your Plants]]></title>
        <id>1847176578</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-difference-between-terracotta-ceramic-and-plastic-1847176578"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Different pots have different uses for your home plants and planters. Plants behave differently in plastic containers than they do in glazed ceramic pots, and each pot has its own set of care instructions. So what is the difference between these various pots and planters? It comes down to breathability and moisture…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use 'Self-Determination Theory' to Motivate Others]]></title>
        <id>1847173631</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/use-self-determination-theory-to-motivate-others-1847173631"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You probably know what it’s like to have a bad boss. You might even know what it’s like to be one. Certainly at work (and if life) nobody likes a micromanager, but a boss who can’t be bothered to actually lead the team or  check-in with their direct reports is just as bad. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Blum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FFS, Put Some Weight on the Bar]]></title>
        <id>1847176087</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/put-some-fucking-weight-on-the-bar-1847176087"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The point of lifting weights is to challenge your body, such that your body rises to the challenge by building muscle. The more you lift, the stronger you get. And yet, too many people get talked out of ever putting some fucking weight on the bar. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Island Vacations Where You Won't Need a Passport]]></title>
        <id>1847174446</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/15-island-vacations-where-you-wont-need-a-passport-1847174446"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not many people first think of the United States when it comes to planning a relaxing island getaway—the thought of an island vacation might instead conjure images of a tropical beach in the Caribbean or the south of France. That’s fair; but there are several island destinations right here in the United States worth…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blend Two Pink Liqueurs Into a Campberry Cooler]]></title>
        <id>1847174411</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/blend-two-pink-liqueurs-into-a-campberry-cooler-1847174411"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A couple of weeks ago, I picked a flat of Hood strawberries. Hoods are  sweet, delicate, and prone to going bad before you can process them all. So I utilized my usual strategy of drinking through my berry haul.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[22 History Facts You Didn't Learn in School, According to Reddit]]></title>
        <id>1847173167</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/22-history-facts-you-didnt-learn-in-school-according-t-1847173167"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Where do you go to find surprising true facts from history, backed up by solid sources and told with nuance? You may be shocked to hear the answer is: Reddit. The sub called r/AskHistorians specializes in exactly this, with experts writing in-depth answers to questions about any area of history. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Way to Pack a Cooler]]></title>
        <id>1844605820</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-best-way-to-pack-a-cooler-1844605820"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T16:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are few things more disappointing in the height of summer than pulling a lukewarm beer or spoiled food out of your cooler. Truly keeping food and beverages cold in very hot weather may seem like an impossible task, but it can be done if you pack your cooler strategically. Here’s how to do it.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Long</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google starts warning users if search results are likely to be poor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/25/google-starts-warning-users-if-search-results-are-likely-to-be-poor</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/25/google-starts-warning-users-if-search-results-are-likely-to-be-poor"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T16:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New message warns that results are ‘changing quickly’ and may not yet include reliable sources
Google has started warning users when they search for a topic that is likely to have poor results, as part of its effort to tackle “data voids” on the search engine.
The new warning was spotted by Renee DiResta, an academic who studies misinformation at Stanford University. “It looks like these results are changing quickly,” Google will now caution users. “If this topic is new, it can sometimes take time for results to be added by reliable sources.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern UK technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chicken Poop Is Really Useful, Actually]]></title>
        <id>1847165526</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/chicken-shit-is-really-useful-actually-1847165526"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This past spring, I set out to design and maintain a sustainable garden in my backyard—and a big part of that project has involved using chickens to fertilize my soil and help process my compost pile. All of their pecking, scratching, and depleting the backyard of its resources can be redirected and contained to one…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Therese McPherson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[13 Smarter Ways to Make Killer Deviled Eggs]]></title>
        <id>1847167171</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/13-smarter-ways-to-make-killer-deviled-eggs-1847167171"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If I had to pick a favorite BBQ appetizer, it would probably be deviled eggs. They are savory, the perfect size, and have a decidedly retro feel that I find incredibly charming. They’re also an incredibly easy dish, but one that is riddled with pitfalls, especially if you’ve never been “in charge” of the deviled eggs…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft to let developers keep all their Windows app store revenue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/25/microsoft-let-developers-keep-all-windows-app-store-revenue</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/25/microsoft-let-developers-keep-all-windows-app-store-revenue"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T15:48:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Change affecting all firms apart from game developers will increase pressure on Apple and Google
Microsoft will no longer force companies to pay it a cut of their revenue if they want a place on the Windows app store, the company has announced, in a move calculated to increase the regulatory pressure on Apple and Google’s mobile duopoly.
As part of the shift to Windows 11, unveiled on Thursday, the company will allow developers to use their own payment systems on apps they sell through the Windows store. Those who do will not have to pay a penny to Microsoft.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern  UK technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get macOS 12's Safari Interface on macOS 11]]></title>
        <id>1847173289</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-get-macos-12s-safari-interface-on-macos-11-1847173289"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apple’s Safari browser will get a visual overhaul as part of the upcoming macOS 12 Monterey update launching later this year, and there are a couple of ways to try out the new browser ahead of the macOS 12 update, including a way to get it now on macOS 11.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Hesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Stop Looking at Your Ex’s Social Media]]></title>
        <id>1847170738</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-stop-looking-at-your-ex-s-social-media-1847170738"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After a breakup, you might find yourself compelled to look at your ex’s Instagram (or Facebook or Venmo or LinkedIn…). Ideally, you’ll see them doing badly and you might feel victorious, although you know that’s not true: Most people don’t post their low moments online. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Ellefson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Out-of-Touch Adults' Guide To Kid Culture: When Will Britney Spears Be Free?]]></title>
        <id>1847170751</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-out-of-touch-adults-guide-to-kid-culture-when-will-1847170751"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week covers the whole spectrum of kid-internet-culture, from Britney Spears stuck in a conservatorship, to a movie about family stuck next to the ultimate Karen, to a TikTok lady who got stuck in her own chair. Let’s dive in—here’s what you need to know.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SACP picket in Western Cape calls for inquiry into “the rot within the police”]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/sacp-picket-in-western-cape-calling-for-inquiry-into-the-rot-within-the-police/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/sacp-picket-in-western-cape-calling-for-inquiry-into-the-rot-within-the-police/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:19:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The party says the public have lost all confidence and trust in the police]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Anger over exclusion of ECD centres from teacher vaccinations]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/anger-over-exclusion-early-childhood-development-centres-teacher-vaccinations/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/anger-over-exclusion-early-childhood-development-centres-teacher-vaccinations/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:16:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Early childhood development centre owners say they are “the forgotten sector”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Have I gone too far in monitoring my children’s online activity? | Annalisa Barbieri]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/25/have-i-gone-too-far-in-monitoring-my-childrens-online-activity</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/25/have-i-gone-too-far-in-monitoring-my-childrens-online-activity"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At this stage, being a parent is more about negotiation and trust, says Annalisa Barbieri. Sit down as a family and talk about it – make rules together
I have two children, aged nine and 11. We’ve always limited their tech but just before the pandemic, we bought them tablets to give them access to education, entertainment and their friends. Then I became concerned about their increasing use and placed more limits on screen time.
Full disclosure: I am a phone addict. So I introduced a rule where we all put our devices in a box when we aren’t using them (I break this rule most). During the last lockdown, we got my older child a phone. She had already asked for TikTok – her friends all had it, but I refused because it has all sorts of age-inappropriate stuff. However, that was how her friends communicated, so I allowed it as long as it was a private account on my device, so I could monitor it and her messages. She agreed to this reluctantly. I know I need to step back, but how do I do that without neglecting my duties as a parent?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Annalisa Barbieri</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When to See Mercury With Your Naked Eyes This July]]></title>
        <id>1847167734</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/when-to-see-mercury-with-your-naked-eyes-this-july-1847167734"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With all of the celestial events coming this summer, we can safely rebrand the next few months Big Planet Season. All of this year’s supermoons have come and gone, but the cosmic gifts dotting the calendar are a bit more mysterious and striking than the moon: Some of the solar system’s biggest and most distant planets…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Blum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[25 of the Best First Films in Movie History]]></title>
        <id>1847165193</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/25-of-the-most-iconic-directorial-debuts-in-movie-histo-1847165193"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It takes a rare sort of artistic genius to create a masterpiece on your first try. Whatever type of art we’re talking about, there is of course nothing wrong with fumbling around in the dark in search of greatness. Certainly the cinema is no different—the careers of many of history’s most revered film directors…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ross Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Difference Between Ragweed and Goldenrod, and What It Means for Your Allergies]]></title>
        <id>1847168303</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-difference-between-ragweed-and-goldenrod-and-what-1847168303"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There has been a lot of talk about the healing power of nature—between forest bathing, fresh air, and all kinds of “wellness” retreats—but people with hay fever may have a slightly different take on the great outdoors. Namely: It can be difficult to really appreciate nature when so much of it makes your eyes water…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng families huddle around fire at night without food or sufficient shelter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/tsakane-families-huddle-around-fire-night-without-food-or-sufficient-shelter/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/tsakane-families-huddle-around-fire-night-without-food-or-sufficient-shelter/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T10:23:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ekurhuleni spokesperson says they were evicted because their occupation was illegal but admits housing backlog was “not being eradicated at the pace the homeless community would like to see”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon and Google investigated by UK regulator over fake reviews]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/25/amazon-and-google-investigated-by-uk-regulator-over-fake-reviews</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jun/25/amazon-and-google-investigated-by-uk-regulator-over-fake-reviews"/>
        <updated>2021-06-25T07:44:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CMA will decide whether consumer law was broken by not taking sufficient action to protect shoppers
Amazon and Google are to be investigated by the UK competition watchdog over concerns the tech companies have not done enough to tackle the widespread problem of fake reviews on their websites.
The Competition and Markets Authority, which began looking at the issue of fake reviews on major platforms two years ago, will now consider whether Amazon and Google have broken consumer law by not taking sufficient action to protect shoppers from fake reviews.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘They can’t do it without us’: Black TikTokers strike to protest dance appropriation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/tiktok-strike-black-creators-megan-thee-stallion-dance</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/tiktok-strike-black-creators-megan-thee-stallion-dance"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T23:37:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some refuse to choreograph Megan Thee Stallion song, highlighting how white users get credit for Black creativity
A number of Black creators on TikTok are on indefinite “strike”, refusing to choreograph dances on the app to protest against the appropriation of their content by white users.
The action has been focused on Megan Thee Stallion’s new song Thot Shit, which was released last week. There are 168,000 videos on TikTok using the song as of Thursday afternoon, but unlike WAP – Stallion and Cardi B’s last viral song – there is not a single trending dance to it. And that is deliberate, some creators say.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[These Are the Only Two Ways to Actually Keep Mosquitoes Away]]></title>
        <id>1844224273</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/to-keep-mosquitoes-away-do-these-two-things-1844224273"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People hate mosquitoes, and so companies make a lot of anti-mosquito things: candles, wristbands, chemical and herbal sprays—even electronic devices. But if you want to keep mosquitoes off your bare skin this summer, you really just need two things: bug spray and a fan. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Update Your Snapchat Password Immediately]]></title>
        <id>1847167673</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/update-your-snapchat-password-immediately-1847167673"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Snapchat users have bombarded with repeated, unexpected two-factor authentication (2FA) text messages  this week, but it’s unclear whether the cause is due to a glitch on Snapchat’s end, or due to hackers attempting to break into unsecured Snapchat accounts en masse. Either way, it’s not a bad idea to update your…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Hesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Do I Share Space With Someone I Hate?]]></title>
        <id>1847165152</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-do-i-share-space-with-someone-i-hate-1847165152"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not all advice need be professional. Sometimes your problems merit a bit of unvarnished honesty from a dude equipped with nothing more than a computer and a conscience. Luckily for you, I’m that guy. Welcome back to Tough Love. (If you’d like to seek my advice, email me at sblum@lifehacker.com)

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Blum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Upgrade Your Old Two-Prong Electrical Sockets to Three-Prong Outlets]]></title>
        <id>1847166279</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-upgrade-your-old-two-prong-electrical-sockets-to-1847166279"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Homes built before the 1960s had different electrical regulations than we do now—including the fact that two-prong outlets were standard, rather than the average three-prong ones we typically see today. The third hole in our outlets basically helps protect against electrical surges and shock, and while two-pronged…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's New on Amazon Prime Video in July 2021]]></title>
        <id>1847166244</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/whats-new-on-amazon-prime-video-in-july-2021-1847166244"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Summer 2021 is shaping up to be a lot better than summer 2020, vaccines be praised (yay science!), but you’ll be forgiven if you’re not ready to head back to theaters to catch a splashy summer blockbuster. Speaking of which, they’re in short supply anyway—outside of a few delayed tentpoles from last year (including …
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Cunningham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Billionaire Peter Thiel amasses $5bn tax-free nest egg in retirement account]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/billionaire-peter-thiel-5bn-tax-free-savings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/billionaire-peter-thiel-5bn-tax-free-savings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:22:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[•  ProPublica reveals files on other billionaires’ tax-free savings
• Roth IRAs were originally intended for middle-class Americans
Billionaire Peter Thiel, one of the founders of PayPal, has used a retirement account designed to help ordinary Americans save for their golden years to amass a $5bn tax-free nest egg, according to records obtained by ProPublica.
Thiel, a vocal opponent of higher taxes, is one of a number of ultra-rich Americans to use a Roth individual retirement account (IRA) to amass a tax-free fortune.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Tickets Now For The Make: Education Forum]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/24/get-tickets-now-for-the-make-education-forum/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/24/get-tickets-now-for-the-make-education-forum/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:18:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The growth of makerspaces in education was interrupted by the shutdown of schools, libraries, and museums over the last year.  Now, as students return to in-person learning, there is an even greater need for maker educators who can provide hands-on making and project-based learning experiences. In addition, making is a practice that can be learned […]
The post Get Tickets Now For The Make: Education Forum appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Keep Your Kid Occupied at the Doctor's Office Without Handing Them a Screen]]></title>
        <id>1847165849</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-keep-your-kid-occupied-at-the-doctors-office-wit-1847165849"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A thing that’s not fun to do when you’re a parent is take your young children to the pediatrician’s office. There are endless reasons why the doctor’s office isn’t fun—it means your kid is hurt, sick, or has some freaky-looking rash; it’s an annual check-up, which might mean shots are in their future; your kid will…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Meghan Moravcik Walbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows 11: Microsoft revamps start menu and adds Android apps]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/windows-11-microsoft-revamps-start-menu-and-adds-android-apps</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/windows-11-microsoft-revamps-start-menu-and-adds-android-apps"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:52:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New version of PC software unveiled with fresh design, faster performance, longer battery life and more open store
Microsoft has unveiled Windows 11 as it seeks to modernise the world’s most popular desktop software, add Android apps and improve gaming without alienating users.
Announced during a livestream that had some technical issues, Windows 11 will replace Windows 10 and marks the biggest change to the 35-year-old operating system since 2015.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Check Your Fridge for These Recalled Vegan Egg Products]]></title>
        <id>1847165122</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/check-your-fridge-for-these-recalled-vegan-egg-products-1847165122"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between vegans and people with egg allergies, chicken eggs aren’t an option for everyone, and that’s where plant-based egg products comes in. But if you happen to have some in your fridge, it’s a good idea to check the label, because there’s been a large voluntary recall of foods made with the vegan egg-flavored…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Letter: Michael Parsons obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/letter-michael-parsons-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/letter-michael-parsons-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T15:38:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Michael Parsons was the best boss a young engineer could have. When asked for help on a complex problem, he would say, “Let’s go back to first principles,” and break the problem down into parts that could be analysed simply.
With typical self-deprecation, he later said that he took this approach because he had a poor memory for more complex solutions. However, it ensured that advanced computer calculations for his cutting-edge bridge designs were always carefully “sense checked”, with the practicalities of construction taken into account.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alasdair Beal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng sewage has shown high rates of Covid-19 for three weeks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/covid-19-poo-surveillance-covid-19-third-wave-in-gauteng/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/covid-19-poo-surveillance-covid-19-third-wave-in-gauteng/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Other hotspots are Gqeberha and Cape Town]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Limpopo villagers have to buy their drinking water]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/limpopo-villagers-have-buy-their-drinking-water/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/limpopo-villagers-have-buy-their-drinking-water/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T11:16:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Taps stopped working in Mabendenge five years ago]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Covid-19 vaccines should be compulsory]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/why-covid-19-vaccines-should-be-compulsory/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/why-covid-19-vaccines-should-be-compulsory/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T10:33:41.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mystery of the wheelie suitcase: how gender stereotypes held back the history of invention]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/mystery-of-wheelie-suitcase-how-gender-stereotypes-held-back-history-of-invention</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jun/24/mystery-of-wheelie-suitcase-how-gender-stereotypes-held-back-history-of-invention"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why have some brilliant innovations – from rolling luggage to electric cars – taken so long to come to market? Macho culture has a lot to answer for
In 1972 an American luggage executive unscrewed four castors from a wardrobe and fixed them to a suitcase. Then he put a strap on his contraption and trotted it gleefully around his house.
This was how Bernard Sadow invented the world’s first rolling suitcase. It happened roughly 5,000 years after the invention of the wheel and barely one year after Nasa managed to put two men on the surface of the moon using the largest rocket ever built. We had driven an electric rover with wheels on a foreign heavenly body and even invented the hamster wheel. So why did it take us so long to put wheels on suitcases? This has become something of a classic mystery of innovation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Katrine Marçal</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protesters open assault case, alleging municipal official pepper-sprayed them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/protesters-open-assault-case-allege-municipal-official-pepper-sprayed-them/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/protesters-open-assault-case-allege-municipal-official-pepper-sprayed-them/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T08:03:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protesting unemployed security guards were demanding jobs with the Nelson Mandela Bay municipality]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[E3 2021: 20 games to watch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/24/e3-2021-20-best-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/24/e3-2021-20-best-games"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T08:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year’s all-digital video game expo involved a deluge of livestreams showcasing upcoming excitements. Here are our picks
The chaotic mini-game series is making a really welcome return, this time featuring two-player co-op. The new vignette challenges range from avoiding bird plops to tweaking someone’s nipple hair. Classic Wario.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[John McAfee: the tech pioneer turned fugitive]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/24/john-mcafee-the-tech-pioneer-turned-fugitive</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/24/john-mcafee-the-tech-pioneer-turned-fugitive"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T04:57:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Founder of McAfee Associates went on the run in 2012 after his Belize neighbour was shot dead

John McAfee: antivirus entrepreneur found dead in Spanish prison

John McAfee, the creator of a programme that is among the most-used virus protection programmes worldwide, was a controversial figure, cryptocurrency promoter, tax opponent and fugitive who twice made long-shot runs for the US presidency. 
He publicly embraced drugs, guns and sex, and had a history of legal woes spanning from Tennessee to Central America to the Caribbean.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Sullivan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cancer patients say they are struggling to access treatment since Charlotte Maxeke fire]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/cancer-patients-struggling-april-access-treatment-charlotte-maxeke-hospital-fire/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/cancer-patients-struggling-april-access-treatment-charlotte-maxeke-hospital-fire/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T01:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Oncology outpatients try their luck at Chris Hani Baragwanath]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Greta Lee Jackson: the 10 funniest things I have ever seen on the internet]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/24/greta-lee-jackson-the-10-funniest-things-i-have-ever-seen-on-the-internet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/24/greta-lee-jackson-the-10-funniest-things-i-have-ever-seen-on-the-internet"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T17:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We ask connoisseurs of comedy to provide a tasting plate from the smorgasbord of laughs. Greta Lee Jackson serves up this one
Hello! I’m Greta Lee Jackson. You might know me from being in my activewear or having a massive go at celebrities during the pandemic. I’m a comedy content maker, meaning I try to make funny clips for TV and the internet. Having said that, I’m fairly confident that nothing I make will ever come close to the level of comedy that the following pieces of content achieve. I will forever be in awe of them, hauling them out whenever times get tough and I need cheering up, or I need inspiration, or just fancy feeling like an abject failure at my chosen profession.
 Related: Alex Gallagher: the 10 funniest things I have ever seen (on the internet) 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Greta Lee Jackson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing The Winners Of Our “May The 4th” Cosplay and Droid Contest]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/23/announcing-the-winners-of-our-may-the-4th-cosplay-and-droid-contest/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/23/announcing-the-winners-of-our-may-the-4th-cosplay-and-droid-contest/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T14:46:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When we announced our Star Wars themed contest, along with NVIDIA, we knew we were going to be in for a difficult time deciding on a winner. There are so many great projects out there with incredible documentation and stunning results! We were not let down by the entries. If you haven’t checked them out […]
The post Announcing The Winners Of Our “May The 4th” Cosplay and Droid Contest appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweat review – the loneliness of the social media influencer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/23/sweat-review-the-loneliness-of-the-social-media-influencer-magdalena-kolesnik</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/23/sweat-review-the-loneliness-of-the-social-media-influencer-magdalena-kolesnik"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Magnus von Horn’s contrived Polish drama about a fitness guru promises more in shock and character than it delivers
In theory, it should be possible to create a drama about a social media influencer and motivational fitness celebrity that isn’t all about the hidden loneliness and shame of her shallow existence. It should be possible to show such a person being a huge hit in public and perfectly content in private. But this movie from Poland-based Swedish director Magnus von Horn pretty much goes for route one, and despite some interesting touches, it promises much more in terms of shock and character insight than it ever really delivers, with some contrived and unconvincing plot transitions.
Sylwia (Magdalena Koleśnik) has 600,000 followers for the Instagram account on which she obsessively posts, detailing every aspect of her day as a successful single woman, running colossally popular fitness events with her beefcake male assistant Klaudiusz (Julian Świeżewski). He clearly has a major thing for her, though at one crucial moment he shows a very implausible kind of restraint. She is living in a sleek apartment with her adorable dog, Jackson; there’s a new fitness DVD out and everything seems to be going well.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 15 greatest video games of the 1990s – ranked!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/23/the-15-greatest-video-games-of-the-1990s-ranked</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/23/the-15-greatest-video-games-of-the-1990s-ranked"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T10:45:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was the decade Sonic the Hedgehog, the original PlayStation, the Nintendo 64 and so much more entered the world – here are the 15 best games of this golden age of gaming
Of all LucasArts’ memorable, quip-fuelled point and click adventures – from dark afterlife comedy Grim Fandango to the surrealist Day of the Tentacle – it’s Monkey Island 2 that gets the most love nowadays, and justifiably so. The puzzles were just on the right side of deliberately obscure, the characters were strange and colourful, and the music unforgettable. And that ending still sparks discussion, 30 years on.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald and Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The EFF wants us to use the Russian and Chinese vaccines. But there are unanswered questions about them]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/eff-wants-us-use-russian-and-chinese-vaccines-there-are-unanswered-questions-about-them/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/eff-wants-us-use-russian-and-chinese-vaccines-there-are-unanswered-questions-about-them/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T08:31:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The regulatory authority must act in the public interest and not be swayed by undue pressure]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“We don’t have anywhere else to go” says Johannesburg occupier]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/we-dont-have-anywhere-else-to-go-says-johannesburg-occupier/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/we-dont-have-anywhere-else-to-go-says-johannesburg-occupier/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T08:13:01.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eviction case pending against Rosettenville families while City asked to provide emergency accommodation]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cloud spraying and hurricane slaying: how ocean geoengineering became the frontier of the climate crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/23/cloud-spraying-and-hurricane-slaying-could-geoengineering-fix-the-climate-crisis</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2021/jun/23/cloud-spraying-and-hurricane-slaying-could-geoengineering-fix-the-climate-crisis"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T05:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Around the world, dozens of ingenious projects are trying to ‘trick’ the ocean into absorbing more CO2. But critics warn of unforeseen consequences
Tom Green has a plan to tackle climate change. The British biologist and director of the charity Project Vesta wants to turn a trillion tonnes of CO2 into rock, and sink it to the bottom of the sea.
Green admits the idea is “audacious”. It would involve locking away atmospheric carbon by dropping pea-coloured sand into the ocean. The sand is made of ground olivine – an abundant volcanic rock, known to jewellers as peridot – and, if Green’s calculations are correct, depositing it offshore on 2% of the world’s coastlines would capture 100% of total global annual carbon emissions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Fleming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[17 Top Container Garden Flowers For Stunning Summer Pots]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34374</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/container-flowers/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T18:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Container gardening flowers are a must for outdoor summer planters. Whether you’re looking to fill hanging baskets, window boxes, small, or a large pots, you’ll find tons of options on this list of the best flowers for container gardening. One of the most fun things to do in the spring is picking out flowers forContinue Reading
The post 17 Top Container Garden Flowers For Stunning Summer Pots appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unemployed security guards shut down municipal customer care centre]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/unemployed-security-guards-shut-down-municipal-customer-care-centre/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/unemployed-security-guards-shut-down-municipal-customer-care-centre/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[They have been demanding municipal jobs since 2019]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“I grabbed my son and a suitcase packed with clothes” says fire victim describing a chaotic scene]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/i-grabbed-my-son-and-a-suitcase-packed-with-clothes-says-fire-victim-describing-chaotic-scene/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/i-grabbed-my-son-and-a-suitcase-packed-with-clothes-says-fire-victim-describing-chaotic-scene/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T14:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 50 Capetonians have been left in the rain with nowhere to sleep tonight]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vaccine registration system cannot work in rural areas, says doctor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/vaccine-registration-system-cannot-work-rural-areas-says-doctor/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/vaccine-registration-system-cannot-work-rural-areas-says-doctor/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T13:06:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Logistics of rollout need to be simpler in the Eastern Cape]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 years later government still “discussing” Basic Income Grant]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/20-years-later-government-still-discussing-basic-income-grant/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/20-years-later-government-still-discussing-basic-income-grant/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T10:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even as the push for a comprehensive grant gathers pace, civil society organisations doubt the political will is there]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teacher “temporarily removed” after sexual assault allegation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/teacher-temporarily-removed-following-allegation-of-sexually-assaulting-learners/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/teacher-temporarily-removed-following-allegation-of-sexually-assaulting-learners/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T08:35:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng education department is investigating following protests by parents]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Source Hardware Certifications for May 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/21/open-source-hardware-certifications-for-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/21/open-source-hardware-certifications-for-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In May 2021 the Open Source Hardware Association (OSHWA) certified a wide variety of hardware as open source.  we will have a certified variety collection of Open Source Hardwares, Let’s take a look! (And remember, certification is a free and easy way to show that your hardware complies with the open source hardware definition.) First, […]
The post Open Source Hardware Certifications for May 2021 appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 finally launched on PlayStation 4]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/21/cyberpunk-2077-finally-launched-on-playstation-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/21/cyberpunk-2077-finally-launched-on-playstation-4"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T12:33:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The troubled sci-fi adventure was taken off the PlayStation store in December 2020 due to serious technical issues – now it’s back, but its use is “not recommended” and PS5 owners still have to wait
The much-hyped sci-fi adventure Cyberpunk 2077 has finally been launched on the PlayStation store, more than six months after the game’s initial release.
 Related: Cyberpunk 2077: how 2020's biggest video game launch turned into a shambles 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pixel Buds A-Series review: Google’s cheaper but good earbuds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AirPods rivals have top sound, battery and translation features but cost significantly less
Google’s latest AirPods competitors, the Pixel Buds A-Series, get a big price cut and a slightly more comfortable design.
The new Bluetooth earbuds take a cue from Google’s cheaper but great A-Series phones, cutting a few features to cost £100 (US$99) – a full £80 cheaper than their predecessors.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Michael Albert]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/18/maker-spotlight-michael-albert/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/18/maker-spotlight-michael-albert/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First and last name Michael Albert Where are you located?  White Plains, New York What is your day job?  Pop Artist/Owner of Sir Real brand of Natural Foods Do you attend a makerspace/fablab/hackerspace?  Not usually, but I’m looking forward to the Mead Library’s Maker Faire Sheboygan this weekend. Website | Pinterest | Art site What […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Michael Albert appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The best video games of 2021 so far]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/18/the-best-video-games-of-2021-so-far</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jun/18/the-best-video-games-of-2021-so-far"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T06:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hostile alien planets, giant vampire women and a jazz age murder mystery – plus some old favourites, rebooted – are among the best games released this year
PC
A gentle, board game style town building sim, which has you matching hexagonal landscape tiles to craft unique locations, laying on further puzzles and pleasures as you go.
What we said: “This is game-playing at its most thoughtfully relaxing, with that rare chance, in video games, to be the architect of a world, rather than its conqueror.” Read the full review.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald and Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[17 Best Ground Cover Plants That Grow Well In The Shade]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34012</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/shade-ground-covers/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T17:36:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shade ground covers make an excellent addition to low light areas. Whether you’re looking for something that can take light foot traffic, or simply want to cover the soil in your shade garden, you’ll find lots of options in this list. Ground cover plants are a simple way to add beauty to your shade garden.Continue Reading
The post 17 Best Ground Cover Plants That Grow Well In The Shade appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where to Get Started in Digital Sculpting for 3D Printing]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/where-to-get-started-in-digital-sculpting-for-3d-printing/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/where-to-get-started-in-digital-sculpting-for-3d-printing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T15:44:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital sculpting isn’t as hard as it looks. At least, getting started isn’t that hard. You’ll still have to put in some serious time to get GOOD, but don’t let that scare you off. You may be surprised by how easily you can get something to be proud of, even as an absolute beginner. There […]
The post Where to Get Started in Digital Sculpting for 3D Printing appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Ben Davidson]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/maker-spotlight-ben-davidson/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/maker-spotlight-ben-davidson/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Name  Ben Davidson Where are you located?  Plymouth, WI What is your day job?  Mechanical engineer www.Grabot.Tech What kinds of stuff do you make?  I make two armed robots, that can be simply controlled with RC.  How did you get started making stuff? As a kid I was always playing with Legos. I have improved […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Ben Davidson appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Classes in July: Video Production for Makers, Whimsical Wearables, Robotics and More]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/maker-classes-in-july-video-production-for-makers-whimsical-wearables-robotics-and-more/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/maker-classes-in-july-video-production-for-makers-whimsical-wearables-robotics-and-more/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T13:54:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Campus is bursting with classes this summer. Who would have thought that over the next month, you can learn video production for makers from Make: Senior Editor Caleb Craft, start your adventure into creating whimsical wearables, or learn tips & tricks for creating better thumbnails of your projects, and more! Introduction To Video Production […]
The post Maker Classes in July: Video Production for Makers, Whimsical Wearables, Robotics and More appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How remote work opened the floodgates to ransomware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/17/ransomware-working-from-home-russia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/17/ransomware-working-from-home-russia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With workers outside the ‘castle walls’ of their companies, criminals have it easier – and cryptocurrency hasn’t helped
Ransomware has roared into the headlines in recent weeks after criminal hacking networks, tentatively linked to Russia, launched attacks on the major US meat packing plant JBS and the nation’s largest fuel pipeline. 
Joe Biden and his administration are scrambling to address the growing threat, pressing Vladimir Putin in a highly anticipated meeting on Wednesday to take action against the rise of ransomware attacks. Biden said he gave Putin a list of 16 areas – mostly in critical infrastructure - that are “off limits” for cyber-attacks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Faire Hannover 2021 Goes Disco]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/16/maker-faire-hannover-2021-goes-disco/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/16/maker-faire-hannover-2021-goes-disco/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T20:17:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The German maker community is back on view this Friday, June 18th as Maker Faire Hannover returns for its 9th edition this Friday and its first exploration of the virtual realm! 
The post Maker Faire Hannover 2021 Goes Disco appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prusa Announces Latest Resin Printer, Boasts Big Speed Boost]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/16/prusa-announces-latest-resin-printer-boasts-big-speed-boost/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/16/prusa-announces-latest-resin-printer-boasts-big-speed-boost/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T15:42:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today Prusa announced a big upgrade to their MSLA resin printer, the Prusa SL1S. While the printer may, at a glance, look just like the original SL1, Prusa has taken their typical approach of incorporating user feedback and huge upgrades to the proven platform for a big performance and user experience boost. The key points […]
The post Prusa Announces Latest Resin Printer, Boasts Big Speed Boost appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[George RR Martin, console-less games and a Final Fantasy fail: the biggest news from E3 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/16/the-biggest-news-from-e3-2021</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/16/the-biggest-news-from-e3-2021"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T13:26:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year’s online-only E3 video game expo was hardly the usual explosion of blockbuster games, but there were still some standout stories 
We all wanted to see Metroid Prime 4, the long-anticipated first-person science-fiction shooter-adventure that has been in development at Nintendo for an absolute age. But instead we got a whole new Metroid – a 2D one in the vein of the SNES and Game Boy Advance classics, the first game in the series in this style for about 19 years. Metroid Dread features Samus Aran being chased by distressing, transforming drone-robots who appear to be largely impervious to her ever-expanding array of weapons, and it looks genuinely scary. It’ll be out on 8 October on Nintendo Switch.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game Builder Garage review – Nintendo lets you loose on its building blocks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/16/game-builder-garage-review-nintendo-lets-you-loose-on-its-building-blocks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/16/game-builder-garage-review-nintendo-lets-you-loose-on-its-building-blocks"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T11:46:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Switch; Nintendo
From Mario Kart racers to 2D platforms, this charming game-maker gives you access to the Nintendo toolkit

One of the most wonderful elements of Nintendo’s Super Mario Maker titles, which give players the chance to build their own platformers, is that they provide a glimpse at how Nintendo thinks about game design. You get to see how every element matters, from the exact length of platforms, to the precise angle of Mario’s jump. It’s like going to a painting lesson with Picasso.
Game Builder Garage broadens the canvas offered by its predecessors by allowing users to construct pretty much any kind of game, from racers to 3D action adventures – all via a cute, powerful visual programming language. Here, the coding experience is represented on a graph paper screen, with each component, whether that’s objects, actions or outcomes, represented as anthropomorphised blocks named Nodons, that you can pick up, move around and link together to create programs. Want to be able to move a character on screen? Simply select a Person Nodon, then an “Input” Nodon and link them together. Each object has a series of properties, that can be switched on or off, making them, say, destructible, transparent and/or movable depending on their role in your masterpiece.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eat Just is racing to put ‘no-kill meat’ on your plate. Is it too good to be true?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/16/eat-just-no-kill-meat-chicken-josh-tetrick</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/16/eat-just-no-kill-meat-chicken-josh-tetrick"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The California startup leads a global push toward lab-grown meat. But experts question its bold claims
In December of last year, a handful of diners sat down to a futuristic meal at 1880, a members-only restaurant in Singapore. The star ingredient was “no-kill” chicken – raised not on a farm but in a laboratory bioreactor. Attendees snacked on lab-grown nuggets paired with crispy maple waffles, bao buns, and black bean puree.
For the California entrepreneur Josh Tetrick, it was a breakthrough. His company, Eat Just, had become the first in the world to sell the product after receiving approval from Singapore authorities. Headlines hailed a landmark step in the quest to end animal agriculture, upend the meat industry and redefine our diets.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erin McCormick in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface Laptop 4 review: Windows 10 as it is meant to be]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-review-windows-10-battery-keyboard-face-recognition</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-review-windows-10-battery-keyboard-face-recognition"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T06:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Premium PC with new choice of faster chips, eight-hour battery, great keyboard and face recognition 
Microsoft’s sleek and stylish Surface Laptop is back for its fourth generation with faster performance and a greater variety of chips.
The Surface Laptop 4 is available with either a 13.5in or a 15in screen and starts at £999 in the UK, $999 in the US or $1,599 in Australia sitting above the Surface Laptop Go as Microsoft’s mainstream premium notebook, competing with the similarly priced Dell XPS 13 and Apple MacBook Air, among others.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Clever Mechanical Approach Saves Big On DIY Flip Dot Displays]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/15/this-clever-mechanical-approach-saves-big-on-diy-flip-dot-displays/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/15/this-clever-mechanical-approach-saves-big-on-diy-flip-dot-displays/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-15T14:46:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This display uses a unique mechanical method to reduce the number of motors needed, called multiplexing.
The post This Clever Mechanical Approach Saves Big On DIY Flip Dot Displays appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Age of the cyber-attack: US struggles to curb rise of digital destabilization]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/age-of-the-cyber-attack-us-digital-destabilization</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/age-of-the-cyber-attack-us-digital-destabilization"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T06:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ransomware attack that caused long lines for fuel on the east coast was just part of a dramatic change in the scale and nature of foreign-based threats
It’s been 40 years since Lisa Donnan has queued for gas. But last month the cybersecurity expert found herself joining the long lines of cars across the east coast of the US looking for fuel after the latest in a series of cyber-attacks had shut down the pipeline that provides fuel to 45% of the region.
“The last time I did that was in the Iran crisis,” she said. “My dad had to wait with me.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe in New York and Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ransomware is biggest online threat to people in UK, spy agency chief to warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/ransomware-is-biggest-online-threat-to-people-in-uk-spy-agency-chief-to-warn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/ransomware-is-biggest-online-threat-to-people-in-uk-spy-agency-chief-to-warn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T23:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GCHQ cybersecurity boss sounds alarm over extortion by hackers who are mostly based in former Soviet states
Ransomware represents the biggest threat to online security for most people and businesses in the UK, the head of GCHQ’s cybersecurity arm is to warn.
Lindy Cameron, chief executive of the National Cyber Security Centre, will say in a speech that the phenomenon, where hackers encrypt data and demand payment for it to be restored, is escalating and becoming increasingly professionalised.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh Defence and security editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Straight story? The YouTuber taking a direct route to success]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/straight-story-the-youtuber-taking-a-direct-route-to-success</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/straight-story-the-youtuber-taking-a-direct-route-to-success"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T17:02:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Davies has 925,000 subscribers who watch his attempts to cross countries without making a turn

When Tom Davies and his stepbrother, Greg, were growing up on the edge of Aldridge, a town in the West Midlands, they would pick a point in the distance, a TV mast for instance, and make their way straight there, even if it meant clambering through quarries, sneaking across railway tracks and running away from angry farmers.
Now Davies has channelled this childhood taste for adventure into a YouTube series following his attempts to traverse entire countries in a direct line, based on GPS tracking.
The scrapes he finds himself in along the way, from almost drowning in swollen rivers and slashing his hand on barbed wire in Wales to a run-in with the police in Scotland, combined with his laid-back humour (he describes Norway as “Wales on steroids”), have garnered him a huge fanbase, with 925,000 subscribers to his channel.
Videos documenting his most recent “straight line mission” across Scotland are currently racking up hundreds of thousands of views, with the next episode set to go live on Sunday – and each one could be his last as obstacles threaten to cut short his journey..
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revealed: rightwing firm posed as leftist group on Facebook to divide Democrats]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/facebook-ads-turning-point-usa-rally-forge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/facebook-ads-turning-point-usa-rally-forge"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T10:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FEC investigation failed to uncover link to Rally Forge, a firm with close ties to Turning Point USA
A digital marketing firm closely linked to the pro-Trump youth group Turning Point USA was responsible for a series of deceptive Facebook ads promoting Green party candidates during the 2018 US midterm elections, the Guardian can reveal.
In an apparent attempt to split the Democratic vote in a number of close races, the ads purported to come from an organization called America Progress Now (APN) and used socialist memes and rhetoric to urge leftwing voters to support Green party candidates.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Carrie Wong in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Startup Wife by Tahmima Anam review – a deft take on tech times]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/11/the-startup-wife-by-tahmima-anam-review-a-deft-take-on-tech-times</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/11/the-startup-wife-by-tahmima-anam-review-a-deft-take-on-tech-times"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T08:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A witty investigation into the misogyny and bro culture of the world of startups and social media apps
From John Carreyrou’s award-winning Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup to Reeves Wiedeman’s WeWork shakedown Billion Dollar Loser, the real-life stories coming out of startup land are so far-fetched that you could be forgiven for thinking there’s no ground left for invention.
So what role can fiction play in this world with no boundaries – between home and work, love and business, purpose and profit? Tahmima Anam’s fourth novel attempts to answer this by taking inspiration from her experience as executive director of ROLI, a music technology startup founded by her husband.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Baker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Act giving AFP powers to monitor An0m devices did not become law until after FBI operation began]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/11/act-giving-afp-powers-to-monitor-an0m-devices-did-not-become-law-until-after-fbi-operation-began</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/11/act-giving-afp-powers-to-monitor-an0m-devices-did-not-become-law-until-after-fbi-operation-began"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police say they used ‘appropriate legislative powers’ during Operation Ironside but a lawyer representing people charged says legal concerns remain
The Australian federal police have clarified the legal basis for a wide-ranging operation that ensnared hundreds of people using compromised encrypted devices developed by an FBI informant.
The An0m devices were released in October 2018 by a convicted narcotics importer who was working for the FBI.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nino Bucci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Herbs To Grow In Your Shade Garden]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34011</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/shade-herbs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T19:43:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Herbs that grow in shade are excellent for those of us with sun-challenged gardens. The good news is that there are lots of options to choose from. In fact, many of the herbs in this list actually prefer the shade! If your yard doesn’t get a lot of sunshine, you might think that you can’tContinue Reading
The post 15 Herbs To Grow In Your Shade Garden appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internet outage illustrates lack of resilience at heart of critical services]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/08/internet-outage-illustrates-lack-of-resilience-at-heart-of-critical-services</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/08/internet-outage-illustrates-lack-of-resilience-at-heart-of-critical-services"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T13:40:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is not clear if UK government had alternative that would have allowed services to be back online promptly
Tuesday morning’s 45-minute internet outage, which knocked out the Gov.uk domain as well as a string of publishers and other websites, cannot easily be dismissed as an isolated event. It demonstrates a lack of resilience at the heart of critical government services.
Anybody wanting to book a Covid test in the late morning on Gov.uk would have struggled. There is an alternative method, by phone, but who knows the number to call: 119? Government services that once delivered by form and post, then call centres, now only really exist through online connections.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds arrested in global crime sting after underworld app is hacked]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/08/anom-encrypted-app-fbi-afp-australia-federal-police-sting-operation-ironside-an0m</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/08/anom-encrypted-app-fbi-afp-australia-federal-police-sting-operation-ironside-an0m"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T10:03:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[European and Australian police join forces with FBI to seize weapons, drugs and $148m in cash
The FBI set up its own encrypted platform used by hundreds of criminals around the world, in an “unprecedented” sting operation that led to more than 800 arrests in 18 countries, law enforcement officers have said.
The operation by the FBI and Australian and European police, ensnared suspects in Australia, Asia, Europe, South America and the Middle East involved in the narcotics trade.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Harding and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the FBI and Australian police gained a front seat view of underworld workings in 90 countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/08/how-the-fbi-and-australian-police-gained-a-front-seat-view-of-underworld-workings-in-90-countries</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/08/how-the-fbi-and-australian-police-gained-a-front-seat-view-of-underworld-workings-in-90-countries"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T09:38:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police in Australia and the US struck a blow to organised crime, resulting in hundreds of arrests. Now, an FBI affidavit reveals how authorities were able to pull it off 
It was mid-2018 when a convicted narcotics importer met with FBI agents from San Diego and made them a tantalising offer: in exchange for a possible reduction in the importer’s sentence on other charges, would the bureau like a backdoor into the encrypted communications of a vast network of international organised crime groups?
The importer had invested a “substantial amount” of money in developing an encrypted device which could be used by criminals around the world to avoid the detection of police.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nino Bucci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DoJ reclaims millions paid to hackers after attack that hobbled US pipeline]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/ransomware-pipeline-money-recovered-us-doj</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/ransomware-pipeline-money-recovered-us-doj"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T20:59:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Operation to recover cryptocurrency from Russia-based hacking group is first undertaken by new ransomware taskforce
The US justice department has recovered the majority of a multimillion-dollar ransom payment to hackers after a cyber-attack that caused the operator of the nation’s largest fuel pipeline to halt its operations last month, officials said on Monday.
The operation to recover the cryptocurrency from the Russia-based hacker group is the first undertaken by a specialized ransomware taskforce created by the Biden administration, and reflects what US officials say is an increasingly aggressive approach to deal with a ransomware threat that in the last month has targeted critical industries around the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vivian Ho and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple overhauls Siri to address privacy concerns and improve performance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/apple-overhauls-siri-to-address-privacy-concerns-and-improve-performance</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/07/apple-overhauls-siri-to-address-privacy-concerns-and-improve-performance"/>
        <updated>2021-06-07T20:28:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Voice assistant will no longer send audio recordings to firm’s servers, instead processing requests ‘on device’
Apple will no longer send Siri requests to its servers, the company has announced, in a move to substantially speed up the voice assistant’s operation and address privacy concerns.
The new feature comes two years after the Guardian revealed that Apple staff regularly heard confidential details while carrying out quality control for the feature.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern UK technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US mulling military response to ransomware attacks, Biden officials say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/06/us-military-response-ransomware-attacks-biden-russia-putin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/06/us-military-response-ransomware-attacks-biden-russia-putin"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T18:07:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Commerce secretary Raimondo says US looking at ‘all options’
Ahead of Putin summit, Russia thought to harbor perpetrators

US officials on Sunday ratcheted up pressure on companies and foreign adversaries to fight cybercriminals, and said Joe Biden was considering options to counter the growing threat including a military response.
 Related: FBI director sees ‘parallels’ between ransomware threat and 9/11  
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Losing Depop to US ownership makes the British tech sector look secondhand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/06/losing-depop-to-us-ownership-makes-the-british-tech-sector-look-secondhand</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/06/losing-depop-to-us-ownership-makes-the-british-tech-sector-look-secondhand"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T06:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The fashion resale app and its young users represents the likely future of retail: more online, more sustainable, and more social
Depop, the fashion resale app, has joined fellow British tech companies such as Arm Holdings and DeepMind in heading to a deep pool of investment outside its homeland.
London-based Depop’s acquisition by Brooklyn-based Etsy for $1.6bn (£1.1bn) last week came just days after Oxford-based WaveOptics, a maker of displays used in augmented-reality glasses, was bought up by the Santa Monica-headquartered owner of Snapchat for $500m.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Technology | The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon Unbound review: how Jeff Bezos engulfed and devoured us all]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/06/amazon-unbound-review-jeff-bezos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/06/amazon-unbound-review-jeff-bezos"/>
        <updated>2021-06-06T06:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Brad Stone’s second book on the world’s richest person is another portrait of great power – and the great damage it does

Amazon fired him – now he’s trying to unionize New York

Brad Stone, a senior editor at Bloomberg News, is now the author of a second book-length portrait of what may be the most successful business of the 21st century. When Stone’s first book, The Everything Store, was published in 2013, Amazon founder Jeff Bezos was worth a piddling $27bn. That number has risen to $190bn, 70% more than he had at the beginning of the pandemic.
 Related: Jeff Bezos thinks our cultural heritage is just ‘intellectual property’ | Nicholas Russell 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Charles Kaiser</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon fired him – now he’s trying to unionize 5,000 workers in New York]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/04/amazon-workers-staten-island-christian-smalls</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/04/amazon-workers-staten-island-christian-smalls"/>
        <updated>2021-06-04T07:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Christian Smalls is taking on the fiercely anti-union colossus , convinced that a union of only Amazon workers is the smartest way to rally Amazon employees 
Christian Smalls has taken on the biggest challenge of his life. Still smarting from when Amazon fired him last year, the 32-year-old is spearheading an effort to unionize more than 5,000 workers at four Amazon facilities in Staten Island, including a giant warehouse.
Smalls is taking a highly unusual route in pursuing this goal; he has founded an independent union, the Amazon Labor Union, convinced that a new union comprising only Amazon workers is the smartest way to rally Amazon employees behind a union after the crushing defeat of an effort to unionize an Amazon warehouse in Alabama earlier this year.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Greenhouse in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[19 Long Blooming Perennials For A More Beautiful Flower Garden]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34010</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/long-blooming-perennials/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-03T19:05:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Long-blooming perennials are the best way to get as much joy from your flower beds as possible. There are tons of great options that you can choose from too. No matter where you live, you’re sure to find plenty of great choices on this list. If you’re tired of perennials that only bloom for aContinue Reading
The post 19 Long Blooming Perennials For A More Beautiful Flower Garden appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sound Heap review – one podcast to spoof them all]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/02/sound-heap-review-john-luke-roberts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2021/jun/02/sound-heap-review-john-luke-roberts"/>
        <updated>2021-06-02T13:30:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Available online
The age of peak podcast meets its match in John-Luke Roberts and his procession of hilariously titled imaginary shows
In 2018, John-Luke Roberts’s Edinburgh show consisted entirely of names of hitherto unheard-of Spice Girls. He’s up to something similar with Sound Heap, a new “podcast of infinite podcasts”, a medley of excerpts from imaginary podcasts performed by a galaxy of comedy stars. As a vehicle to parody the current glut of (celebrity, hobbyist and vanishingly niche) audio series, it works a treat, as Roberts lines up clips from Ventriloquists Talk True Crime, Memes with Val and Britain’s Worst Bastards for our listening pleasure.
No one who has followed Roberts’s career will expect anything less than creative fecundity, and he certainly delivers: the ideas for ridiculous but just-about-credible podcasts keep coming. Occasionally, the titles are as funny as his sketches get. More often, those sketches seize the opportunities offered by Roberts’s instinct for absurdity, as when Pranks With Full Consent recasts Jeremy Beadle for the age of the trigger warning, or Passwords of My Life with Tom Allen imagines a celebrity so delighted to talk about himself, he barely notices the associated sacrifice in cyber-security.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Logan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gadgets have stopped working together, and it’s becoming an issue]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/30/gadgets-have-stopped-working-together-interoperability-apple</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/may/30/gadgets-have-stopped-working-together-interoperability-apple"/>
        <updated>2021-05-30T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our reliance on technology means ever more devices and apps and ever less interoperability – and the ubiquity of Apple hasn’t helped
In 2001, if you listened to digital music, you did it with a large folder of MP3 files. How you acquired them is probably best left between you and a priest, but you may have ripped them from a CD, downloaded them from a file sharing service, or bought them from one of a few nascent download sites.
Whichever option you picked, you’d play them on your computer with a program built for the task. And if you were lucky enough to have an early standalone MP3 player, it was probably made by another company again.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>