<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-07-11T00:36:17.616Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-07-11T00:36:17.616Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is It A Cyberdeck Or A Vintage Toshiba?]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=485284</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/10/is-it-a-cyberdeck-or-a-vintage-toshiba/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T23:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberdecks, the portable computers notable for a freely expressed form factor, owe much to post-apocalyptic sci-fi. But they are not always the most practical devices. There’s a reason that all …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jenny List</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skin-Mounted Wearable Bend Sensor Gets Close and Personal]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=485145</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/10/skin-mounted-wearable-bend-sensor-gets-close-and-personal/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T20:01:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[[Mikst] has been working on wearable electronics and sensors for a long time, and shared the results of a different kind of bend sensor that fits directly onto the skin. …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donald Papp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Cold Call a Job Recruiter (and Why You Should)]]></title>
        <id>1847259887</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-cold-call-a-job-recruiter-and-why-you-should-1847259887"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest Bureau of Labor Statistics report says the U.S. added 850,000 jobs in June, and who knows—one of those could be your dream job! Or your dream job could be one that hasn’t been made up yet, but might be, if the decision-makers at the right company only knew about you, your skills, and your goals.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Ellefson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Clean Reusable Straws (Because Yours Are Probably Gross)]]></title>
        <id>1847263628</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-clean-reusable-straws-because-yours-are-probabl-1847263628"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When people make the switch to reusable straws, it is usually with the best intentions—specifically, cutting down on the amount of landfill garbage they produce everyday. They’re great the first time you use them, but before long, the entire set is sitting at bottom of the sink, and you’re out of clean straws.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building a Big Ol’ Powerful Wheelbarrow]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=485885</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/10/building-a-big-ol-powerful-wheelbarrow/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T17:01:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes you’ve gotta haul big heavy loads around a wide area. Regular wheelbarrows are fine, but it can quickly grow tiring when one has to make multiple trips. [Workshop from …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lewin Day</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Take Screenshots on the Xbox Series X|S Outside of Gameplay]]></title>
        <id>1847257809</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-take-screenshots-on-the-xbox-series-x-s-outside-1847257809"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gaming on the Xbox Series X|S is a hoot and a half, but there is one thing about the console that’s made me want to tear my hair out: It doesn’t let you quickly take screenshots outside of gameplay. If you want to show off your home screen or take a few screenshots of your settings pages, the Xbox just doesn’t make it…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranay Parab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Force Restart Any iPhone or iPad]]></title>
        <id>1847257706</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-force-restart-any-iphone-or-ipad-1847257706"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If your iPhone or iPad is frozen or not recognizing touchscreen inputs, a forced restart may be necessary to get it working again. The force restart method allows you to shut down and reboot the iPhone without using the touchscreen.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranay Parab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How bitcoin and Putin are enabling the ransomware crime spree | John Naughton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/10/how-bitcoin-and-putin-are-enabling-the-ransomware-spree</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/10/how-bitcoin-and-putin-are-enabling-the-ransomware-spree"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T15:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A combination of cyber attackers’ increased sophistication, the availability of cryptocurrencies and the activities of Russian security agencies has created a perfect storm
I’ve just visited the Kaseya website. “We Are Kaseya,” it burbles cheerfully. “Providing you with best-in-breed technologies that allow you to efficiently manage, secure and back up IT under a single pane of glass.
“Technology,” it continues, “is the backbone of all modern business. Small to mid-size businesses deserve powerful security and IT management tools that are efficient, cost-effective, and secure. Enter Kaseya. We exist to help multi-function IT professionals get the most out of their IT tool stack.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Earn $1,500 to Go Camping for 3 Nights and Rate Your Sleep Quality]]></title>
        <id>1847263612</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/earn-1-500-to-go-camping-for-3-nights-and-rate-your-sl-1847263612"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the rise of glamping and other high-end, not-at-all-roughing-it experiences, our concept of camping has changed a lot. But there are some people who genuinely enjoy going through all the hassle of setting up a tent for the night (or a few nights), unrolling a sleeping bag, and sleeping on the ground. If you fall…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Can’t Fix What You Can’t Measure]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=486187</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/10/you-cant-fix-what-you-cant-measure/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T14:00:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last year, as my Corona Hobby™, I took up RC plane flying. I started out with discus-launched gliders, and honestly that’s still my main love, but there’s only so much …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elliot Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Tell If Your Chicken Is Part of the 9 Million Pound Recall]]></title>
        <id>1847263547</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-tell-if-your-chicken-is-part-of-the-9-million-po-1847263547"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fully cooked, ready-to-eat chicken may be a convenient way to add some protein to a meal, but if you have any in your fridge right now, you’re going to want to check the label. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Let Go of Parental Guilt and Forgive Yourself]]></title>
        <id>1847255690</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-let-go-of-parental-guilt-and-forgive-yourself-1847255690"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There is a moment (or several moments) in every parent’s life they wish they could take back. It could be as simple as the first time you ever raised your voice and caused your child to cry, the thoughtless thing you said that hurt their feelings, or the preventable accident that resulted in a trip to the emergency…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Keil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fractal Vise Holds Odd-Shaped Objects Tight]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=485889</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/10/fractal-vise-holds-odd-shaped-objects-tight/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T11:01:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A regular vice is great if you want to clamp rectangular objects, but it can fall down a little with more complex shapes. Inspired by an ancient vise [Chris Borge] …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lewin Day</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vancouver judge’s decision over Huawei finance chief may deepen US-China row]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/10/vancouver-judges-decision-over-huawei-finance-chief-may-deepen-us-china-row</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/10/vancouver-judges-decision-over-huawei-finance-chief-may-deepen-us-china-row"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T10:48:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Judge refuses to admit new evidence that might have helped Meng Wanzhou avoid extradition to US
The prospect of a deepening diplomatic row between the US and China has grown after a Canadian judge refused to admit new evidence that might have helped the Huawei chief financial officer, Meng Wanzhou, avoid extradition to the US.
The arrest of Meng, the daughter of the Chinese telecommunication company’s billionaire founder, has prompted a sharp deterioration in relations between Canada, the US and China. Soon after Meng’s detention in Vancouver in December 2018, China arrested two Canadians in China: Michael Spavor and Michael Kovrig.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Patrick Wintour Diplomatic editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[FinTok: how TikTok is helping young people use cash wisely]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jul/10/fintok-how-tiktok-is-helping-young-people-use-cash-wisely</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jul/10/fintok-how-tiktok-is-helping-young-people-use-cash-wisely"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T10:00:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not just jokes and emojis – the video-sharing platform can help users learn how to manage money
Sea shanties and viral dance trends have helped make TikTok a hit since the start of the pandemic. In 2020, the social media app, which allows users to create and share one or more 60-second films soundtracked with music clips, surpassed 2bn global downloads.
In the financial world, TikTok has a reputation for promoting volatile cryptocurrencies and activist investing – interest in Dogecoin and GameStop has been fuelled by the platform. But, beyond the jokes and rocket emojis being shared by some users, there is a wealth of practical personal finance videos that are teaching young people how to use their money better.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ellie House</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Where else can I make a month’s rent in two days?’: the unlikely stars of OnlyFans]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jul/10/where-else-can-i-make-a-months-rent-in-two-days-the-unlikely-stars-of-onlyfans</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/media/2021/jul/10/where-else-can-i-make-a-months-rent-in-two-days-the-unlikely-stars-of-onlyfans"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T09:30:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Clarita needed to put herself through nursing school; Lex wanted to boost his income as a labourer – now they are erotic influencers on the subscriber site
In many ways, Lex Lederman, 28, is a classic American family man. He owns a farm in New Hampshire, where he lives with his wife and three children (plus a sizable company of chickens, pigs and geese). He’s teaching himself home renovation (plumbing, electrics, how to lay floors) and regularly helps out with homeless food charities, refugee relief, and the local high school football team. But this lifestyle has only become possible since he quit his construction job for a full-time career on OnlyFans – the content subscription service where he uploads erotic pictures and videos for his predominantly gay male fanbase.
One of the biggest tech success stories of the last few years, OnlyFans was founded by British entrepreneur Tim Stokely in September 2016. “You could see the explosion of influencer marketing, but the influencers were getting paid via ad campaigns and product endorsements,” he explained in an interview earlier this year. “Our thinking was always, OK, what if you could build a platform where it’s similar to existing on social media, but with the key difference being the payment button?” Stokely is now worth an estimated $120m (£86m).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emma Garland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Up Close and Personal With Some Busted Avionics]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=486137</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/10/up-close-and-personal-with-some-busted-avionics/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T08:01:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When he found this broken Narco DME 890 that was headed for the trash, [Yeo Kheng Meng] did what any self-respecting hardware hacker would do: he took it back to …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Nardi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Richard Branson’s quest: to boldly go where no billionaire has gone before]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jul/10/richard-branson-virgin-galactic-flight-billionaire-space-tourism-race-jeff-bezos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jul/10/richard-branson-virgin-galactic-flight-billionaire-space-tourism-race-jeff-bezos"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T06:00:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Successful flight on Virgin Galactic craft would mark the next phase of space tourism race with Jeff Bezos
It does not often rain in Las Cruces, New Mexico. Nevertheless, Sir Richard Branson is likely to feel nervous as he checks the weather forecast on Sunday morning: if there are blue skies ahead then the British entrepreneur is likely to become the richest person ever to venture into space.
Branson and his team – two pilots and three other “mission specialists” – will strap into the spacecraft, the VSS Unity. If all goes well Branson and co will be propelled 50 miles above the Earth’s surface, the point considered by Nasa, the US space agency, to mark the end of the Earth’s atmosphere.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly and Gwyn Topham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Home Automation for Fans of Quick-and-Dirty Solutions]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=485670</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/09/a-home-automation-solution-for-fans-of-quick-and-dirty-solutions/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T05:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At Hackaday, we celebrate all kinds of projects, but we’ll have to admit that the polished and professional-looking builds tend to catch our eye a lot more than perhaps they …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Maloney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Huawei finance chief faces setback in fight against US extradition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/10/huawei-finance-chief-faces-setback-in-fight-against-us-extradition</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/10/huawei-finance-chief-faces-setback-in-fight-against-us-extradition"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T22:58:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vancouver judge denies bid by Meng Wanzhou to add over 300 HSBC documents to her legal battle
A Canadian judge has denied an application by Meng Wanzhou, the Huawei chief financial officer, to add documents her legal team received from HSBC as evidence to her US extradition case, the judge announced on Friday.
Meng, 49, is facing extradition from Canada to the US on charges of bank fraud for allegedly misleading HSBC about Huawei’s business dealings in Iran, potentially causing the bank to break US sanctions. She has been held under house arrest in Vancouver since December 2018, when she was first detained.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies in Vancouver</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A woman with HIV took over 200 days to clear her Covid infection. Here’s why researchers are worried]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/a-woman-with-hiv-took-over-200-days-to-clear-her-covid-infection-heres-why-researchers-are-worried/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/a-woman-with-hiv-took-over-200-days-to-clear-her-covid-infection-heres-why-researchers-are-worried/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T22:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A case study suggests that people with HIV should be prioritised for Covid vaccination]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 Video Games for Newbies Who Always Wanted to Become Gamers]]></title>
        <id>1847262076</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/10-video-games-for-newbies-who-always-wanted-to-become-1847262076"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Video games offer a wide range of genres and gameplay styles, and there’s probably a game out there for everyone. But despite the variety of experiences, jumping into console or PC gaming can be daunting, especially if you didn’t grow up playing games. Luckily, there are plenty of great video games out there for…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Hesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Difference Between Aluminum and Tin Foil]]></title>
        <id>1847261235</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-difference-between-aluminum-and-tin-foil-1847261235"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We recently posted about the many ways aluminum foil is helpful around the house and quickly found that mentioning “tin foil” was scientifically incorrect (and I’m always willing to admit my mistakes). Depending where you’re from, it might be a natural reflex to say “tin foil” when wrapping up leftovers or cooking on…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Shouldn't Use Your New Credit Card Until You Do These Things]]></title>
        <id>1847261332</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/you-shouldnt-use-your-new-credit-card-until-you-do-thes-1847261332"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trying out a new credit card is like driving a new car for the first time: In the same way you might adjust the seat and mirrors, locate the emergency brake, or fiddle around with the air conditioner controls, you’ll want to fine-tune the settings for your new card before you start spending. Here’s a checklist of…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use Kombucha to Make a Summery 'Negroni']]></title>
        <id>1847261973</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/use-kombucha-to-make-a-summery-negroni-1847261973"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thanks to a very detailed and helpful explainer that was recently published on this very site, I have started brewing my own kombucha. As a former brewer of beer, I have to say that brewing ‘booch is a much easier, more relaxed endeavor, and the end product does not make me sneeze. (Beer started making me sneeze in my…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mars and Venus Are About to Make Out, Guys]]></title>
        <id>1847259759</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/mars-and-venus-are-about-to-make-out-guys-1847259759"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The cosmos is in constant motion, and during the month of July, the movements of celestial bodies are an especially welcome treat for those on the ground. The two planets situated on either side of Earth—Mars and Venus—are poised to drift within a relatively close distance of each other, at least in the grand scheme…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Blum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You (Still) Shouldn't Expect a COVID Vaccine Booster Anytime Soon [Updated]]]></title>
        <id>1847160793</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/why-you-shouldnt-expect-a-covid-vaccine-booster-anytime-1847160793"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T18:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t know how long protection from the COVID-19 vaccines will last, which has led to speculation that we might all need to get booster shots—perhaps yearly, as with flu shots—to stay protected. Pfizer recently announced they plan to seek FDA authorization soon for a booster dose of their vaccine.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Easiest (and Most Natural) Ways to Get Rid of Garbage Disposal Odors]]></title>
        <id>1847259575</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-easiest-and-most-natural-ways-to-get-rid-of-garba-1847259575"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The garbage disposal may be one of the miracles of modern life, but it’s also a source for foul odors to build up. Once the odors are there, it can be a challenge to get rid of them completely—rather than just covering them up. But a few lemons and limes (plus vinegar) can go a long way—if you keep them on hand and…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Fairbank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[24 of the Best Comic Book Adaptations That Aren't Marvel or DC]]></title>
        <id>1847258633</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/24-of-the-best-comic-book-adaptations-that-arent-marvel-1847258633"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It only took Marvel 20-ish movies to give Scarlett Johansson’s Black Widow her own solo film, but that wasn’t her first, nor even her second comic book movie character. We’ve just reached the point where most popular actors will have played at least a few comics-based characters before they retire. But we come here to…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ross Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TikTok's 'Dehydration Check' Is Silly and Useless]]></title>
        <id>1847260616</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/tiktoks-dehydration-check-is-silly-and-useless-1847260616"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[TikTok is a fantastic place to discover new things to worry about, or new ways to worry about old things. The latest is the “dehydration check,” in which you pinch the skin on your knuckle. If the skin stays wrinkled for a few seconds, that’s (supposedly) your sign to grab a glass of water.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[14 Flowers You Can Actually Eat (and How to Prepare Them)]]></title>
        <id>1847257040</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/14-flowers-you-can-actually-eat-and-how-to-prepare-the-1847257040"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Flowers give us vibrant pops of color in our garden and beautiful centerpieces for special occasions—but it’s easy to forget that they can provide us sustenance, too. Flowers are plants, and some plants are edible—even delicious. That’s why horticulturists like Alexis Nikole, known as the Black Forager, are showing us…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Watch These Sports If the Olympics Get Cancelled After All]]></title>
        <id>1847253999</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/watch-these-sports-if-the-olympics-get-cancelled-after-1847253999"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With COVID-19 making a resurgence in Tokyo, the Olympics are currently coming apart at the seams, including an announcement on Thursday from Japan’s Olympics Minister Tamayo Marukawa that the Games would proceed without fans. If watching the world’s most prestigious athletic competition take place in deserted venues…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Blum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What to Do When You See Your Ex on a Date]]></title>
        <id>1847257072</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/what-to-do-when-you-see-your-ex-on-a-date-1847257072"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s officially a post-vax slutty summer, which means people are out and about. Everyone is going on dates and having fun, and that includes your ex. (Sorry!) But what happens if you run into them? Well, here’s what you should do.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Ellefson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get a Baby to Like You]]></title>
        <id>1847255554</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-get-a-baby-to-like-you-1847255554"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re like me, then you have consciously made the decision to avoid all people under the age of 25. However, sometimes you get stuck in a room with a tiny baby that just wants to cry and drool and who can sense that your biggest fear is them pooping on you.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Kahn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Out-of-Touch Adults' Guide To Kid Culture: Could We Really Colonize Venus?]]></title>
        <id>1847249246</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-out-of-touch-adults-guide-to-kid-culture-could-we-1847249246"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’ve tested the global youth-culture internet and the results have come back positive: Everything is looking up this week. We’re even talking about colonizing Venus, which is cool...if not impossible. 

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephen Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Kind of Burnt Out Are You? (And Why It Matters)]]></title>
        <id>1847256205</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/what-kind-of-burnt-out-are-you-and-why-it-matters-1847256205"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Fairbank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[16 of Our Best Parenting Hacks of 2021 So Far]]></title>
        <id>1847220889</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/16-of-our-best-parenting-hacks-of-2021-so-far-1847220889"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I can’t be the only one who blinked hard at the calendar in July, wondering where the hell the first half of 2021 had gone. After spending the better part of 2020 wanting the whole year to vanish off the space-time continuum, it’s a little surreal to watch time speed up again as life around us normalizes. Even so,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Meghan Moravcik Walbert</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Unlimited Vacation Days Is a Scam]]></title>
        <id>1847255661</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/why-unlimited-vacation-days-is-a-scam-1847255661"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Increasingly, companies include unlimited paid time off as part of their job offers, as it’s an enticement popular with millennials and Gen Z workers. But you’ll want to think twice about whether it’s really all that great—studies show that workers often take less time off with unlimited vacation days. Why would that…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[When Exactly Should You Pepper a Steak?]]></title>
        <id>1847254928</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/when-exactly-should-you-pepper-a-steak-1847254928"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the exception of salt, pepper is the most common and ubiquitous seasoning in American cooking.  The berries themselves vary wildly in both color and flavor, but when and how you grind and cook them also has a big impact on their flavor.  (Growing up, my sister called pre-ground black pepper “hot salt,” though it…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rubbish collection stopped by garbage collectors demanding permanent jobs in Kariega]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/rubbish-collection-stopped-garbage-collectors-demanding-permanent-jobs-kariega/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/rubbish-collection-stopped-garbage-collectors-demanding-permanent-jobs-kariega/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T09:39:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The workers say they were employed as casuals from 2018 until June 2021]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire kills one man and destroys 200 shacks in Cato Manor]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/one-man-died-and-200-shacks-destroyed-fire-cato-manor/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/one-man-died-and-200-shacks-destroyed-fire-cato-manor/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T08:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residents say this is the third devastating fire in eight months at Marikana informal settlement]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Cuphead to Super Meat Boy: 10 of the most fiendishly difficult games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jul/09/difficult-games-super-meat-boy-spelunky-dark-souls-returnal-cuphead-sekiro</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jul/09/difficult-games-super-meat-boy-spelunky-dark-souls-returnal-cuphead-sekiro"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T08:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roguelike shooters, punishing platformers and brutal, sword-heavy RPGs … not all great games have to be a walk in the park

Modern Toss on twiddling their thumbs

If you want to try and enjoy beautiful 1930s-style animation while being so frustrated that you nearly throw your controller at the wall, Cuphead is your game. It’s a run-and-gun cartoon caper that looks non-threatening but is actually evil. I had nightmares about one of its bosses (the transforming wedding-cake castle), but when I beat it I felt like an actual god.
Consoles, Mac, PC
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Over 4 million vaccines administered, as rollout goes full steam ahead]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/over-4-million-vaccines-administered-rollout-goes-full-steam-ahead/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/over-4-million-vaccines-administered-rollout-goes-full-steam-ahead/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T06:52:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Evidence accumulates that Covid-19 vaccines are saving lives across the planet]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[3D Modeling for Makers]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/08/3d-modeling-for-makers/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/08/3d-modeling-for-makers/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T05:52:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lydia Sloan Cline is the author of Fusion 360 for Makers, which is out in a new second edition. She teaches 3D design and fabrication at Johnson County Community College in Overland Park, Kansas, where she began as a drafting professor with a degree in Architecture. In this episode of Make:cast, Patrick DiJusto, Make: Books […]
The post 3D Modeling for Makers appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wild tales of illegal animal trading – podcasts of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/09/wild-tales-of-animal-trading-podcasts-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/09/wild-tales-of-animal-trading-podcasts-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T05:00:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Natural History Museum’s new podcast covers poaching, smuggling and more. Plus: To Live and Die in LA returns, and Atlas Obscura offers instant wanderlust
Wild Crimes
As the Natural History Museum’s Tori Herridge informs us, wildlife crime is the fourth most lucrative illegal industry in the world, after narcotics, human trafficking and arms dealing. The first episode of this engaging podcast on the subject, helmed by Herridge and her colleague Khalil Thirlaway, considers the demand for pangolins, for the production of everything from wine to shoes. Episode two focuses on reptile smuggling, and episode three on the black market eel trade, with instalments on ivory, bushmeat, fossils and more on the way
Hannah J Davies
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah J Davies, Hannah Verdier and Elena Morresi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[As many as 750,000 children have dropped out of school during the pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/many-750000-children-have-dropped-out-school-during-pandemic/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/many-750000-children-have-dropped-out-school-during-pandemic/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T04:14:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[School attendance is at the lowest level it has been in 20 years]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Workers dismissed for refusing polygraph test head to Labour Court]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/workers-dismissed-refusing-polygraph-test-head-labour-court/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/workers-dismissed-refusing-polygraph-test-head-labour-court/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The workers will argue that polygraph tests are unscientific and will ask for their dismissals to be rescinded]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eastern Cape fishers celebrate chance to once again catch squid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/eastern-cape-fishers-celebrate-chance-once-again-catch-squid/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/eastern-cape-fishers-celebrate-chance-once-again-catch-squid/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Small-scale fisheries have been given a 15% squid quota]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Housing for informal settlement near Cape Town airport on hold]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/housing-development-informal-settlement-hold-after-acsa-opposes-development/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/housing-development-informal-settlement-hold-after-acsa-opposes-development/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T02:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Province waiting for tests on aircraft noise, but resident says they have been living there since the 1990s and have not gone deaf]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Mice, cockroaches, mosquitos and flies were attracted to the dumping site”]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/there-were-mice-cockroaches-mosquitos-and-flies-that-were-attracted-by-the-dumping-site/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/there-were-mice-cockroaches-mosquitos-and-flies-that-were-attracted-by-the-dumping-site/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T02:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[eThekwini Municipality warns of fines of up to R5,000 for illegal dumping]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Currency and control: why China wants to undermine bitcoin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/09/currency-and-control-why-china-wants-to-undermine-bitcoin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/09/currency-and-control-why-china-wants-to-undermine-bitcoin"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T00:38:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beijing’s crackdown on cryptocurrencies has captured headlines, while behind the scenes its reserve bank set up its own digital currency

Few would dispute that China’s recent crackdown on cryptocurrency trading and mining has contributed to the recent plunge in the value of bitcoin and other cryptos.
But while the argument rages about whether the volatility of cryptos is a sign of fundamental weakness or merely a bump along the road, the initiatives coming out of Beijing are being seen by experts as a sign of China’s attempts to incubate its own fledgling e-currency and reboot the international financial system.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Martin Farrer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency firm Circle to float in US in $4.5bn merger deal]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/08/cryptocurrency-firm-circle-to-float-in-us-in-45bn-merger-deal-usd-coin</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/08/cryptocurrency-firm-circle-to-float-in-us-in-45bn-merger-deal-usd-coin"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T16:15:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Operator behind USD Coin will merge with company chaired by former Barclays chief executive Bob Diamond
Circle, the company behind digital currency USD Coin, is to float in the US in a $4.5bn (£3.27bn) merger deal with a company chaired by former Barclays chief executive Bob Diamond.
It will merge with Concord Acquisition Corp, which is chaired by Diamond, with the combined business to be taken over by a newly formed Irish holding company that will then list on the New York Stock Exchange.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Female -vs- Male Squash Flowers: How To Tell The Difference]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34781</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/male-vs-female-squash-blossoms/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T15:11:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Squash plants have both male and female blossoms, and they each play a key role in fruit production. In this post, I’ll talk about the differences between female vs male squash flowers, and show you tons of photos to help you easily and quickly tell them apart. It’s important to be able to tell theContinue Reading
The post Female -vs- Male Squash Flowers: How To Tell The Difference appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This charity has been feeding Cape Town’s hungry for more than 80 years. Never have so many people queued for food]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/the-service-dining-rooms-have-been-feeding-cape-towns-hungry-for-more-than-80-years-but-never-have-so-many-people-queued-for-food/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/the-service-dining-rooms-have-been-feeding-cape-towns-hungry-for-more-than-80-years-but-never-have-so-many-people-queued-for-food/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T08:43:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“The increase in numbers shows how much people are struggling out there”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elections 2021: Xolobeni voters may kick ANC out]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/elections-2021-xolobeni-residents-may-vote-out-anc/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/elections-2021-xolobeni-residents-may-vote-out-anc/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T05:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Poor services and a controversial mining project have fuelled disaffection with governing party]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Siqalo shack dwellers want solar power]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/siqalo-shack-dwellers-see-solar-power-solution-their-electricity-woes/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/siqalo-shack-dwellers-see-solar-power-solution-their-electricity-woes/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residents are asking the City of Cape Town to subsidise a model they say worked in Stellenbosch]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Makeshift church takes in flood victims in Bloekombos]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/makeshift-church-takes-flood-victims-bloekombos/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/makeshift-church-takes-flood-victims-bloekombos/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T03:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nomava Mboniswa offered her zinc church structure after she saw images of the flood on TV]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Survey estimates half of all adults under 70 have likely had Covid-19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/blood-survey-finds-half-south-africans-have-likely-had-covid-19/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/blood-survey-finds-half-south-africans-have-likely-had-covid-19/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T03:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Study was conducted in January and May, before the third wave peaked]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US urged to investigate deceptive Facebook ads tied to rightwing group]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/07/facebook-ads-turning-point-usa-rally-forge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/07/facebook-ads-turning-point-usa-rally-forge"/>
        <updated>2021-07-07T15:48:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Watchdog calls for inquiry after Guardian investigation reveals ‘Green party’ ads were placed by conservative marketing firm
A campaign finance watchdog group has requested that the justice department open a criminal investigation into the figures behind a series of deceptive Facebook ads that promoted Green party candidates in the 2018 midterm elections.
A Guardian investigation recently revealed that the ads were placed by a major conservative marketing firm, contradicting an inquiry by the Federal Election Commission (FEC), which accepted the statement of Evan Muhlstein that he was responsible for the ads and had failed to comply with FEC reporting requirements due to “inexperience”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Carrie Wong</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Can you hear the Hum? The mystery noise that says a lot about modern life]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/07/the-hum-mystery-noise-says-a-lot-about-modern-life</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/07/the-hum-mystery-noise-says-a-lot-about-modern-life"/>
        <updated>2021-07-07T11:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The insistent low-frequency sound has been heard from Bristol to Swansea and ascribed to everything from horny fish to 5G – but the enigma itself is telling
Maybe you hear it. A low frequency hum, almost a vibration, just on the threshold of human hearing. It’s not particularly loud. In fact, you might not have even noticed it yet – but once you do, you can’t stop hearing it. It sounds like a truck, idling on the street in front your house. Or the atmospheric din of an airplane flying overhead, that never gets further away. You can hear it when you’re outside, but it seems louder indoors, and particularly at night, when you’re lying in bed. Maybe it keeps you awake. Maybe it causes you headaches, dizziness, even nosebleeds.
If you do hear it, you’re among the roughly 4% of the world’s population affected by “the Hum”, a frequently reported but little understood global phenomenon. The earliest reliable reports of the Hum date from the UK in the mid-1970s, most notably from Bristol, when letters began appearing in the Bristol Evening Post about a low rumble heard by dozens of residents throughout the city. What began as an irritating if innocuous noise eventually drove many who heard it to distraction, and was said to be linked to two suicides. A prevailing theory was that the Bristol Hum originated from large industrial fans used at a warehouse in nearby Avonmouth. But according to some Bristolians the Hum persists to this day, despite the warehouse having long been decommissioned.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jordan Tannahill</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng government takes vaccination drive to SASSA queues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-government-takes-vaccination-drive-sassa-queues/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-government-takes-vaccination-drive-sassa-queues/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-07T08:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“We’ve been using vaccines for years. I don’t understand why people are afraid of this vaccine” says Soweto pensioner]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin machines: the curious history of video games on vinyl]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/07/video-games-on-vinyl-flexi-discs-zx-spectrum</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/07/video-games-on-vinyl-flexi-discs-zx-spectrum"/>
        <updated>2021-07-07T08:45:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During the early 80s home computing boom, flexi discs full of data were briefly all the rage, and Frank Sidebottom, the Thompson Twins and the Stranglers made their way to the ZX Spectrum
It’s almost unthinkable now, but from the 1970s until the early 1980s, vinyl records were explored as a means of storing computer data – including video games. Some magazines of the time tucked code-packed flexi disc inserts into their pages: paper-thin plastic records that could be fed into home computers from an ordinary turntable, magically manifesting a game on screen. Long before Travis Scott was attracting 12 million players to a gig hosted in Fortnite, there was a coming together of a British game developer, a magazine and a pop act that marked the beginning of the intersection between the music and games industries.
The Thompson Twins Adventure Game came cover-mounted on a 1984 issue of the beloved magazine Computer & Video Games, the first UK magazine devoted to games. Almost everyone involved in the project – a promotional item linked to the release of the single Doctor Doctor – admits the game was imperfect. It was a weird text adventure garnished with incidental visuals, in which the members of the Thompson Twins had to locate the ingredients of a potion to be made by the song’s eponymous medic. The idea was that readers could load the disc from a turntable linked directly to a Spectrum, or copy the audio on to a cassette, which could then be used to load the game on a Spectrum or Commodore. Getting the recording level right could take multiple attempts, as users experimented with audio settings, and some of the disks got damaged as they dangled exposed on the cover.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Freeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Republican National Committee denies Russian hackers accessed data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/06/republican-national-committee-denies-hack-synnex</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/06/republican-national-committee-denies-hack-synnex"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T23:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Report says RNC computers were breached by Cozy Bear hackers, accused of DNC hack in 2016
The US Republican National Committee has denied that Russian hackers accessed data during a breach of third-party provider last week.
The hackers were part of APT29 or Cozy Bear, according to Bloomberg, citing two unnamed people familiar with the matter. The group is linked with Russia’s foreign intelligence service, the SVR, and was previously accused of hacking the Democratic National Committee in 2016, as well as carrying out the historic cybersecurity breach against SolarWinds, which affected about 100 US companies and nine federal agencies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK supercomputer Cambridge-1 to hunt for medical breakthroughs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/07/uk-supercomputer-cambridge-1-to-hunt-for-medical-breakthroughs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/07/uk-supercomputer-cambridge-1-to-hunt-for-medical-breakthroughs"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T23:01:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Computer – the most powerful in Britain – will use AI to find new cures and deepen understanding of diseases
The UK’s most powerful supercomputer, which its creators hope will make the process of preventing, diagnosing and treating disease better, faster and cheaper, is operational.
Christened Cambridge-1, the supercomputer represents a $100m investment by US-based computing company Nvidia. The idea capitalises on artificial intelligence (AI) – which combines big data with computer science to facilitate problem-solving – in healthcare. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Story of Film: A New Generation review – invigorating study of 21st century cinema]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/06/the-story-of-film-a-new-generation-review-invigorating-study-of-21st-century-cinema</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/06/the-story-of-film-a-new-generation-review-invigorating-study-of-21st-century-cinema"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T19:27:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critic and film-maker Mark Cousins offers a new instalment in his monumental Story of Film series, examining what digital technology has brought to the table
Critic and documentary film-maker Mark Cousins has returned to Cannes with another episode of his amazingly ambitious cinephile history The Story of Film, an illuminated patchwork clip-quilt, accompanied by his inimitable incantation-voiceover. It’s another example of his unique approach: Cousins is subjective almost to the point of free-associating or even sleep-talking (maybe appropriate for the dream state of the movies) but also colossally well-informed, bracingly internationalist and genuinely educational. I have never yet watched a Cousins film without learning something and being a bit sheepish about what I didn’t know.
That said, Cousins’s style takes some getting used to – almost like a hyper-innocent form of criticism, wide-eyed with wonder at cinema’s brave new world, a Miranda of the movies. Occasionally Cousins’s commentary verges on the superfluous, simply describing what is on screen, although there is almost always a shrewd insight there: he has a great section on a creepy travelling shot in David Robert Mitchell’s psychological horror It Follows.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Pollinate Squash By Hand For Maximum Production]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34564</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/pollinating-squash/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T16:27:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pollinating squash by hand is easy, will ensure higher yields, and doesn’t take much time. In this post, I will explain why your baby squash keep falling off, and discuss the processes of hand pollinating the flowers step-by-step. One of the biggest struggles that newbies face when growing vegetables for the first time is havingContinue Reading
The post How To Pollinate Squash By Hand For Maximum Production appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Nintendo Switch model announced for October]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/06/new-nintendo-switch-oled-model-announced</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/06/new-nintendo-switch-oled-model-announced"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:35:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The upgraded OLED model will have a bigger screen and more storage for games
Nintendo has announced a new version of the Nintendo Switch, due out on 8 October this year. The Nintendo Switch OLED model will have a larger and brighter 7in screen, a wide kickstand for tabletop play, enhanced audio in handheld mode and 64GB of storage for games. Like the 2017 Nintendo Switch, it can be slotted into a dock for playing on a TV at home, or taken out and played as a handheld console. The TV dock will also have a wired LAN port, an important addition for those who like to play competitively online.
An upgraded model of Nintendo’s successful console has been rumoured for the past year, and was at one point expected to be announced during E3 last June. It will be available on the same day as Metroid Dread, the most anticipated game in Nintendo’s 2021 lineup.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Stefan Hermann of CNC Kitchen]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/06/maker-spotlight-stefan-hermann-of-cnc-kitchen/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/06/maker-spotlight-stefan-hermann-of-cnc-kitchen/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First and last name Stefan Hermann Where are you located?  Germany What is your day job?  Metal Additive Manufacturing Research Engineer Youtube Channel | Patreon What kinds of stuff do you make?  3D Printing Stuff, Material Tests and 3D Printing Research How did you get started making stuff?  Bought a book about Arduino, purchased a […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Stefan Hermann of CNC Kitchen appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ransomware hackers demand $70m after attack on US software firm Kaseya]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/06/kaseya-ransomware-hackers-attack</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/06/kaseya-ransomware-hackers-attack"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T14:11:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between 800 and 1,500 businesses around the world, including supermarkets and dentists’ offices, affected by attack
Between 800 and 1,500 businesses around the world have been affected by a ransomware attack centered on the US information technology firm Kaseya, its chief executive said on Monday.
 Related: Republicans’ effort to deny the Capitol attack is working – and it’s dangerous 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Venu 2 review: can Garmin make a good smartwatch?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/venu-2-review-can-garmin-make-a-good-smartwatch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/venu-2-review-can-garmin-make-a-good-smartwatch"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T06:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fitness firm’s new Apple Watch-rival looks the part and tracks loads of data but lacks some real smarts
Garmin’s latest device aims to beat the Apple Watch and rivals at their own game, offering longer battery life and better fitness tracking in a more traditional touchscreen smartwatch body.
The Venu 2 comes in either 40mm or 45mm models, costs from £349.99 ($399.99/A$629) and is compatible with both Android and iPhones connecting via Bluetooth.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden announces investigation into international ransomware attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/kaseya-ransomware-attack-us-sweden</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/kaseya-ransomware-attack-us-sweden"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T21:43:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President addresses hack of Kaseya software that has affected hundreds of US businesses and shut down Swedish shops
Joe Biden said on Saturday he had directed US intelligence agencies to investigate a sophisticated ransomware attack that hit hundreds of American businesses as the Fourth of July holiday weekend began and aroused suspicions of Russian gang involvement.
 Related: Joe Biden cherry-picks audience to promote bipartisan infrastructure deal 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The week in audio: Pieces of Britney; Elon Musk: The Evening Rocket; Human Resources and more]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/03/pieces-of-britney-review-elon-musk-the-evening-rocket-human-resources-the-essay-caribbean-voices-the-kindness-experiment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/03/pieces-of-britney-review-elon-musk-the-evening-rocket-human-resources-the-essay-caribbean-voices-the-kindness-experiment"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T16:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Radio 4 series on Britney Spears’s troubles and Elon Musk’s space ambitions highlight society’s double standards
Pieces of Britney (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Elon Musk: The Evening Rocket (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Human Resources Broccoli Productions | Spotify
The Essay: Caribbean Voices (Radio 3) | BBC Sounds
The Kindness Experiment (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Britney Spears has been in the news a lot over the past few weeks. Her recent court plea to be released from legal conservatorship was horrible and shocking; and also rejected. Judge Brenda Penny ruled last Wednesday that the current situation – where Britney’s father Jamie is a co-conservator, even though he’s ill – should stay in place. Pain, when expressed by a woman, is often disbelieved and ignored.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Sawyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enjoy the restored Night Watch, but don’t ignore the machine behind the Rembrandt]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/commentisfree/2021/jul/03/enjoy-the-restored-night-watch-but-dont-ignore-the-machine-behind-the-rembrandt</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/commentisfree/2021/jul/03/enjoy-the-restored-night-watch-but-dont-ignore-the-machine-behind-the-rembrandt"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T15:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The computer restoration of this masterpiece illustrates both the benefits and the dangers of AI
In the late 1970s I lived and worked briefly in the Netherlands. Often, on Sundays, I would travel to Amsterdam, go to the morning concert in the Spiegelzaal of the Concertgebouw, and afterwards walk over to the Rijksmuseum, Holland’s national gallery, and spend a couple of hours there. The museum is a wonderful storehouse of Dutch art and there was always much to explore. But on nearly every visit I found myself being drawn back to one of Rembrandt’s most famous pictures – The Night Watch – which I guess is to the Rijksmuseum what the Mona Lisa is to the Louvre.
Its official title is Militia Company of District II under the Command of Captain Frans Banninck Cocq. It came to be called The Night Watch because by the end of the 18th century it had darkened considerably through the accumulation of layers of dirt and varnish, leading to the belief that the painted scene had occurred after dusk.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Umurangi Generation review – chic photographic hide-and-seek]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/03/umurangi-generation-review-photography-hide-and-seek-maori</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/03/umurangi-generation-review-photography-hide-and-seek-maori"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T12:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this compelling game, your mission is to locate and photograph a series of images in a Māori-influenced world under occupation
Many contemporary video games include a “photo mode” to enable the player to pause the action, position a virtual camera and take a snapshot of a scene (and then, the designers surely hope, post the results online, enabling grassroots marketing). Few make photography the entire point of the enterprise, however. Nintendo’s recent Pokémon Snap asked us to capture images of its mythic animals doing noteworthy things on safari-style tours, before grading the results. Umurangi Generation, another rare example of the genre, is less interested in making value judgments about your virtual photography (“Art is subjective,” the game’s tutorial assures); instead, you are whisked to a series of highly stylised scenes and given 10 minutes to collect a set of specific shots to a tight brief: seven birds, two boomboxes, a mountain, and so on.
The world is rendered in jagged polygons straight out of a late-90s PlayStation game (early-era 3D has now replaced 80s pixel art as the throwback trend in games), lending each image produced a nu-vintage appeal. Framing and focusing shots is elegantly straightforward, as is switching between lenses. You can jump, crouch, rotate the frame and, using three sliders, adjust the colour, tint and exposure within seconds.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Parkin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s next for Jeff Bezos? Space, climate and media may all figure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/whats-next-for-jeff-bezos-space-climate-and-media-may-all-figure</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/whats-next-for-jeff-bezos-space-climate-and-media-may-all-figure"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T05:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As he hands over top job at Amazon, Bezos will remain largest shareholder and ‘has never had more energy’
A quarter of a century after he founded Amazon in a Seattle garage, Jeff Bezos is preparing to loosen his grip on his $1.7tn (£1.2tn) company. Few employees in the sphere conservatories at Amazon’s sprawling Seattle campus headquarters reckon Bezos will relinquish that much of his iron grip on the company’s big decisions when Andy Jassy succeeds him as CEO on Monday. After all, Bezos will become executive chairman of Amazon’s board and remains the company’s biggest shareholder. But Bezos, 57, told his 1.3 million employees (whom he refers to as “fellow Amazonians”) that “as much as I still tap dance into the office, I’m excited about this transition”.
“I’ve never had more energy, and this isn’t about retiring,” he said. “I intend to focus my energies and attention on new products and early initiatives … I’m super passionate about the impact I think these organisations can have.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate Wealth correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Latest ransomware attack appears to hit hundreds of American businesses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/latest-ransomware-attack-american-businesses-kaseya</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/latest-ransomware-attack-american-businesses-kaseya"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T00:01:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The US cybersecurity agency said it was investigating the attack after an incident at the Miami-based IT firm Kaseya
Hundreds of American businesses have been hit by a ransomware attack ahead of the Fourth of July holiday weekend, according to the cybersecurity company Huntress Labs.
Huntress Labs said on Friday that 200 American businesses were hit after an incident at the Miami-based IT firm Kaseya, potentially marking the latest in a line of hacks destabilizing US companies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wildermyth review – fantasy RPG with real heart and soul]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/02/wildermyth-review-worldwalker-games-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/02/wildermyth-review-worldwalker-games-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T07:30:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PC; Worldwalker Games
Witty writing, evocative art and engrossing battles combine in a wonderful homage to classic tabletop games
Fantasy role-playing games love saying that the real treasure was the friends we made along the way, but, for most, literal treasure remains the focus. Who’s got time for the business of human companionship, after all, when there are Platinum Swords of Eldritch to track down? Thank the old gods, then, for Wildermyth, a sumptuous virtual tabletop experience from a tiny Texas studio that plays like a tale told over a campfire, deep in the woods.
Each Wildermyth session is a colourful mix of scripted events and random occurrences, but they all go something like this: a band of peasants take up arms against otherworldly horrors. You move them around a swirling parchment map, scouting regions, defeating the local bogeymen and driving back regular full-scale invasions of tentacle demons, goblins and skeletal machines.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edwin Evans-Thirlwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire HD 10 Plus (2021) review: Amazon’s top budget tablet upgraded]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/fire-hd-10-plus-2021-review-amazons-top-budget-tablet-upgraded</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/fire-hd-10-plus-2021-review-amazons-top-budget-tablet-upgraded"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T06:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Slimmer, better design, long battery life, 10.1in HD screen and speakers makes for a good TV tablet
Amazon’s top 10in Fire OS tablet has had a makeover and now has faster performance, without costing iPad money.
The 2021 Fire HD 10 comes in either a standard version costing £150/US$150 or a “Plus” version, as tested here, costing £180/US$180, with a few more bells and whistles.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emotion and Empathy Are Glue for Makers]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/01/emotion-and-empathy-are-glue-for-makers/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/01/emotion-and-empathy-are-glue-for-makers/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:33:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2020, Dr. Andreea Gorbatai and two co-authors published a research paper in the journal Organization Science titled: “Making Space for Emotions: Empathy, Contagion, and Legitmacy’s Double-Edged Sword.” It’s about the maker movement and what holds it together. It turns out, it’s not skills and tools as much as it is emotions and empathy — […]
The post Emotion and Empathy Are Glue for Makers appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting Brussels Sprouts – Everything You Need To Know]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34562</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/harvesting-brussels-sprouts/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:38:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting brussels sprouts is easier than you might think, and actually kinda fun too! In this post, you’ll learn how to tell when they are ready to pick, plus I’ll show you step by step exactly how to gather them, and even give you tips for using, and storing them for later. Have you everContinue Reading
The post Harvesting Brussels Sprouts – Everything You Need To Know appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to photograph the moon on your phone or camera with the best settings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/30/how-to-photograph-the-full-moon-with-phone-tips-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/30/how-to-photograph-the-full-moon-with-phone-tips-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T01:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Australia picture editor Carly Earl explains the dos and don’ts of taking pictures of the moon
When a full moon rises, many people will pull out their mobile phones to try and get an Instagram-worthy photograph, but unfortunately it’s really challenging to take a great picture of the moon.
Two reasons: it is very far away and unless you have a telephoto lens (which makes the moon appear closer than it is) it will always appear as a very small glowing dot in the frame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carly Earl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting Kohlrabi – Everything You Need To Know]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34560</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/harvesting-kohlrabi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T18:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting kohlrabi may sound intimidating, but it’s actually very easy. In this post, I’ll show how to tell when they are ready, the best way to pick them, and even give you tips for using and storing your garden fresh kohlrabi harvest. Despite how it may sound, the steps for harvesting kohlrabi are actually veryContinue Reading
The post Harvesting Kohlrabi – Everything You Need To Know appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If You’re Into 3D Printing, You Need To Be Watching CNC Kitchen]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/29/if-youre-into-3d-printing-you-need-to-be-watching-cnc-kitchen/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/29/if-youre-into-3d-printing-you-need-to-be-watching-cnc-kitchen/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T15:04:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CNC Kitchen channel, run by Stefan, is a treasure trove of tests and real data surrounding many 3d printing topics
The post If You’re Into 3D Printing, You Need To Be Watching CNC Kitchen appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Making Of ‘Lord of the Rings’ inspired ‘Fellbeast’ Head]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/28/the-making-of-lord-of-the-rings-inspired-fellbeast-head/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/28/the-making-of-lord-of-the-rings-inspired-fellbeast-head/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Follow along as an artist shares the process of recreating the Fell Beast form the Lord Of The Rings
The post The Making Of ‘Lord of the Rings’ inspired ‘Fellbeast’ Head appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memo to corporate leaders post-Covid: the disruption to businesses has only just begun | John Naughton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/memo-to-corporate-leaders-post-covid-the-disruption-to-businesses-has-only-just-begun</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/memo-to-corporate-leaders-post-covid-the-disruption-to-businesses-has-only-just-begun"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Managerial hierarchies must learn the true lessons of the pandemic if they are to survive and thrive
Pandemics, the historian Yuval Noah Harari has observed, have a way of accelerating history. Just ask the founders of Zoom. Only two years ago, we were all thinking that it would take at least another decade before video-conferencing became an integral part of the way we work in organisations. Then along comes Covid and in three weeks we’re all happily Zooming (or unhappily in the case of Handforth parish council). And now we’re more or less acclimatised or, at any rate, resigned to the idea that remote meetings might be here to stay.
The problem with having had the fast-forward button suddenly propel us into an unexpected place, though, is that we find ourselves unmoored. We start wondering about what lies ahead as the immediate threat of the virus recedes. What will our post-pandemic future be like? In relation to work, three main possibilities are currently taking up all the airtime: continuing to work from home (WFH); a hybrid mode in which we spend some time in the office but also two or three days WFH; and a return to ye olde days commuting to the office to gather round the water cooler and pretend to be doing something useful.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Tickets Now For The Make: Education Forum]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/24/get-tickets-now-for-the-make-education-forum/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/24/get-tickets-now-for-the-make-education-forum/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:18:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The growth of makerspaces in education was interrupted by the shutdown of schools, libraries, and museums over the last year.  Now, as students return to in-person learning, there is an even greater need for maker educators who can provide hands-on making and project-based learning experiences. In addition, making is a practice that can be learned […]
The post Get Tickets Now For The Make: Education Forum appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mario Golf: Super Rush review – madcap golf game switches things up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/24/mario-golf-super-rush-review-madcap-golf-game-switches-things-up</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/24/mario-golf-super-rush-review-madcap-golf-game-switches-things-up"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch; Camelot
The innovation of players running around after their shots is fun but you may find yourself longing for a leisurely stroll over the course
My first memory of Mario Golf involves showing my dad – who, like many Scottish dads I know, is a steadfastly committed and resolutely mediocre golfer – a round of the Nintendo 64 version when I was a child. I hoped that this might be a potential bonding moment where our worlds temporarily collided, but after patiently watching me play a few holes as Luigi, he failed to see the point. Why not just play real golf, he asked, which to me seemed a bit like asking why you didn’t just become a Premiership footballer instead of watching football on TV. 
It is a question that would make even less sense now. In 1999, Mario Golf was just normal golf with Nintendo characters. This month’s Mario Golf: Super Rush is a mad cartoonish caricature of the sport played by Nintendo characters in fabulously camp outfits, where you have to sprint after your shot as soon as you’ve hit it, ride tornadoes up cliffs to find the ball, and try to avoid the tackles and explosions that other players send your way. Doing any of that down the real-life course on a Sunday would, at best, get you politely removed from the premises.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon crushed the Alabama union drive – can the Teamsters do better?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/amazon-alabama-union-drive-teamsters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/amazon-alabama-union-drive-teamsters"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Teamsters union is rich, strong, and experienced – and it’s ready to help workers and give Amazon a headache  
The announcement that the Teamsters – one of America’s most powerful unions – is going to mount an ambitious campaign to unionize Amazon warehouses across the US presents the e-retailing colossus with a far bigger threat than the recent effort to unionize an Amazon warehouse in Alabama ever did.
 Related: Amazon fired him – now he’s trying to unionize 5,000 workers in New York 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Greenhouse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing The Winners Of Our “May The 4th” Cosplay and Droid Contest]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/23/announcing-the-winners-of-our-may-the-4th-cosplay-and-droid-contest/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/23/announcing-the-winners-of-our-may-the-4th-cosplay-and-droid-contest/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T14:46:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When we announced our Star Wars themed contest, along with NVIDIA, we knew we were going to be in for a difficult time deciding on a winner. There are so many great projects out there with incredible documentation and stunning results! We were not let down by the entries. If you haven’t checked them out […]
The post Announcing The Winners Of Our “May The 4th” Cosplay and Droid Contest appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweat review – the loneliness of the social media influencer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/23/sweat-review-the-loneliness-of-the-social-media-influencer-magdalena-kolesnik</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/23/sweat-review-the-loneliness-of-the-social-media-influencer-magdalena-kolesnik"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Magnus von Horn’s contrived Polish drama about a fitness guru promises more in shock and character than it delivers
In theory, it should be possible to create a drama about a social media influencer and motivational fitness celebrity that isn’t all about the hidden loneliness and shame of her shallow existence. It should be possible to show such a person being a huge hit in public and perfectly content in private. But this movie from Poland-based Swedish director Magnus von Horn pretty much goes for route one, and despite some interesting touches, it promises much more in terms of shock and character insight than it ever really delivers, with some contrived and unconvincing plot transitions.
Sylwia (Magdalena Koleśnik) has 600,000 followers for the Instagram account on which she obsessively posts, detailing every aspect of her day as a successful single woman, running colossally popular fitness events with her beefcake male assistant Klaudiusz (Julian Świeżewski). He clearly has a major thing for her, though at one crucial moment he shows a very implausible kind of restraint. She is living in a sleek apartment with her adorable dog, Jackson; there’s a new fitness DVD out and everything seems to be going well.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NFTs and me: meet the people trying to sell their memes for millions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/23/nfts-and-me-meet-the-people-trying-to-sell-their-memes-for-millions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/23/nfts-and-me-meet-the-people-trying-to-sell-their-memes-for-millions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once, people who owned viral photos made little money from them. Now, the ‘original’ can potentially sell for an enormous sum. But are buyers savvy investors – or unwitting dupes?
The photographer Jeff McCurry’s favourite Harambe memes are the ones where the dead gorilla is in heaven, Photoshopped alongside Diana, Princess of Wales, Tupac and Muhammad Ali. “It’s like: wow,” says McCurry. “What greater spot can you be placed in? Harambe’s at the top of the hill, waiting to meet you there.”
McCurry took the photograph of the 17-year-old western lowland gorilla that went on to become a meme. In it, Harambe kneels, projecting a fearsome aura of strength, nobility and calm. A former volunteer photographer at Cincinnati zoo, McCurry was there on 28 May 2016, the fateful day a three-year-old boy climbed into the gorilla’s enclosure, forcing zookeepers to shoot Harambe dead. “It didn’t seem real at first,” says McCurry, who was a regular visitor to the zoo. “When any of your friends die, it’s hard to process. I was in shock.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sirin Kale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[17 Top Container Garden Flowers For Stunning Summer Pots]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34374</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/container-flowers/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T18:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Container gardening flowers are a must for outdoor summer planters. Whether you’re looking to fill hanging baskets, window boxes, small, or a large pots, you’ll find tons of options on this list of the best flowers for container gardening. One of the most fun things to do in the spring is picking out flowers forContinue Reading
The post 17 Top Container Garden Flowers For Stunning Summer Pots appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Source Hardware Certifications for May 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/21/open-source-hardware-certifications-for-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/21/open-source-hardware-certifications-for-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In May 2021 the Open Source Hardware Association (OSHWA) certified a wide variety of hardware as open source.  we will have a certified variety collection of Open Source Hardwares, Let’s take a look! (And remember, certification is a free and easy way to show that your hardware complies with the open source hardware definition.) First, […]
The post Open Source Hardware Certifications for May 2021 appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pixel Buds A-Series review: Google’s cheaper but good earbuds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AirPods rivals have top sound, battery and translation features but cost significantly less
Google’s latest AirPods competitors, the Pixel Buds A-Series, get a big price cut and a slightly more comfortable design.
The new Bluetooth earbuds take a cue from Google’s cheaper but great A-Series phones, cutting a few features to cost £100 (US$99) – a full £80 cheaper than their predecessors.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Michael Albert]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/18/maker-spotlight-michael-albert/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/18/maker-spotlight-michael-albert/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First and last name Michael Albert Where are you located?  White Plains, New York What is your day job?  Pop Artist/Owner of Sir Real brand of Natural Foods Do you attend a makerspace/fablab/hackerspace?  Not usually, but I’m looking forward to the Mead Library’s Maker Faire Sheboygan this weekend. Website | Pinterest | Art site What […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Michael Albert appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[17 Best Ground Cover Plants That Grow Well In The Shade]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34012</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/shade-ground-covers/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T17:36:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shade ground covers make an excellent addition to low light areas. Whether you’re looking for something that can take light foot traffic, or simply want to cover the soil in your shade garden, you’ll find lots of options in this list. Ground cover plants are a simple way to add beauty to your shade garden.Continue Reading
The post 17 Best Ground Cover Plants That Grow Well In The Shade appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where to Get Started in Digital Sculpting for 3D Printing]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/where-to-get-started-in-digital-sculpting-for-3d-printing/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/where-to-get-started-in-digital-sculpting-for-3d-printing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T15:44:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital sculpting isn’t as hard as it looks. At least, getting started isn’t that hard. You’ll still have to put in some serious time to get GOOD, but don’t let that scare you off. You may be surprised by how easily you can get something to be proud of, even as an absolute beginner. There […]
The post Where to Get Started in Digital Sculpting for 3D Printing appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How remote work opened the floodgates to ransomware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/17/ransomware-working-from-home-russia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/17/ransomware-working-from-home-russia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With workers outside the ‘castle walls’ of their companies, criminals have it easier – and cryptocurrency hasn’t helped
Ransomware has roared into the headlines in recent weeks after criminal hacking networks, tentatively linked to Russia, launched attacks on the major US meat packing plant JBS and the nation’s largest fuel pipeline. 
Joe Biden and his administration are scrambling to address the growing threat, pressing Vladimir Putin in a highly anticipated meeting on Wednesday to take action against the rise of ransomware attacks. Biden said he gave Putin a list of 16 areas – mostly in critical infrastructure - that are “off limits” for cyber-attacks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eat Just is racing to put ‘no-kill meat’ on your plate. Is it too good to be true?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/16/eat-just-no-kill-meat-chicken-josh-tetrick</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/16/eat-just-no-kill-meat-chicken-josh-tetrick"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The California startup leads a global push toward lab-grown meat. But experts question its bold claims
In December of last year, a handful of diners sat down to a futuristic meal at 1880, a members-only restaurant in Singapore. The star ingredient was “no-kill” chicken – raised not on a farm but in a laboratory bioreactor. Attendees snacked on lab-grown nuggets paired with crispy maple waffles, bao buns, and black bean puree.
For the California entrepreneur Josh Tetrick, it was a breakthrough. His company, Eat Just, had become the first in the world to sell the product after receiving approval from Singapore authorities. Headlines hailed a landmark step in the quest to end animal agriculture, upend the meat industry and redefine our diets.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erin McCormick in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface Laptop 4 review: Windows 10 as it is meant to be]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-review-windows-10-battery-keyboard-face-recognition</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-review-windows-10-battery-keyboard-face-recognition"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T06:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Premium PC with new choice of faster chips, eight-hour battery, great keyboard and face recognition 
Microsoft’s sleek and stylish Surface Laptop is back for its fourth generation with faster performance and a greater variety of chips.
The Surface Laptop 4 is available with either a 13.5in or a 15in screen and starts at £999 in the UK, $999 in the US or $1,599 in Australia sitting above the Surface Laptop Go as Microsoft’s mainstream premium notebook, competing with the similarly priced Dell XPS 13 and Apple MacBook Air, among others.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Age of the cyber-attack: US struggles to curb rise of digital destabilization]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/age-of-the-cyber-attack-us-digital-destabilization</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/age-of-the-cyber-attack-us-digital-destabilization"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T06:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ransomware attack that caused long lines for fuel on the east coast was just part of a dramatic change in the scale and nature of foreign-based threats
It’s been 40 years since Lisa Donnan has queued for gas. But last month the cybersecurity expert found herself joining the long lines of cars across the east coast of the US looking for fuel after the latest in a series of cyber-attacks had shut down the pipeline that provides fuel to 45% of the region.
“The last time I did that was in the Iran crisis,” she said. “My dad had to wait with me.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe in New York and Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ransomware is biggest online threat to people in UK, spy agency chief to warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/ransomware-is-biggest-online-threat-to-people-in-uk-spy-agency-chief-to-warn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/ransomware-is-biggest-online-threat-to-people-in-uk-spy-agency-chief-to-warn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T23:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GCHQ cybersecurity boss sounds alarm over extortion by hackers who are mostly based in former Soviet states
Ransomware represents the biggest threat to online security for most people and businesses in the UK, the head of GCHQ’s cybersecurity arm is to warn.
Lindy Cameron, chief executive of the National Cyber Security Centre, will say in a speech that the phenomenon, where hackers encrypt data and demand payment for it to be restored, is escalating and becoming increasingly professionalised.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh Defence and security editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Straight story? The YouTuber taking a direct route to success]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/straight-story-the-youtuber-taking-a-direct-route-to-success</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/straight-story-the-youtuber-taking-a-direct-route-to-success"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T17:02:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Davies has 925,000 subscribers who watch his attempts to cross countries without making a turn

When Tom Davies and his stepbrother, Greg, were growing up on the edge of Aldridge, a town in the West Midlands, they would pick a point in the distance, a TV mast for instance, and make their way straight there, even if it meant clambering through quarries, sneaking across railway tracks and running away from angry farmers.
Now Davies has channelled this childhood taste for adventure into a YouTube series following his attempts to traverse entire countries in a direct line, based on GPS tracking.
The scrapes he finds himself in along the way, from almost drowning in swollen rivers and slashing his hand on barbed wire in Wales to a run-in with the police in Scotland, combined with his laid-back humour (he describes Norway as “Wales on steroids”), have garnered him a huge fanbase, with 925,000 subscribers to his channel.
Videos documenting his most recent “straight line mission” across Scotland are currently racking up hundreds of thousands of views, with the next episode set to go live on Sunday – and each one could be his last as obstacles threaten to cut short his journey..
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>