<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-07-07T00:34:11.207Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-07-07T00:34:11.207Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Republican National Committee denies Russian hackers accessed data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/06/republican-national-committee-denies-hack-synnex</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/06/republican-national-committee-denies-hack-synnex"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T23:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Report says RNC computers were breached by Cozy Bear hackers, accused of DNC hack in 2016
The US Republican National Committee has denied that Russian hackers accessed data during a breach of third-party provider last week.
The hackers were part of APT29 or Cozy Bear, according to Bloomberg, citing two unnamed people familiar with the matter. The group is linked with Russia’s foreign intelligence service, the SVR, and was previously accused of hacking the Democratic National Committee in 2016, as well as carrying out the historic cybersecurity breach against SolarWinds, which affected about 100 US companies and nine federal agencies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK supercomputer Cambridge-1 to hunt for medical breakthroughs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/07/uk-supercomputer-cambridge-1-to-hunt-for-medical-breakthroughs</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/07/uk-supercomputer-cambridge-1-to-hunt-for-medical-breakthroughs"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T23:01:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Computer – the most powerful in Britain – will use AI to find new cures and deepen understanding of diseases
The UK’s most powerful supercomputer, which its creators hope will make the process of preventing, diagnosing and treating disease better, faster and cheaper, is operational.
Christened Cambridge-1, the supercomputer represents a $100m investment by US-based computing company Nvidia. The idea capitalises on artificial intelligence (AI) – which combines big data with computer science to facilitate problem-solving – in healthcare. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Natalie Grover Science correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[See-Through Carburetor Gives A Clear Demonstration]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=485131</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/06/see-through-carburetor-gives-a-clear-demonstration/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T23:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Carburetors have been largely phased out on most automobiles, but for a century they were the standard, and still are on many smaller engines. Armed with a high-speed camera and …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Danie Conradie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Count Reps and Sets of an Exercise When Your Brain Just Won't Pay Attention]]></title>
        <id>1847239060</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-count-reps-and-sets-of-an-exercise-when-your-bra-1847239060"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Counting is hard. Yeah, it was easy enough when we were in kindergarten, but fast forward a little and suddenly you’re an adult who can’t manage to count past 10 when there’s a weight in your hand. You’re not alone! Especially if you’re doing anything for higher reps or for more than a few sets, it’s normal to lose…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What to Pack for a Day at the Beach Without Kids]]></title>
        <id>1847237933</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/what-to-pack-for-a-day-at-the-beach-without-kids-1847237933"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you’re planning a family trip to the beach, you probably pack with kids in mind. But an adult beach day requires a different set of items. It’s time to trade in your kids’ toys for card games, beach sports, music, liquor, and more. Here’s how to pack for a grown-up day by the water.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[E-Paper Pocket Map Goes Where Your Phone Can’t]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=485041</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/06/e-paper-pocket-map-goes-where-your-phone-cant/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T20:00:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s easy to take for granted the constantly-connected, GPS-equipped, navigation device most of us now carry in our pockets. Want to know how to get to that new restaurant you …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Nardi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[13 Safari Settings You Should Change to Make It a Better Browser]]></title>
        <id>1847236951</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/13-safari-settings-you-should-change-to-make-a-better-b-1847236951"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Safari is a perfectly good browser in its own right, but its default settings can understandably frustrate those switching over from Chrome and Firefox. Basic features—such as the showing expanded URLs in the status bar, for example—are disabled, which is less than ideal. Here’s how to fix some of those annoyances,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranay Parab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Best Career Advice of 2021 So Far]]></title>
        <id>1847235546</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/our-best-career-advice-of-2021-so-far-1847235546"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To forge a career is to accept a life of constant learning, which means always being open to soaking up the wisdom of those with greater insight. Though we’re only halfway through 2021, we’ve encountered and shared so much potentially life-changing career advice this year—a year during which the continuing pandemic…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Blum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Story of Film: A New Generation review – invigorating study of 21st century cinema]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/06/the-story-of-film-a-new-generation-review-invigorating-study-of-21st-century-cinema</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/06/the-story-of-film-a-new-generation-review-invigorating-study-of-21st-century-cinema"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T19:27:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critic and film-maker Mark Cousins offers a new instalment in his monumental Story of Film series, examining what digital technology has brought to the table
Critic and documentary film-maker Mark Cousins has returned to Cannes with another episode of his amazingly ambitious cinephile history The Story of Film, an illuminated patchwork clip-quilt, accompanied by his inimitable incantation-voiceover. It’s another example of his unique approach: Cousins is subjective almost to the point of free-associating or even sleep-talking (maybe appropriate for the dream state of the movies) but also colossally well-informed, bracingly internationalist and genuinely educational. I have never yet watched a Cousins film without learning something and being a bit sheepish about what I didn’t know.
That said, Cousins’s style takes some getting used to – almost like a hyper-innocent form of criticism, wide-eyed with wonder at cinema’s brave new world, a Miranda of the movies. Occasionally Cousins’s commentary verges on the superfluous, simply describing what is on screen, although there is almost always a shrewd insight there: he has a great section on a creepy travelling shot in David Robert Mitchell’s psychological horror It Follows.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Keep a Stash of Mini Candy Bars in My Freezer]]></title>
        <id>1847236172</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/why-i-keep-a-stash-of-mini-candy-bars-in-my-freezer-1847236172"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When I was about six years old, my mother, sisters, and I moved from Aberdeen, Mississippi to Los Angeles, California. My dad stayed in the South, and the twins and I would visit him during the summer. I don’t know if you’ve ever been to northern Mississippi in July, but it is very hot, humid, and full of bugs.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[USB Power Bank’s Auto-Off Becomes Useful Feature In Garage Door Remote]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=484954</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/06/usb-power-banks-auto-off-becomes-useful-feature-in-garage-door-remote/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T18:30:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For devices that are destined for momentary and infrequent use as well as battery power, some kind of power saving is pretty much a required feature. For example, when [PJ …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donald Papp</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Tell When Your Child Needs a Therapist (and How to Find One)]]></title>
        <id>1847233297</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-tell-when-your-child-needs-a-therapist-and-how-1847233297"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The past year has been rough on all of us, including our kids. Many of our kids are still too young to be vaccinated and yet they will be expected to return to in-person school in the fall, where in addition to the normal stressors of school, there will be the added stress of processing the events of the last year.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Fairbank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Download Spotify Songs to Your Apple Watch Instead of Streaming Them]]></title>
        <id>1847236084</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-download-spotify-songs-to-your-apple-watch-inste-1847236084"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spotify has finally delivered what we once called the “Holy Grail of smartphone streaming”—the ability to download songs to your watch, so you can listen to them even when your phone is at home and you’re jogging through the woods without a data connection. The feature is rolling out now, although you’ll need a…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Grow Orchids Without Killing Them]]></title>
        <id>1847223688</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-grow-orchids-without-killing-them-1847223688"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Orchids are known for being tricky: They’re delicate, require watering and misting, and they need proper drainage and just the right amount of light. That level of plant care can be overwhelming, but once you’ve got a routine, you’ll knock it out of the park. Here’s how to care for an orchid in your home.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Be an Adult, With Julie Lythcott-Haims]]></title>
        <id>1847236367</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-be-an-adult-with-julie-lythcott-haims-1847236367"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[How do you know when you’re officially an adult? When is it okay to quit a job, and when should you stick it out? How the heck do you figure out what you want to do with your life?
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Micaela Heck</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Chop a Potato Without It Sticking to Your Knife]]></title>
        <id>1847235390</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-chop-a-potato-without-it-sticking-to-your-knife-1847235390"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T17:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most potatoes need a little knife work before you cook and eat them; unless you are baking whole spuds to consume alongside a juicy steak, slicing and dicing is just part of the process. The premise behind chopping a potato is simple: Steady the potato on a cutting board and push or drag your knife through it. Repeat…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Fu: PDF for Penguins]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=484877</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/06/linux-fu-pdf-for-penguins/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T17:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PostScript started out as a programming language for printers. While PostScript printers are still a thing, there are many other ways to send data to a printer. But PostScript also …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Al Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enlist in the Chicken Wars for National Fried Chicken Day]]></title>
        <id>1847235528</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/enlist-in-the-chicken-wars-for-national-fried-chicken-d-1847235528"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you didn’t know it already, today is National Fried Chicken Day, and a bunch of restaurant chains are offering discounts and freebies on their fried chicken menu items. Considering that there’s chicken shortages amidst a raging “chicken sandwich war,” it’s not clear that Americans need more incentives to eat…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 of the Best Audacity Alternatives]]></title>
        <id>1847230891</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/10-of-the-best-audacity-alternatives-1847230891"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Audacity has been the go-to free audio editing app for years, but its recent privacy policy changes mention invasive data collection practices that are (rightfully) making a lot of people very uncomfortable.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranay Parab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Pollinate Squash By Hand For Maximum Production]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34564</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/pollinating-squash/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T16:27:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pollinating squash by hand is easy, will ensure higher yields, and doesn’t take much time. In this post, I will explain why your baby squash keep falling off, and discuss the processes of hand pollinating the flowers step-by-step. One of the biggest struggles that newbies face when growing vegetables for the first time is havingContinue Reading
The post How To Pollinate Squash By Hand For Maximum Production appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Disable Spotlight Search on Mac (and Replace It With Something Better)]]></title>
        <id>1847227585</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-disable-spotlight-search-on-mac-and-replace-it-1847227585"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spotlight Search is Mac’s built-in search feature. It shows up when you use the Command + Space keyboard shortcut, or when you click the Search icon in the menu bar to hunt for a file somewhere on your machine.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Over a Post-Pandemic Fear of Crowds]]></title>
        <id>1847223360</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-get-over-a-post-pandemic-fear-of-crowds-1847223360"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine this: You’re out with your friends at a park or a beer garden when one of them suggests going into a bar. Two summers ago, that’d be no big deal, but after such a long time away from crowds during the pandemic, you might be a little nervous.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Ellefson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘I can’t remember feeling as excited about the future’: redesigning space travel for women]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/careers/2021/jul/06/i-cant-remember-feeling-as-excited-about-the-future-redesigning-space-travel-for-women</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/careers/2021/jul/06/i-cant-remember-feeling-as-excited-about-the-future-redesigning-space-travel-for-women"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:15:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The drive for more women and greater diversity in the space sector will lead to new ideas and innovations, from spacesuits to toilets and beyond

“Remember when Nasa sent a woman to space for only six days and they gave her 100 tampons and asked will that be enough?” So goes last year’s viral TikTok referring to astronaut Sally Ride being asked by Nasa engineers in 1983 whether 100 tampons would be sufficient for her week-long stay in space (she was not actually sent with them).
Recalling the incident some years later, Ride, America’s first woman astronaut, said: “There were probably some other, similar sorts of issues, just because they had never thought about what kind of personal equipment a female astronaut would take.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kieran Yates</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lightwave Multimeter Teardown]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=484750</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/06/lightwave-multimeter-teardown/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You tend to think of test equipment in fairly basic terms: a multimeter, a power supply, a signal generator, and an oscilloscope. However, there are tons of highly-specialized test equipment …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Al Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Audacity Really Spyware?]]></title>
        <id>1847230028</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/is-audacity-really-spyware-1847230028"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Audacity is an open-source audio editor popular among podcasters and musicians. In May 2021, Audacity was acquired by Muse group, and this is where the story begins.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Stefan Hermann of CNC Kitchen]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/06/maker-spotlight-stefan-hermann-of-cnc-kitchen/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/06/maker-spotlight-stefan-hermann-of-cnc-kitchen/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First and last name Stefan Hermann Where are you located?  Germany What is your day job?  Metal Additive Manufacturing Research Engineer Youtube Channel | Patreon What kinds of stuff do you make?  3D Printing Stuff, Material Tests and 3D Printing Research How did you get started making stuff?  Bought a book about Arduino, purchased a […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Stefan Hermann of CNC Kitchen appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Stop Nintendo From Sharing Your eShop Data With Google Analytics]]></title>
        <id>1847222162</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-stop-nintendo-from-sharing-your-eshop-data-with-1847222162"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whenever you buy a game through the Nintendo Switch eShop, Nintendo collects and shares your shopping data with Google analytics. Nintendo has done this for a long time, but some users may not be aware of—or comfortable with—the practice.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Hesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ransomware hackers demand $70m after attack on US software firm Kaseya]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/06/kaseya-ransomware-hackers-attack</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/06/kaseya-ransomware-hackers-attack"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T14:11:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between 800 and 1,500 businesses around the world, including supermarkets and dentists’ offices, affected by attack
Between 800 and 1,500 businesses around the world have been affected by a ransomware attack centered on the US information technology firm Kaseya, its chief executive said on Monday.
 Related: Republicans’ effort to deny the Capitol attack is working – and it’s dangerous 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TerraPower’s Natrium: Combining A Fast Neutron Reactor With Built-In Grid Level Storage]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=482428</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/06/terrapowers-natrium-combining-a-fast-neutron-reactor-with-built-in-grid-level-storage/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T14:01:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most new nuclear fission reactors being built today are of the light water reactor (LWR) type, which use water for neutron moderation into thermal neutrons as well as neutron capture. …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Posch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why the 'Slow Fade' Is Worse Than Ghosting]]></title>
        <id>1847227847</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/why-the-slow-fade-is-worse-than-ghosting-1847227847"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many people can’t stomach the confrontation of a break up, so they might offer the vague promise of continuing the relationship with a series of noncommittal overtures. Basically, they might kind of, sort of, maybe have time for you eventually, but in reality they’re hoping the relationship will slowly whither without…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Blum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Filthy water killed my chickens, says Khayelitsha protester]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/khayelitsha-resident-says-most-his-chickens-died-after-drinking-overflowing-water-pump-station/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/khayelitsha-resident-says-most-his-chickens-died-after-drinking-overflowing-water-pump-station/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T13:54:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shack dwellers demand the nearby sewage pump station be fixed]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Hide Your Nudes in Google Photos]]></title>
        <id>1847219237</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-hide-your-sensitive-pictures-in-google-photos-1847219237"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If, for some reason, you have taken photos on your phone that you don’t want just anyone to see, you may want to use some sort of privacy feature. While there are third party apps that can hide your intimate photos, Google recently announced a new feature to lock your private images directly in Google Photos.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Kahn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Qualify for Free Healthcare If You're Unemployed]]></title>
        <id>1847215619</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-qualify-for-free-healthcare-if-youre-unemployed-1847215619"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As of July 1, unemployed Americans qualify for hefty Obamacare subsidies that, for 60% of them, reduces their premiums to $0 per month. If you were unemployed at any time in 2021, you might qualify for a new plan by visiting the Health Insurance Marketplace between now and August 15, when an ongoing special enrollment…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google, Facebook and other tech companies threaten to quit Hong Kong over privacy law]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/06/google-facebook-and-other-tech-companies-threaten-to-quit-hong-kong-over-privacy-law</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/06/google-facebook-and-other-tech-companies-threaten-to-quit-hong-kong-over-privacy-law"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T12:04:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Asia Internet Coalition, including Twitter and Apple, sounds warning over amendments to laws that could see individuals hit with ‘severe sanctions’
Tech giants including Google, Facebook, and Twitter could stop offering services to Hong Kong if the city moves forward with laws to impose penalties on users who publicly release identifying information about individual or organisations,an Asian industry group has warned.
The Asia Internet Coalition, which counts the three major companies as well as Apple Inc and LinkedIn as members, wrote to Hong Kong’s Privacy Commissioner to warn that privacy laws which could see undefined “severe sanctions” against individuals for so-called doxing were “not aligned with global norms and trends”. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Helen Davidson in Taipei</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[In defence of email, the tech marvel we couldn’t do without | Joanne McNeil]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/06/email-inbox-anxiety-work</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/06/email-inbox-anxiety-work"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T11:33:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t blame the medium for our inbox anxiety. The more fundamental issue is how work dominates our lives
I am about to defend the seemingly indefensible: email, the inbox, all of it. And yes, I’m offering this case at a time when it might sound especially unlikely. This is the season of holiday responder messages and out-of-office replies. The back-and-forth of delayed communications makes email an especially draining project during the summer.
I’m not unfamiliar with the paralysing anxiety that settles in when I see a notification that my unread messages total some ungodly number. I probably owe an email to a percentage of people reading this. (Sorry! Things are a bit busy!) And I’d love to never see the words “hope this message finds you well” again in my life. But the decentralised wonder that is email isn’t the cause of my stress; the real problem is work and too much of it, as relayed through these messages. When it comes to communications systems, email – a technology that’s 50 years old this year – is hard to beat.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joanne McNeil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Source Ultrasonic Anemometer]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=481916</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/06/open-source-ultrasonic-anemometer/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T11:00:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Weather stations are a popular project for experimenting with various environmental sensors, and for wind speed and direction the choice is usually a simple cup anemometer and wind vane. For …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Danie Conradie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Makhanda municipality dodges responsiblity for abandoned houses]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/rdp-homes-abandoned-first-their-owners-then-municipality-are-magnet-crime-say-makhanda-residents/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/rdp-homes-abandoned-first-their-owners-then-municipality-are-magnet-crime-say-makhanda-residents/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T10:35:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Empty RDP houses attract crime, say residents]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[There is no right to carry a gun under our Constitution]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/there-no-right-carry-gun-under-our-constitution/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/there-no-right-carry-gun-under-our-constitution/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T09:19:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yet much debate on the Firearms Control Amendment Bill is based on the “right” to have a gun for self-defence]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Protesters demanding water stone cars in Dunoon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/water-protesters-stone-cars-dunoon/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/water-protesters-stone-cars-dunoon/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T07:29:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residents in Zwelitsha informal settlement have been without potable water for weeks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Court dismisses Observatory occupants’ application against City of Cape Town]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/former-circus-school-occupants-lose-court-bid-to-exclude-the-citys-housing-report/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/former-circus-school-occupants-lose-court-bid-to-exclude-the-citys-housing-report/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T03:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A date for the final hearing on the eviction case is yet to be determined]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese-owned firm acquires UK’s largest semiconductor manufacturer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/05/chinese-owned-firm-acquires-uks-largest-semiconductor-manufacturer</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/05/chinese-owned-firm-acquires-uks-largest-semiconductor-manufacturer"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T18:13:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tory MP Tom Tugendhat raises concerns about deal in light of global computer chip shortage
The UK’s largest producer of semiconductors has been acquired by the Chinese-owned manufacturer Nexperia, prompting a senior Tory MP to call for the government to review the sale to a foreign owner during an increasingly severe global shortage of computer chips.
Nexperia, a Dutch firm owned by China’s Wingtech, said on Monday that it had taken full control of Newport Wafer Fab (NWF), the UK’s largest producer of silicon chips, which are vital in products from TVs and mobile phones to cars and games consoles.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mark Sweney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Break Into the Legal Weed Industry]]></title>
        <id>1847223015</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-break-into-the-legal-weed-industry-1847223015"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The weed legalization train is on the move around America, and whether it’s already been through your state or is headed your way, you might be interested in getting into the industry. There’s always been money in marijuana, but now there’s money in marijuana that you can actually talk about with the stranger across…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Ellefson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 7 Types of Rest, and How to Get the Kind You Need]]></title>
        <id>1847223651</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-7-types-of-rest-and-how-to-get-the-kind-you-need-1847223651"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a long time, our default answer to the question “How are you?” has been “fine,” or some variation of it. But over the past few years—and especially during the pandemic—another response is becoming increasingly common: Telling the person who asked that you’re “tired,” or even “exhausted.”

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Barker obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/tom-barker-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/tom-barker-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T14:29:48.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My grandfather Tom Barker, who has died of cancer aged 84, was a pivotal figure in mechanical engineering. He collaborated with some of the world’s best architects, putting heat, sound, light and air at the forefront of design. As director of Ove Arup & Partners (now Arup Group), the global engineering company, he was known for his work on the Pompidou Centre in Paris and the Lloyd’s building in London, among many others.
Tom led Arup’s engineering group for 26 years, designing for key projects such as the Menil Collection museum in Houston, Texas, and Kansai international airport in Osaka, Japan, with Peter Rice. 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Phoebe Barker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Use Kitchen Scraps on Your Plants Without Having to Learn Composting]]></title>
        <id>1847223657</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-use-kitchen-scraps-on-your-plants-without-having-1847223657"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We should start by saying that we are not anti-compost. In fact, we have several articles walking you through the ins and outs of the composting process. In a perfect world, everyone would have the time, energy, and space to have their own compost pile or container, and then use the finished product to help their…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sanitation worse than ever after floods hit informal settlement]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/sanitation-worse-ever-after-floods-hit-informal-settlement/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/sanitation-worse-ever-after-floods-hit-informal-settlement/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T13:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residents of Ethembeni in Khayelitsha say they urgently need ten to 15 chemical toilets]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use These Botanical Gardens-Inspired Decor Tips to Make Your Home Feel Like an Oasis]]></title>
        <id>1847223642</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/use-these-botanical-gardens-inspired-decor-tips-to-make-1847223642"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s something very calming about visiting a botanical garden. Perhaps it’s being surrounded by foliage, or taking in the array of colors. Or maybe it’s just nice to be able to enjoy well-manicured and maintained nature where someone else did all the gardening and landscaping work. Whatever the reason, if you’re…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ivermectin: balance of evidence shows no benefit against Covid-19]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/ivermectin-flops-largest-trial-yet/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/ivermectin-flops-largest-trial-yet/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T10:58:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While it’s too soon to say that the drug is useless, it has clearly been overhyped]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Man accused of stealing a cellphone and set alight recovers in hospital from severe burns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/durban-man-accused-of-stealing-a-cellphone-was-set-alight-by-a-mob-he-is-in-hospital-with-severe-burn-wounds/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/durban-man-accused-of-stealing-a-cellphone-was-set-alight-by-a-mob-he-is-in-hospital-with-severe-burn-wounds/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T08:58:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At least three people killed every day by vigilantes according to latest quarterly crime stats]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Equal Education goes back to court to force government to feed hungry school children]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/equal-education-goes-back-court-force-government-feed-hungry-school-children/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/equal-education-goes-back-court-force-government-feed-hungry-school-children/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T08:18:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Minister Motshekga and eight provincial education MECs in contempt of court, says NGO]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng police have killed hundreds, but SAPS leaves brutal cops unchecked]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-police-have-killed-hundreds-saps-leave-brutal-cops-unchecked/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-police-have-killed-hundreds-saps-leave-brutal-cops-unchecked/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T08:03:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Official statistics show no Gauteng officers have been disciplined for violent offences since 2016]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Venu 2 review: can Garmin make a good smartwatch?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/venu-2-review-can-garmin-make-a-good-smartwatch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/venu-2-review-can-garmin-make-a-good-smartwatch"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T06:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fitness firm’s new Apple Watch-rival looks the part and tracks loads of data but lacks some real smarts
Garmin’s latest device aims to beat the Apple Watch and rivals at their own game, offering longer battery life and better fitness tracking in a more traditional touchscreen smartwatch body.
The Venu 2 comes in either 40mm or 45mm models, costs from £349.99 ($399.99/A$629) and is compatible with both Android and iPhones connecting via Bluetooth.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uninstall These Malicious Android Apps That Stole Facebook Passwords]]></title>
        <id>1847227502</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/uninstall-these-malicious-android-apps-that-stole-faceb-1847227502"/>
        <updated>2021-07-04T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers from Dr. Web have found nine apps with more than 5.8 million combined downloads that were sneakily stealing user’s Facebook passwords using a genuine Facebook login page. As of writing, Google has  banned the developer and removed these nine apps from the Play Store, but if you’ve downloaded any of them,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Paid $5,000 to Do Summer Activities That Are Already on Your List]]></title>
        <id>1847221891</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/get-paid-5-000-to-do-summer-activities-that-are-alread-1847221891"/>
        <updated>2021-07-04T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you think of the classic summer jobs for young adults, things like lifeguarding, scooping ice cream, or mowing lawns might come to mind. (And honestly don’t sound half bad.) But then you grow up, and there’s no such thing as summer vacation, and your summer job is also your fall job, winter job, and spring job.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep sea robots will let us find millions of shipwrecks, says man who discovered Titanic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jul/04/deep-sea-robots-will-let-us-find-millions-of-shipwrecks-says-man-who-discovered-titanic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2021/jul/04/deep-sea-robots-will-let-us-find-millions-of-shipwrecks-says-man-who-discovered-titanic"/>
        <updated>2021-07-04T10:00:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A revolutionary new class of amphibious vehicle will transform the search for lost vessels on the ocean floor, says marine archaeologist Dr Robert Ballard

He is the celebrated deep-sea explorer who discovered the Titanic, as well as the German battleship Bismarck and other historic sunken vessels around the world.
Now Dr Robert Ballard is pioneering cutting-edge technology – autonomous underwater vehicles that will “revolutionise” the search for more than three million shipwrecks that lie scattered across ocean floors, according to a Unesco estimate. Many will offer new insights into life on board at the time of sinking, hundreds or even thousands of years ago.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dalya Alberge</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This space race has its downside… Rocketwoman Wally Funk joins crew for Jeff Bezos’s ego trip]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/04/this-space-race-has-its-downside-rocketwoman-wally-funk-joins-crew-for-jeff-bezoss-ego-trip</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/04/this-space-race-has-its-downside-rocketwoman-wally-funk-joins-crew-for-jeff-bezoss-ego-trip"/>
        <updated>2021-07-04T09:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The veteran US pilot is set to become the oldest woman in space – the only snag is she has to go with the Amazon billionaire 
You have to feel for the American pilot Wally Funk. You would sympathise with anyone with that name, but she has had a particularly mixed week. On one hand, at 82, she is set to finally fulfil her life’s ambition and travel into space. Funk was one of the most promising female candidates for the Mercury 13 programme in the 1960s, but was denied a spot because of her gender. Right stuff, wrong parts. On Thursday, the Amazon founder, Jeff Bezos, announced on Instagram that Wally would become the oldest person in space as one of the four passengers on New Shepard, the rocket being launched by his company Blue Origin on 20 July. “I didn’t think I’d ever get to go up,” Funk said in an interview.
The obvious downside, which she was too polite to mention, is that she has to ride with Bezos, his brother and one other, in a kind of UberPool from hell. She ought to have been more specific to the genie. Midlife does strange things to men, and so does being a billionaire. The combination leads to some odd outcomes. Not content with building his own rockets, Jeff, as he approaches 60, has decided to start riding them as well. Towers and yachts are so passé. Private space travel is the thing. Elon Musk is at it, too, and presumably a load of guys in China.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Cumming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden announces investigation into international ransomware attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/kaseya-ransomware-attack-us-sweden</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/kaseya-ransomware-attack-us-sweden"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T21:43:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President addresses hack of Kaseya software that has affected hundreds of US businesses and shut down Swedish shops
Joe Biden said on Saturday he had directed US intelligence agencies to investigate a sophisticated ransomware attack that hit hundreds of American businesses as the Fourth of July holiday weekend began and aroused suspicions of Russian gang involvement.
 Related: Joe Biden cherry-picks audience to promote bipartisan infrastructure deal 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The week in audio: Pieces of Britney; Elon Musk: The Evening Rocket; Human Resources and more]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/03/pieces-of-britney-review-elon-musk-the-evening-rocket-human-resources-the-essay-caribbean-voices-the-kindness-experiment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/03/pieces-of-britney-review-elon-musk-the-evening-rocket-human-resources-the-essay-caribbean-voices-the-kindness-experiment"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T16:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Radio 4 series on Britney Spears’s troubles and Elon Musk’s space ambitions highlight society’s double standards
Pieces of Britney (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Elon Musk: The Evening Rocket (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Human Resources Broccoli Productions | Spotify
The Essay: Caribbean Voices (Radio 3) | BBC Sounds
The Kindness Experiment (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Britney Spears has been in the news a lot over the past few weeks. Her recent court plea to be released from legal conservatorship was horrible and shocking; and also rejected. Judge Brenda Penny ruled last Wednesday that the current situation – where Britney’s father Jamie is a co-conservator, even though he’s ill – should stay in place. Pain, when expressed by a woman, is often disbelieved and ignored.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Sawyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Only batteries have the power to save British carmaking]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/03/only-batteries-have-the-power-to-save-british-carmaking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/03/only-batteries-have-the-power-to-save-british-carmaking"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T15:00:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nissan’s ‘gigafactory’ in Sunderland must be the first of many sites if the UK is to compete in the electric vehicle era
The British government’s £100m-plus commitment to secure Nissan’s battery gigafactory for Sunderland has been like gadget-shopping on Amazon writ large: splurging on some new technology that has suddenly become essential – and then being immediately prompted to buy another six.
This time, though, duplicating the spending looks more sensible. More gigafactories – or plain old big battery factories – are not essential for the UK to transition to using electric vehicles (EVs). But they certainly will be if Britain hopes to keep making, selling and exporting its own cars.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Gwyn Topham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Umurangi Generation review – chic photographic hide-and-seek]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/03/umurangi-generation-review-photography-hide-and-seek-maori</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/03/umurangi-generation-review-photography-hide-and-seek-maori"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T12:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this compelling game, your mission is to locate and photograph a series of images in a Māori-influenced world under occupation
Many contemporary video games include a “photo mode” to enable the player to pause the action, position a virtual camera and take a snapshot of a scene (and then, the designers surely hope, post the results online, enabling grassroots marketing). Few make photography the entire point of the enterprise, however. Nintendo’s recent Pokémon Snap asked us to capture images of its mythic animals doing noteworthy things on safari-style tours, before grading the results. Umurangi Generation, another rare example of the genre, is less interested in making value judgments about your virtual photography (“Art is subjective,” the game’s tutorial assures); instead, you are whisked to a series of highly stylised scenes and given 10 minutes to collect a set of specific shots to a tight brief: seven birds, two boomboxes, a mountain, and so on.
The world is rendered in jagged polygons straight out of a late-90s PlayStation game (early-era 3D has now replaced 80s pixel art as the throwback trend in games), lending each image produced a nu-vintage appeal. Framing and focusing shots is elegantly straightforward, as is switching between lenses. You can jump, crouch, rotate the frame and, using three sliders, adjust the colour, tint and exposure within seconds.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Parkin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alcohol bans reduced deaths, study finds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/alcohol-bans-reduced-deaths-study-finds/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/alcohol-bans-reduced-deaths-study-finds/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T09:24:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[UCT and MRC researchers found that dozens of deaths a day were averted by restrictions]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cryptocurrency scam costs online dating user £20,000]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/cryptocurrency-scam-online-dating-covid-binance-grindr</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/cryptocurrency-scam-online-dating-covid-binance-grindr"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T08:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Internet cons have surged in the Covid crisis, with some victims left with little recourse to recover cash
In early May, James Evans* met a man on the dating app Grindr. The man, who said his name was David, was friendly and chatty. “It started off as a normal conversation,” says Evans. “We moved to WhatsApp and exchanged messages. After a few days he started telling me about crypto trading and how he could show me how it worked and how I could earn money from it. It seemed like a genuine connection.”
Unfortunately for Evans, , that wasn’t the case. He hadhooked up with a scammer, who within a week had convinced him to hand over £20,000.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hilary Osborne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Andy Jassy steps out of the shadows – so who exactly is Amazon’s new CEO?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/03/who-is-andy-jassy-new-amazon-ceo-jeff-bezos</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/03/who-is-andy-jassy-new-amazon-ceo-jeff-bezos"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T05:00:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The elevation of the man behind the Cloud while Jeff Bezos relinquishes day-to-day control, comes at a critical time for Amazon 
Andy Jassy made a powerful – and painful – first impression on the billionaire Amazon founder Jeff Bezos soon after he joined the then start-up bookseller in 1997.
During a rambunctious game of “broomball” – a cross between lacrosse and football that another Amazon executive invented and is still overly competitively played at the company – Jassy, then a fresh-faced recruit from Harvard Business School, accidentally hit Bezos over the head with a kayak paddle.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate Wealth correspondent and Sarah Butler</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[ECD staff, social workers, and SASSA tellers could be vaccinated soon, says Minister Zulu]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/ecd-staff-social-workers-and-sassa-tellers-could-be-vaccinated-soon-says-minister-zulu/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/ecd-staff-social-workers-and-sassa-tellers-could-be-vaccinated-soon-says-minister-zulu/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T12:23:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ECD staff remain sceptical, demand Zulu commits to timelines]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where are our ward councillors? ask flood victims]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/where-are-our-ward-councillors-ask-flood-victims/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/where-are-our-ward-councillors-ask-flood-victims/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T12:11:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shacks flooded by heavy rains in Khayelitsha]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Postpone elections, say top doctors, but little consensus at Moseneke commission]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/postpone-elections-say-top-doctors-little-consensus-moseneke-commission/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/postpone-elections-say-top-doctors-little-consensus-moseneke-commission/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T11:20:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[ANC and DA want October poll to proceed]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taxi bosses surprise drivers with Covid-19 inspection]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/taxi-bosses-surprise-drivers-inspection-after-commuter-complaints-over-covid-19-compliance/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/taxi-bosses-surprise-drivers-inspection-after-commuter-complaints-over-covid-19-compliance/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T09:58:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Association warns drivers to wear masks and sanitise, or face penalties from Monday]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wildermyth review – fantasy RPG with real heart and soul]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/02/wildermyth-review-worldwalker-games-pc</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/02/wildermyth-review-worldwalker-games-pc"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T07:30:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PC; Worldwalker Games
Witty writing, evocative art and engrossing battles combine in a wonderful homage to classic tabletop games
Fantasy role-playing games love saying that the real treasure was the friends we made along the way, but, for most, literal treasure remains the focus. Who’s got time for the business of human companionship, after all, when there are Platinum Swords of Eldritch to track down? Thank the old gods, then, for Wildermyth, a sumptuous virtual tabletop experience from a tiny Texas studio that plays like a tale told over a campfire, deep in the woods.
Each Wildermyth session is a colourful mix of scripted events and random occurrences, but they all go something like this: a band of peasants take up arms against otherworldly horrors. You move them around a swirling parchment map, scouting regions, defeating the local bogeymen and driving back regular full-scale invasions of tentacle demons, goblins and skeletal machines.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Edwin Evans-Thirlwell</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire HD 10 Plus (2021) review: Amazon’s top budget tablet upgraded]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/fire-hd-10-plus-2021-review-amazons-top-budget-tablet-upgraded</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/fire-hd-10-plus-2021-review-amazons-top-budget-tablet-upgraded"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T06:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Slimmer, better design, long battery life, 10.1in HD screen and speakers makes for a good TV tablet
Amazon’s top 10in Fire OS tablet has had a makeover and now has faster performance, without costing iPad money.
The 2021 Fire HD 10 comes in either a standard version costing £150/US$150 or a “Plus” version, as tested here, costing £180/US$180, with a few more bells and whistles.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[British Scandal serves up tabloid trouble – podcasts of the week]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/02/british-scandal-serves-up-tabloid-trouble-podcasts-of-the-week</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/02/british-scandal-serves-up-tabloid-trouble-podcasts-of-the-week"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T05:00:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alice Levine and Matt Forde delve into the News International phone-hacking scandal. Plus: spoofy horror in Summer Camp Massacre, and an insightful look at trans rights in sport
British Scandal 
The new season of the dirt-dishing podcast sees Alice Levine and Matt Forde delve into the News International phone-hacking scandal, with Rebekah Brooks and Andy Coulson under the spotlight. There is a fair bit of sexing-up of the situation as Brooks “pushes her unruly red ringlets out of her face” and Coulson quaffs champagne from the bottle at Stringfellows. But despite some My Dad Wrote a Porno-esque moments, the details of journalists bugging celebrities’ phones for News of the World exclusives are genuinely shocking. Hannah Verdier
Summer Camp Massacre 
Adam Peacock is the host of this seasonal spin-off of horror spoof My Neighbours Are Dead. There’s a killer on the loose at a Michigan summer camp, so Peacock starts off by interviewing Chet, the suspiciously chirpy counsellor (Tim Ryder), who’s keen to point out he doesn’t share the murderer’s name. An absurd story about the killer’s work being aided by the children’s inability to run away due to the over-use of calamine lotion is just the beginning. Their conversation gets darker and funnier as it goes on. HV
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hannah Verdier and Danielle Stephens</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emotion and Empathy Are Glue for Makers]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/01/emotion-and-empathy-are-glue-for-makers/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/01/emotion-and-empathy-are-glue-for-makers/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:33:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2020, Dr. Andreea Gorbatai and two co-authors published a research paper in the journal Organization Science titled: “Making Space for Emotions: Empathy, Contagion, and Legitmacy’s Double-Edged Sword.” It’s about the maker movement and what holds it together. It turns out, it’s not skills and tools as much as it is emotions and empathy — […]
The post Emotion and Empathy Are Glue for Makers appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting Brussels Sprouts – Everything You Need To Know]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34562</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/harvesting-brussels-sprouts/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:38:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting brussels sprouts is easier than you might think, and actually kinda fun too! In this post, you’ll learn how to tell when they are ready to pick, plus I’ll show you step by step exactly how to gather them, and even give you tips for using, and storing them for later. Have you everContinue Reading
The post Harvesting Brussels Sprouts – Everything You Need To Know appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to photograph the moon on your phone or camera with the best settings]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/30/how-to-photograph-the-full-moon-with-phone-tips-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/30/how-to-photograph-the-full-moon-with-phone-tips-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings"/>
        <updated>2021-06-30T01:01:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Australia picture editor Carly Earl explains the dos and don’ts of taking pictures of the moon
When a full moon rises, many people will pull out their mobile phones to try and get an Instagram-worthy photograph, but unfortunately it’s really challenging to take a great picture of the moon.
Two reasons: it is very far away and unless you have a telephoto lens (which makes the moon appear closer than it is) it will always appear as a very small glowing dot in the frame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carly Earl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting Kohlrabi – Everything You Need To Know]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34560</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/harvesting-kohlrabi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T18:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting kohlrabi may sound intimidating, but it’s actually very easy. In this post, I’ll show how to tell when they are ready, the best way to pick them, and even give you tips for using and storing your garden fresh kohlrabi harvest. Despite how it may sound, the steps for harvesting kohlrabi are actually veryContinue Reading
The post Harvesting Kohlrabi – Everything You Need To Know appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If You’re Into 3D Printing, You Need To Be Watching CNC Kitchen]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/29/if-youre-into-3d-printing-you-need-to-be-watching-cnc-kitchen/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/29/if-youre-into-3d-printing-you-need-to-be-watching-cnc-kitchen/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T15:04:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CNC Kitchen channel, run by Stefan, is a treasure trove of tests and real data surrounding many 3d printing topics
The post If You’re Into 3D Printing, You Need To Be Watching CNC Kitchen appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Making Of ‘Lord of the Rings’ inspired ‘Fellbeast’ Head]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/28/the-making-of-lord-of-the-rings-inspired-fellbeast-head/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/28/the-making-of-lord-of-the-rings-inspired-fellbeast-head/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Follow along as an artist shares the process of recreating the Fell Beast form the Lord Of The Rings
The post The Making Of ‘Lord of the Rings’ inspired ‘Fellbeast’ Head appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memo to corporate leaders post-Covid: the disruption to businesses has only just begun | John Naughton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/memo-to-corporate-leaders-post-covid-the-disruption-to-businesses-has-only-just-begun</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/memo-to-corporate-leaders-post-covid-the-disruption-to-businesses-has-only-just-begun"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Managerial hierarchies must learn the true lessons of the pandemic if they are to survive and thrive
Pandemics, the historian Yuval Noah Harari has observed, have a way of accelerating history. Just ask the founders of Zoom. Only two years ago, we were all thinking that it would take at least another decade before video-conferencing became an integral part of the way we work in organisations. Then along comes Covid and in three weeks we’re all happily Zooming (or unhappily in the case of Handforth parish council). And now we’re more or less acclimatised or, at any rate, resigned to the idea that remote meetings might be here to stay.
The problem with having had the fast-forward button suddenly propel us into an unexpected place, though, is that we find ourselves unmoored. We start wondering about what lies ahead as the immediate threat of the virus recedes. What will our post-pandemic future be like? In relation to work, three main possibilities are currently taking up all the airtime: continuing to work from home (WFH); a hybrid mode in which we spend some time in the office but also two or three days WFH; and a return to ye olde days commuting to the office to gather round the water cooler and pretend to be doing something useful.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Tickets Now For The Make: Education Forum]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/24/get-tickets-now-for-the-make-education-forum/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/24/get-tickets-now-for-the-make-education-forum/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:18:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The growth of makerspaces in education was interrupted by the shutdown of schools, libraries, and museums over the last year.  Now, as students return to in-person learning, there is an even greater need for maker educators who can provide hands-on making and project-based learning experiences. In addition, making is a practice that can be learned […]
The post Get Tickets Now For The Make: Education Forum appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mario Golf: Super Rush review – madcap golf game switches things up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/24/mario-golf-super-rush-review-madcap-golf-game-switches-things-up</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/24/mario-golf-super-rush-review-madcap-golf-game-switches-things-up"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T14:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch; Camelot
The innovation of players running around after their shots is fun but you may find yourself longing for a leisurely stroll over the course
My first memory of Mario Golf involves showing my dad – who, like many Scottish dads I know, is a steadfastly committed and resolutely mediocre golfer – a round of the Nintendo 64 version when I was a child. I hoped that this might be a potential bonding moment where our worlds temporarily collided, but after patiently watching me play a few holes as Luigi, he failed to see the point. Why not just play real golf, he asked, which to me seemed a bit like asking why you didn’t just become a Premiership footballer instead of watching football on TV. 
It is a question that would make even less sense now. In 1999, Mario Golf was just normal golf with Nintendo characters. This month’s Mario Golf: Super Rush is a mad cartoonish caricature of the sport played by Nintendo characters in fabulously camp outfits, where you have to sprint after your shot as soon as you’ve hit it, ride tornadoes up cliffs to find the ball, and try to avoid the tackles and explosions that other players send your way. Doing any of that down the real-life course on a Sunday would, at best, get you politely removed from the premises.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon crushed the Alabama union drive – can the Teamsters do better?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/amazon-alabama-union-drive-teamsters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/amazon-alabama-union-drive-teamsters"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Teamsters union is rich, strong, and experienced – and it’s ready to help workers and give Amazon a headache  
The announcement that the Teamsters – one of America’s most powerful unions – is going to mount an ambitious campaign to unionize Amazon warehouses across the US presents the e-retailing colossus with a far bigger threat than the recent effort to unionize an Amazon warehouse in Alabama ever did.
 Related: Amazon fired him – now he’s trying to unionize 5,000 workers in New York 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Greenhouse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[E3 2021: 20 games to watch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/24/e3-2021-20-best-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/24/e3-2021-20-best-games"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T08:00:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year’s all-digital video game expo involved a deluge of livestreams showcasing upcoming excitements. Here are our picks
The chaotic mini-game series is making a really welcome return, this time featuring two-player co-op. The new vignette challenges range from avoiding bird plops to tweaking someone’s nipple hair. Classic Wario.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing The Winners Of Our “May The 4th” Cosplay and Droid Contest]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/23/announcing-the-winners-of-our-may-the-4th-cosplay-and-droid-contest/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/23/announcing-the-winners-of-our-may-the-4th-cosplay-and-droid-contest/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T14:46:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When we announced our Star Wars themed contest, along with NVIDIA, we knew we were going to be in for a difficult time deciding on a winner. There are so many great projects out there with incredible documentation and stunning results! We were not let down by the entries. If you haven’t checked them out […]
The post Announcing The Winners Of Our “May The 4th” Cosplay and Droid Contest appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweat review – the loneliness of the social media influencer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/23/sweat-review-the-loneliness-of-the-social-media-influencer-magdalena-kolesnik</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/23/sweat-review-the-loneliness-of-the-social-media-influencer-magdalena-kolesnik"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Magnus von Horn’s contrived Polish drama about a fitness guru promises more in shock and character than it delivers
In theory, it should be possible to create a drama about a social media influencer and motivational fitness celebrity that isn’t all about the hidden loneliness and shame of her shallow existence. It should be possible to show such a person being a huge hit in public and perfectly content in private. But this movie from Poland-based Swedish director Magnus von Horn pretty much goes for route one, and despite some interesting touches, it promises much more in terms of shock and character insight than it ever really delivers, with some contrived and unconvincing plot transitions.
Sylwia (Magdalena Koleśnik) has 600,000 followers for the Instagram account on which she obsessively posts, detailing every aspect of her day as a successful single woman, running colossally popular fitness events with her beefcake male assistant Klaudiusz (Julian Świeżewski). He clearly has a major thing for her, though at one crucial moment he shows a very implausible kind of restraint. She is living in a sleek apartment with her adorable dog, Jackson; there’s a new fitness DVD out and everything seems to be going well.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 15 greatest video games of the 1990s – ranked!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/23/the-15-greatest-video-games-of-the-1990s-ranked</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/23/the-15-greatest-video-games-of-the-1990s-ranked"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T10:45:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was the decade Sonic the Hedgehog, the original PlayStation, the Nintendo 64 and so much more entered the world – here are the 15 best games of this golden age of gaming
Of all LucasArts’ memorable, quip-fuelled point and click adventures – from dark afterlife comedy Grim Fandango to the surrealist Day of the Tentacle – it’s Monkey Island 2 that gets the most love nowadays, and justifiably so. The puzzles were just on the right side of deliberately obscure, the characters were strange and colourful, and the music unforgettable. And that ending still sparks discussion, 30 years on.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald and Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NFTs and me: meet the people trying to sell their memes for millions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/23/nfts-and-me-meet-the-people-trying-to-sell-their-memes-for-millions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/23/nfts-and-me-meet-the-people-trying-to-sell-their-memes-for-millions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once, people who owned viral photos made little money from them. Now, the ‘original’ can potentially sell for an enormous sum. But are buyers savvy investors – or unwitting dupes?
The photographer Jeff McCurry’s favourite Harambe memes are the ones where the dead gorilla is in heaven, Photoshopped alongside Diana, Princess of Wales, Tupac and Muhammad Ali. “It’s like: wow,” says McCurry. “What greater spot can you be placed in? Harambe’s at the top of the hill, waiting to meet you there.”
McCurry took the photograph of the 17-year-old western lowland gorilla that went on to become a meme. In it, Harambe kneels, projecting a fearsome aura of strength, nobility and calm. A former volunteer photographer at Cincinnati zoo, McCurry was there on 28 May 2016, the fateful day a three-year-old boy climbed into the gorilla’s enclosure, forcing zookeepers to shoot Harambe dead. “It didn’t seem real at first,” says McCurry, who was a regular visitor to the zoo. “When any of your friends die, it’s hard to process. I was in shock.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sirin Kale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[17 Top Container Garden Flowers For Stunning Summer Pots]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34374</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/container-flowers/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T18:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Container gardening flowers are a must for outdoor summer planters. Whether you’re looking to fill hanging baskets, window boxes, small, or a large pots, you’ll find tons of options on this list of the best flowers for container gardening. One of the most fun things to do in the spring is picking out flowers forContinue Reading
The post 17 Top Container Garden Flowers For Stunning Summer Pots appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Source Hardware Certifications for May 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/21/open-source-hardware-certifications-for-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/21/open-source-hardware-certifications-for-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In May 2021 the Open Source Hardware Association (OSHWA) certified a wide variety of hardware as open source.  we will have a certified variety collection of Open Source Hardwares, Let’s take a look! (And remember, certification is a free and easy way to show that your hardware complies with the open source hardware definition.) First, […]
The post Open Source Hardware Certifications for May 2021 appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cyberpunk 2077 finally launched on PlayStation 4]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/21/cyberpunk-2077-finally-launched-on-playstation-4</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jun/21/cyberpunk-2077-finally-launched-on-playstation-4"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T12:33:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The troubled sci-fi adventure was taken off the PlayStation store in December 2020 due to serious technical issues – now it’s back, but its use is “not recommended” and PS5 owners still have to wait
The much-hyped sci-fi adventure Cyberpunk 2077 has finally been launched on the PlayStation store, more than six months after the game’s initial release.
 Related: Cyberpunk 2077: how 2020's biggest video game launch turned into a shambles 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pixel Buds A-Series review: Google’s cheaper but good earbuds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AirPods rivals have top sound, battery and translation features but cost significantly less
Google’s latest AirPods competitors, the Pixel Buds A-Series, get a big price cut and a slightly more comfortable design.
The new Bluetooth earbuds take a cue from Google’s cheaper but great A-Series phones, cutting a few features to cost £100 (US$99) – a full £80 cheaper than their predecessors.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Michael Albert]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/18/maker-spotlight-michael-albert/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/18/maker-spotlight-michael-albert/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First and last name Michael Albert Where are you located?  White Plains, New York What is your day job?  Pop Artist/Owner of Sir Real brand of Natural Foods Do you attend a makerspace/fablab/hackerspace?  Not usually, but I’m looking forward to the Mead Library’s Maker Faire Sheboygan this weekend. Website | Pinterest | Art site What […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Michael Albert appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[17 Best Ground Cover Plants That Grow Well In The Shade]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34012</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/shade-ground-covers/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T17:36:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shade ground covers make an excellent addition to low light areas. Whether you’re looking for something that can take light foot traffic, or simply want to cover the soil in your shade garden, you’ll find lots of options in this list. Ground cover plants are a simple way to add beauty to your shade garden.Continue Reading
The post 17 Best Ground Cover Plants That Grow Well In The Shade appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where to Get Started in Digital Sculpting for 3D Printing]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/where-to-get-started-in-digital-sculpting-for-3d-printing/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/where-to-get-started-in-digital-sculpting-for-3d-printing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T15:44:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital sculpting isn’t as hard as it looks. At least, getting started isn’t that hard. You’ll still have to put in some serious time to get GOOD, but don’t let that scare you off. You may be surprised by how easily you can get something to be proud of, even as an absolute beginner. There […]
The post Where to Get Started in Digital Sculpting for 3D Printing appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Ben Davidson]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/maker-spotlight-ben-davidson/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/maker-spotlight-ben-davidson/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T14:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Name  Ben Davidson Where are you located?  Plymouth, WI What is your day job?  Mechanical engineer www.Grabot.Tech What kinds of stuff do you make?  I make two armed robots, that can be simply controlled with RC.  How did you get started making stuff? As a kid I was always playing with Legos. I have improved […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Ben Davidson appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How remote work opened the floodgates to ransomware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/17/ransomware-working-from-home-russia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/17/ransomware-working-from-home-russia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With workers outside the ‘castle walls’ of their companies, criminals have it easier – and cryptocurrency hasn’t helped
Ransomware has roared into the headlines in recent weeks after criminal hacking networks, tentatively linked to Russia, launched attacks on the major US meat packing plant JBS and the nation’s largest fuel pipeline. 
Joe Biden and his administration are scrambling to address the growing threat, pressing Vladimir Putin in a highly anticipated meeting on Wednesday to take action against the rise of ransomware attacks. Biden said he gave Putin a list of 16 areas – mostly in critical infrastructure - that are “off limits” for cyber-attacks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eat Just is racing to put ‘no-kill meat’ on your plate. Is it too good to be true?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/16/eat-just-no-kill-meat-chicken-josh-tetrick</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/food/2021/jun/16/eat-just-no-kill-meat-chicken-josh-tetrick"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T10:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The California startup leads a global push toward lab-grown meat. But experts question its bold claims
In December of last year, a handful of diners sat down to a futuristic meal at 1880, a members-only restaurant in Singapore. The star ingredient was “no-kill” chicken – raised not on a farm but in a laboratory bioreactor. Attendees snacked on lab-grown nuggets paired with crispy maple waffles, bao buns, and black bean puree.
For the California entrepreneur Josh Tetrick, it was a breakthrough. His company, Eat Just, had become the first in the world to sell the product after receiving approval from Singapore authorities. Headlines hailed a landmark step in the quest to end animal agriculture, upend the meat industry and redefine our diets.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Erin McCormick in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Microsoft Surface Laptop 4 review: Windows 10 as it is meant to be]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-review-windows-10-battery-keyboard-face-recognition</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/16/microsoft-surface-laptop-4-review-windows-10-battery-keyboard-face-recognition"/>
        <updated>2021-06-16T06:00:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Premium PC with new choice of faster chips, eight-hour battery, great keyboard and face recognition 
Microsoft’s sleek and stylish Surface Laptop is back for its fourth generation with faster performance and a greater variety of chips.
The Surface Laptop 4 is available with either a 13.5in or a 15in screen and starts at £999 in the UK, $999 in the US or $1,599 in Australia sitting above the Surface Laptop Go as Microsoft’s mainstream premium notebook, competing with the similarly priced Dell XPS 13 and Apple MacBook Air, among others.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Age of the cyber-attack: US struggles to curb rise of digital destabilization]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/age-of-the-cyber-attack-us-digital-destabilization</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/age-of-the-cyber-attack-us-digital-destabilization"/>
        <updated>2021-06-14T06:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ransomware attack that caused long lines for fuel on the east coast was just part of a dramatic change in the scale and nature of foreign-based threats
It’s been 40 years since Lisa Donnan has queued for gas. But last month the cybersecurity expert found herself joining the long lines of cars across the east coast of the US looking for fuel after the latest in a series of cyber-attacks had shut down the pipeline that provides fuel to 45% of the region.
“The last time I did that was in the Iran crisis,” she said. “My dad had to wait with me.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe in New York and Julian Borger in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ransomware is biggest online threat to people in UK, spy agency chief to warn]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/ransomware-is-biggest-online-threat-to-people-in-uk-spy-agency-chief-to-warn</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/14/ransomware-is-biggest-online-threat-to-people-in-uk-spy-agency-chief-to-warn"/>
        <updated>2021-06-13T23:01:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[GCHQ cybersecurity boss sounds alarm over extortion by hackers who are mostly based in former Soviet states
Ransomware represents the biggest threat to online security for most people and businesses in the UK, the head of GCHQ’s cybersecurity arm is to warn.
Lindy Cameron, chief executive of the National Cyber Security Centre, will say in a speech that the phenomenon, where hackers encrypt data and demand payment for it to be restored, is escalating and becoming increasingly professionalised.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh Defence and security editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Straight story? The YouTuber taking a direct route to success]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/straight-story-the-youtuber-taking-a-direct-route-to-success</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/straight-story-the-youtuber-taking-a-direct-route-to-success"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T17:02:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Davies has 925,000 subscribers who watch his attempts to cross countries without making a turn

When Tom Davies and his stepbrother, Greg, were growing up on the edge of Aldridge, a town in the West Midlands, they would pick a point in the distance, a TV mast for instance, and make their way straight there, even if it meant clambering through quarries, sneaking across railway tracks and running away from angry farmers.
Now Davies has channelled this childhood taste for adventure into a YouTube series following his attempts to traverse entire countries in a direct line, based on GPS tracking.
The scrapes he finds himself in along the way, from almost drowning in swollen rivers and slashing his hand on barbed wire in Wales to a run-in with the police in Scotland, combined with his laid-back humour (he describes Norway as “Wales on steroids”), have garnered him a huge fanbase, with 925,000 subscribers to his channel.
Videos documenting his most recent “straight line mission” across Scotland are currently racking up hundreds of thousands of views, with the next episode set to go live on Sunday – and each one could be his last as obstacles threaten to cut short his journey..
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revealed: rightwing firm posed as leftist group on Facebook to divide Democrats]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/facebook-ads-turning-point-usa-rally-forge</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/11/facebook-ads-turning-point-usa-rally-forge"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T10:00:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FEC investigation failed to uncover link to Rally Forge, a firm with close ties to Turning Point USA
A digital marketing firm closely linked to the pro-Trump youth group Turning Point USA was responsible for a series of deceptive Facebook ads promoting Green party candidates during the 2018 US midterm elections, the Guardian can reveal.
In an apparent attempt to split the Democratic vote in a number of close races, the ads purported to come from an organization called America Progress Now (APN) and used socialist memes and rhetoric to urge leftwing voters to support Green party candidates.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Carrie Wong in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Startup Wife by Tahmima Anam review – a deft take on tech times]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/11/the-startup-wife-by-tahmima-anam-review-a-deft-take-on-tech-times</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jun/11/the-startup-wife-by-tahmima-anam-review-a-deft-take-on-tech-times"/>
        <updated>2021-06-11T08:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A witty investigation into the misogyny and bro culture of the world of startups and social media apps
From John Carreyrou’s award-winning Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup to Reeves Wiedeman’s WeWork shakedown Billion Dollar Loser, the real-life stories coming out of startup land are so far-fetched that you could be forgiven for thinking there’s no ground left for invention.
So what role can fiction play in this world with no boundaries – between home and work, love and business, purpose and profit? Tahmima Anam’s fourth novel attempts to answer this by taking inspiration from her experience as executive director of ROLI, a music technology startup founded by her husband.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Baker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Act giving AFP powers to monitor An0m devices did not become law until after FBI operation began]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/11/act-giving-afp-powers-to-monitor-an0m-devices-did-not-become-law-until-after-fbi-operation-began</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/11/act-giving-afp-powers-to-monitor-an0m-devices-did-not-become-law-until-after-fbi-operation-began"/>
        <updated>2021-06-10T17:30:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police say they used ‘appropriate legislative powers’ during Operation Ironside but a lawyer representing people charged says legal concerns remain
The Australian federal police have clarified the legal basis for a wide-ranging operation that ensnared hundreds of people using compromised encrypted devices developed by an FBI informant.
The An0m devices were released in October 2018 by a convicted narcotics importer who was working for the FBI.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nino Bucci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[15 Herbs To Grow In Your Shade Garden]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34011</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/shade-herbs/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T19:43:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Herbs that grow in shade are excellent for those of us with sun-challenged gardens. The good news is that there are lots of options to choose from. In fact, many of the herbs in this list actually prefer the shade! If your yard doesn’t get a lot of sunshine, you might think that you can’tContinue Reading
The post 15 Herbs To Grow In Your Shade Garden appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Internet outage illustrates lack of resilience at heart of critical services]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/08/internet-outage-illustrates-lack-of-resilience-at-heart-of-critical-services</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/08/internet-outage-illustrates-lack-of-resilience-at-heart-of-critical-services"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T13:40:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is not clear if UK government had alternative that would have allowed services to be back online promptly
Tuesday morning’s 45-minute internet outage, which knocked out the Gov.uk domain as well as a string of publishers and other websites, cannot easily be dismissed as an isolated event. It demonstrates a lack of resilience at the heart of critical government services.
Anybody wanting to book a Covid test in the late morning on Gov.uk would have struggled. There is an alternative method, by phone, but who knows the number to call: 119? Government services that once delivered by form and post, then call centres, now only really exist through online connections.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hundreds arrested in global crime sting after underworld app is hacked]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/08/anom-encrypted-app-fbi-afp-australia-federal-police-sting-operation-ironside-an0m</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2021/jun/08/anom-encrypted-app-fbi-afp-australia-federal-police-sting-operation-ironside-an0m"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T10:03:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[European and Australian police join forces with FBI to seize weapons, drugs and $148m in cash
The FBI set up its own encrypted platform used by hundreds of criminals around the world, in an “unprecedented” sting operation that led to more than 800 arrests in 18 countries, law enforcement officers have said.
The operation by the FBI and Australian and European police, ensnared suspects in Australia, Asia, Europe, South America and the Middle East involved in the narcotics trade.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Harding and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How the FBI and Australian police gained a front seat view of underworld workings in 90 countries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/08/how-the-fbi-and-australian-police-gained-a-front-seat-view-of-underworld-workings-in-90-countries</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jun/08/how-the-fbi-and-australian-police-gained-a-front-seat-view-of-underworld-workings-in-90-countries"/>
        <updated>2021-06-08T09:38:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police in Australia and the US struck a blow to organised crime, resulting in hundreds of arrests. Now, an FBI affidavit reveals how authorities were able to pull it off 
It was mid-2018 when a convicted narcotics importer met with FBI agents from San Diego and made them a tantalising offer: in exchange for a possible reduction in the importer’s sentence on other charges, would the bureau like a backdoor into the encrypted communications of a vast network of international organised crime groups?
The importer had invested a “substantial amount” of money in developing an encrypted device which could be used by criminals around the world to avoid the detection of police.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Nino Bucci</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>