<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-07-27T00:35:08.855Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-07-27T00:35:08.855Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building An Electronic Tester For Measuring Arrow Stiffness]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=487713</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/26/building-an-electronic-tester-for-measuring-arrow-stiffness/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T23:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When shooting archery, if you want to be accurate, you need arrows of uniform specification and quality. One important part of this is making sure each arrow has a spine …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lewin Day</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tesla second-quarter profits top $1bn even as it struggles to handle demand]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/26/tesla-profits-second-quarter-demand-chip-shortage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/26/tesla-profits-second-quarter-demand-chip-shortage"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T21:56:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A global shortfall of semiconductors has affected the Tesla supply chain as well as car manufacturers across the world
Tesla made a profit of more than $1bn in the last three months even as it struggled to keep up with demand for electric cars in the face of a global chip shortage.
The company announced Monday that it has made a profit of $1.14bn in its second quarter, 10 times what it made a year ago and its eighth quarter of back-to-back profits.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Back Up and Restore Your PlayStation 5 Data]]></title>
        <id>1847364876</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-backup-and-restore-your-playstation-5-data-1847364876"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T21:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Backing up your PC, smartphone, and other devices ensures you can recover your data in the event of a crash, sudden power outage, or total hardware failure—but not many people considering doing the same for their game consoles. Luckily, the PlayStation 5 makes it easy to back up your files to an external USB device,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Hesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned About Weightlifting From Two Olympic Competitors]]></title>
        <id>1847294339</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/what-i-learned-about-weightlifting-from-two-olympic-com-1847294339"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Explosively lifting a giant barbell over your head  takes strength, technique, and a certain fearlessness. I’ve been training this sport—Olympic style weightlifting—for about two years now, and it seems like I find something new to learn about it every day. Recently, I had a chance to ask two members of the US Olympic…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[WiFiWart Boots Linux, Moves To Next Design Phase]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=488213</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/26/wifiwart-boots-linux-moves-to-next-design-phase/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T20:00:27.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the last few months we’ve been keeping an eye on WiFiWart, an ambitious project to develop a Linux single-board computer (SBC) small enough to fit inside a USB wall …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Nardi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Are Bone Conduction Headphones Worth the Hype?]]></title>
        <id>1847360844</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/are-bone-conduction-headphones-worth-the-hype-1847360844"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Would you try a pair of headphones that rests on your cheekbones and sends audio to your ears through your bones? This is possible through a technology called “bone conduction,” and it’s most used in consumer headphones. These products aren’t too expensive and may be a good alternative for people who don’t enjoy using…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranay Parab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Houseplants Actually Filter Your Air?]]></title>
        <id>1847363465</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/do-houseplants-actually-filter-your-air-1847363465"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plants are pretty wonderful, providing us with food, shade, and breathable air, but they aren’t magical. Yes, rainforests are vital for our ecosystem because they filter carbon out of the air and create oxygen—but any notion that houseplants can be used to filter toxins out of the air in our homes is, as this report…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Stop Getting Ripped Off by Hotel Fees]]></title>
        <id>1847363798</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-stop-getting-ripped-off-by-hotel-fees-1847363798"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hotels are already expensive, so the last thing you need are sneaky fees adding unexpected costs to your travel budget. Hotel fees aren’t always something you can avoid—especially at popular resort destinations—but you shouldn’t be surprised by them, either. With that in mind, here’s a look at some commonly tacked-on…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Don't Need Makeup-Remover to Remove Your Makeup]]></title>
        <id>1847363458</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/you-dont-need-makeup-remover-to-remove-your-makeup-1847363458"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The worst part of wearing makeup is taking it off at the end of the day. Single-use makeup wipes and cotton pads are as expensive as they are wasteful, but most people see them as a necessary evil. Assuming your cleanser can’t remove makeup on its own, you need something that does. But here’s the thing: No matter what…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>A.A. Newton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Little Quadruped Uses Many Servos]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=487711</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/26/little-quadruped-uses-many-servos/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T18:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Walking robots were once the purview of major corporations spending huge dollars on research programs. Now, they’re something you can experiment with at home. [Technovation] has been doing just that …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lewin Day</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Pooped Your Pants During A Run, Now What?]]></title>
        <id>1847362571</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/you-shit-your-pants-during-a-run-now-what-1847362571"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve been a runner for a while, there’s a good chance that, at one point or another, you’ve had to take an emergency pit stop to poop while on a long run. If you were lucky, there was a bathroom nearby. If you weren’t... well, let’s never speak about that again.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Fairbank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Build a Better Salad]]></title>
        <id>1847362554</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-build-a-better-salad-1847362554"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Leaves are a big, if not the main, component of a salad, but the other stuff is what makes it fun. But you know what’s not fun? Adding all of your tasty toppings, crispy bits, and proteins, only to have them fall to the bottom of the bowl when you toss the salad in an attempt to distribute them. This is not a…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Set Unique Text Sizes for Different Apps in iOS 15]]></title>
        <id>1847355175</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-set-unique-text-sizes-for-different-apps-in-ios-1847355175"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The iPhone has a great accessibility feature that’s been adopted by many popular apps—Dynamic Type, which lets you increase or decrease the text size for the OS and all supported apps, is a prime example. Starting in iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, you’ll be able to specify the text size for each app (and even the home screen)…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Linux Fu: Superpowers for Mere Mortals]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=486464</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/26/linux-fu-superpowers-for-mere-mortals/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T17:00:09.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can hardly mention the sudo command without recalling the hilarious XKCD strip about making sandwiches. It does seem like sudo is the magic power to make a Linux system …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Al Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Fake Pockets Might Not Be Fake After All]]></title>
        <id>1847361906</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/your-fake-pockets-might-not-be-fake-after-all-1847361906"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I still remember the time I was in a parking lot after work, absentmindedly shoving my hand into a fake blazer pocket, when I realized there was a hole in the stitching. Great, I thought, there’s still no place to put my phone and now I have a hole in my blazer. I fiddled with the loose thread and realized that’s not…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Change Alexa's Voice on Amazon Echo, Finally [Updated]]]></title>
        <id>1847355030</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-change-alexas-voice-on-amazon-echo-finally-1847355030"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since its inception, Amazon Echo has featured a titular, feminine voice that became the identity that we all associate with the voice assistant. After all these years, Amazon is finally letting users switch to a new, masculine voice—and even refer to it by a new name by changing the wake word to a new option, Ziggy.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Finally Look Better on Video Calls Using an iPad Pro]]></title>
        <id>1847361024</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-finally-look-better-on-video-calls-using-an-ipad-1847361024"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Though it feels like we’ve been Zooming and FaceTiming and using Google Hangouts for an eternity, most of us have still not figured out how to look good on a video call. Luckily, a new feature on iPad Pro called Center Stage has launched, and without much effort, it can make you look just a little bit better on camera.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Kahn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm 'Listen Like You Mean It' Author Ximena Vengoechea, and This Is How I Work]]></title>
        <id>1847358610</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/im-listen-like-you-mean-it-author-ximena-vengoechea-an-1847358610"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ximena Vengoechea has done a lot of listening. Keeping her ears and mind attuned to the needs of others is something of a calling for her not only in her work as a user researcher at some of the biggest names in the technology industry, but as a person navigating the constant stimuli of modern life. Her book Listen…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Blum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Build With Acrylic Using the Tools You Have]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=488247</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/26/how-to-build-with-acrylic-using-the-tools-you-have/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T15:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In a perfect world, we’d all have laser cutters and could pop intricate designs out of acrylic sheets with just a few clicks of the mouse. But in reality, most …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Nardi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Tell If Your Pillow Is Dead]]></title>
        <id>1847351627</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-tell-if-your-pillow-is-dead-1847351627"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Getting a restful night’s sleep depends on several factors—and the pillow itself is a biggie. Pillows provide support for the alignment of your spine, and they are a necessary factor in one’s slumber comfort. The thickness and firmness of the pillow you need or prefer will very from person to person, but any pillow…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My 15-Year Quest to Make the Ultimate DIY Coffee Roaster]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/26/my-15-year-quest-to-make-the-ultimate-diy-coffee-roaster/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/26/my-15-year-quest-to-make-the-ultimate-diy-coffee-roaster/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One man's 15-year quest to build — and rebuild, and rebuild — the ultimate DIY coffee roaster
The post My 15-Year Quest to Make the Ultimate DIY Coffee Roaster appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Iced Coffee Needs Some Citrus Soda]]></title>
        <id>1847361312</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/your-iced-coffee-needs-some-citrus-soda-1847361312"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the time of summer when the heat can go from barely tolerable to unbearably hot, with no respite to be found. Although most of my regular food and drinks can be swapped out for lighter, more summer-appropriate options, my daily coffee presents a quandary. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Fairbank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[RNA Therapeutics And Fighting Diseases By Working With The Immune System]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=484064</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/26/rna-therapeutics-and-fighting-diseases-by-working-with-the-immune-system/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T14:01:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Before the SARS-CoV-2 pandemic took hold, few people were aware of the existence of mRNA vaccines. Yet after months of vaccinations from Moderna and BioNTech and clear indications of robust …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Posch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Deal With a Work Bully]]></title>
        <id>1847353554</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-deal-with-a-work-bully-1847353554"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do you have a work bully? Don’t be embarrassed if you do. Unnecessarily mean and aggressive peers are typically associated with high school, but don’t fool yourself: There are cruel adults out there, too, and you could easily end up working with one.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Ellefson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Return to school spoiled by Cape Town taxi war]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/return-school-spoiled-cape-town-taxi-war/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/return-school-spoiled-cape-town-taxi-war/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T13:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Western Cape MEC suspends Bellville – Paarl taxi route for two months]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ensure You'll Be Approved for a Credit Limit Increase Before You Apply]]></title>
        <id>1847352723</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/ensure-youll-be-approved-for-a-credit-limit-increase-be-1847352723"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s a bit of a Catch 22 when it comes to applying for a credit card limit increase: A higher limit can boost your credit score, but asking for an increase can also hurt your credit score, temporarily. And if the lender rejects your request? You just dinged your credit score for no reason—which can be literally the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Put Mayo on Both Pieces of Bread, You Weirdos]]></title>
        <id>1847351385</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/put-mayo-on-both-pieces-of-bread-you-weirdos-1847351385"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most people are shy about mayonnaise, but not me. I’m loud, if not downright obnoxious about it. It’s no secret that I am very white (and sort of Southern), and my enthusiasm for the pale complected, emulsified condiment comes to me quite naturally. (We match!) I have many mayo hacks, but the first, original mayo hack…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winters are the worst nightmare for us, says homeless man in Springs]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/winters-are-worst-nightmare-us-says-homeless-man-springs/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/winters-are-worst-nightmare-us-says-homeless-man-springs/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T12:06:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last week temperatures dropped to minus 7ºC]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Some Close Air Support With A Nerf Drone]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=488292</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/26/get-some-close-air-support-with-a-nerf-drone/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T11:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Working from home has the major advantage of spending more time with loved ones, but it all that time can sometimes lead to friction. [Cory] found that Nerf battles with …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Danie Conradie</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19: Unions should push harder for teachers to get vaccinated]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/covid-19-unions-should-ensure-teachers-must-get-vaccinated-against/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/covid-19-unions-should-ensure-teachers-must-get-vaccinated-against/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T10:33:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s almost never a reasonable choice to not get vaccinated]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lottery COO back at work after 17-month “leave of absence”]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/lotteries-commission-coo-back-at-work-after-17-month-leave-of-absence/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/lotteries-commission-coo-back-at-work-after-17-month-leave-of-absence/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T09:55:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Audit firm SkX has so far been paid R9.65 million to investigate alleged Lottery corruption]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng informal traders feel the aftermath of July unrest]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-informal-traders-feel-aftermath-july-unrest/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-informal-traders-feel-aftermath-july-unrest/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-26T09:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“We are not making money and our fridges at home are empty. We can’t carry on like this,” says Kwa Mai Mai Market food seller]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Jump-Start an Electric Car That has a Dead Battery]]></title>
        <id>1847355623</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-jump-start-an-electric-car-that-has-a-dead-batte-1847355623"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re new to electric vehicles—or are starting to research options for an upcoming purchase—you may not know that in addition to the high-voltage battery pack that supplies power to the motor, they also use the same 12-volt batteries that gas-powered vehicles do. And, yes, these 12-volt batteries can lose their…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use This Free App to Create a Shareable Travel Journal With Minimal Effort]]></title>
        <id>1847355580</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/use-this-free-app-to-create-a-shareable-travel-journal-1847355580"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you’re finally on your long-awaited (and likely previously canceled) vacation, you may face a conundrum. On the one hand, you want to document your trip—both for yourself, and so your friends and family can see and enjoy your travels. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emmanuel Macron ‘pushes for Israeli inquiry’ into NSO spyware concerns]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/25/emmanuel-macron-pushes-for-israeli-inquiry-into-nso-spyware-concerns</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/25/emmanuel-macron-pushes-for-israeli-inquiry-into-nso-spyware-concerns"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T14:26:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[French president reportedly spoke to Naftali Bennett to ensure ‘proper investigation’ after Pegasus project
Emmanuel Macron has reportedly spoken to the Israeli prime minister, Naftali Bennett, to ensure that the Israeli government is “properly investigating” allegations that the French president could have been targeted with Israeli-made spyware by Morocco’s security services.
In a phone call, Macron expressed concern that his phone and those of most of his cabinet could have been infected with Pegasus, hacking software developed by the Israeli surveillance firm NSO Group, which enables operators of the tool to extract messages, photos and emails, record calls and secretly activate microphones from infected devices.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Bethan McKernan Middle East correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Tell a Friend Their Partner Sucks]]></title>
        <id>1847353703</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-tell-a-friend-their-partner-sucks-1847353703"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is your best friend dating an asshole? At some point, your best friend is gonna date an asshole. These are the facts, unless you’re extremely lucky, and these facts suck. It hurts to see someone you care about dating someone who is terrible, especially if they don’t see that yet.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Ellefson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cryptocurrencies could lead to ‘limitless’ losses for UK government]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/25/cryptocurrencies-could-lead-to-limitless-losses-for-uk-government</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/25/cryptocurrencies-could-lead-to-limitless-losses-for-uk-government"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T13:32:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Experts warn of danger of untraceable funds if companies accepting payments in cryptos go bust
The government could face “limitless” losses as a result of businesses that accept payments in untaxed and untraceable cryptocurrencies going bust, an insolvency expert has warned.
A growing number of companies, including the ethical cosmetics firm Lush and office-sharing firm WeWork, have begun taking payments for goods and services in cryptocurrencies such as bitcoin, alongside debit payments, credit or cash.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kalyeena Makortoff Banking correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Survive a Multigenerational Family Vacation]]></title>
        <id>1847355632</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-survive-a-multigenerational-family-vacation-1847355632"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After spending so much time apart thanks to COVID travel restrictions, this summer’s family reunions have taken on new meaning. In some cases, families have decided to take these reunions on the road, and make it a multigenerational family vacation. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jeanette Winterson: ‘The male push is to discard the planet: all the boys are going off into space’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/25/jeanette-winterson-the-male-push-is-to-discard-the-planet-all-the-boys-are-going-off-into-space</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/25/jeanette-winterson-the-male-push-is-to-discard-the-planet-all-the-boys-are-going-off-into-space"/>
        <updated>2021-07-25T10:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The writer’s new essay collection covers 200 years of women and science, from Mary Shelley to AI. She discusses burning books and the ensuing Twitter storm, the end of her marriage, and why a move into politics could be next
There’s a disconcerting silence outside Jeanette Winterson’s London pied-a-terre. It’s the morning after the night before, when she travelled across London after dinner with her publisher to scenes of football fans setting the city alight with their cup final fervour. “It was uproar,” she says, “We saw cars on fire.” Her flat is in the East End district of Spitalfields in a Georgian house, which she bought 25 years ago, complete with a little shop that she ran for years as an organic grocer and tea room until the rates got too high, and she let it out to an upmarket chocolatier.
It’s as if a scene from Dickens’s The Old Curiosity Shop has been dropped into a satire about prosperity Britain: the quaint old shopfront is still intact, while outside it a lifesize sculpture of a rowing boat full of people sits surreally in the middle of the street, and a little further along, a herd of large bronze elephants frolics. These public artworks only arrived a few weeks ago, Winterson explains, as part of a grand plan to pedestrianise the area, and make it more buzzy, just at the moment that the sort of well-heeled office workers who bought upmarket chocolates are abandoning it owing to the Covid pandemic.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Armitstead</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[2021 iPhone photography awards – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/gallery/2021/jul/25/2021-iphone-photography-awards-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/gallery/2021/jul/25/2021-iphone-photography-awards-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-07-24T20:00:32.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The 14th annual iPhone photography awards offer glimpses of beauty, hope and the endurance of the human spirit. Out of thousands of submissions, photojournalist Istvan Kerekes of Hungary was named the grand prize winner for his image Transylvanian Shepherds. In it, two rugged shepherds traverse an equally rugged industrial landscape, bearing a pair of lambs in their arms.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Technology | The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Paid $5,000 to Play Video Games, Stream TV Shows, or Shop Online]]></title>
        <id>1847354091</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/get-paid-5-000-to-play-video-games-stream-tv-shows-o-1847354091"/>
        <updated>2021-07-24T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Everyone has taken a few minutes (or hours) of time during their workday to get some personal stuff done. But what if you had an entire week to spend doing whatever you want online—and got paid to do it? One company is hiring someone to do just that. Here’s what to know about the position, and how to apply.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Exactly What You Want at a Botox Appointment]]></title>
        <id>1847353579</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-get-exactly-what-you-want-at-a-botox-appointment-1847353579"/>
        <updated>2021-07-24T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you see someone with facial injectables you don’t like, there’s something you need to remember (besides the fact that your opinion on someone else’s aesthetic enhancements isn’t relevant): For everyone with exaggerated filler or too-frozen Botox you spot in the wild, there are dozens more people walking around…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Ellefson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Use Dish Soap and/or a Garden Hose to Locate Leaks in an Air Mattress]]></title>
        <id>1847354067</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/use-dish-soap-and-or-a-garden-hose-to-locate-leaks-in-a-1847354067"/>
        <updated>2021-07-24T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of sleeping on low-quality air mattresses, you finally decided to invest in a good one. Maybe it even has special features—like a built-in air pump, or being thicker. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sucks to be him! How Henry the vacuum cleaner became an accidental design icon]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/24/how-henry-vacuum-cleaner-became-accidental-design-icon</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/24/how-henry-vacuum-cleaner-became-accidental-design-icon"/>
        <updated>2021-07-24T09:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Henry is a fixture in millions of homes – including 10 Downing Street – despite almost no advertising. Meet the man behind a curiously British success story
In March this year, photos of the government’s glitzy new briefing room, where Boris Johnson’s new media chief was set to host daily press conferences, leaked to the media. The centrepiece of a “presidential” approach to communications, it was already controversial for its cost to taxpayers of £2.6m. With its gaudy blue backdrop, giant union flags and imposing podium, it looked like the stage for a US political or legal TV show: The West Wing with a touch of Judge Judy.
What the briefing room needed was something to suck the pomposity out of it. What it needed, it turned out, was a cameo appearance from a 620-watt anthropomorphic vacuum cleaner. The stocky red and black appliance was barely visible in the wings, stage left, yet instantly recognisable. Turned away from the podium, his chrome wand propped casually against a varnished dado rail, the Henry vacuum cleaner looked almost as if he were rolling his eyes.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Simon Usborne</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Smart security: how to keep your home safe while you’re away]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jul/24/smart-security-how-to-keep-your-home-safe-while-youre-away</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/money/2021/jul/24/smart-security-how-to-keep-your-home-safe-while-youre-away"/>
        <updated>2021-07-24T08:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tech options to deter would-be intruders, and let you monitor your house from anywhere
With the prospect of trips out and holidays finally on the cards, over the next few weeks many of us will be leaving our houses unattended for the first time in months. So now is the time to think about making your home a bit more secure.
In addition to the basics, there is a range of DIY tech that may help to deter would-be intruders and allow you to keep an eye on your home from almost anywhere in the world.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Demonstrations and inquiries: the global impact of the Pegasus project]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jul/23/demonstrations-and-inquiries-the-global-impact-of-the-pegasus-project</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jul/23/demonstrations-and-inquiries-the-global-impact-of-the-pegasus-project"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T13:09:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Worldwide concern over the use of invasive spyware sold to autocratic regimes
The Pegasus project investigation has reverberated across the world; claims about the use of invasive spyware, and the governments that use the technology, have provoked demonstrations, political outrage and calls for industry regulation.
Here, Guardian reporters pull together the impact of the investigation, which has put a spotlight on the government customers of the Israeli company NSO Group.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reporting team</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dodgy Lottery: Judge dismisses attempt to block SIU investigating lottery millions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/dodgy-lottery-siu-rebuffs-interdict-attempt-ramulifho-associate/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/dodgy-lottery-siu-rebuffs-interdict-attempt-ramulifho-associate/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T12:28:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng High Court has dismissed Ramulifho associate Liesl Moses’s interdict to keep the SIU from investigating her]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cape Town taxi violence: City businesses put staff up in hotels]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/cape-town-businesses-opt-plan-bnb-amidst-taxi-violence/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/cape-town-businesses-opt-plan-bnb-amidst-taxi-violence/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T11:12:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the safety of their staff and to keep their doors open, some businesses are accommodating employees so that they do not have to commute]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How NSO became the company whose software can spy on the world]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jul/23/how-nso-became-the-company-whose-software-can-spy-on-the-world</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jul/23/how-nso-became-the-company-whose-software-can-spy-on-the-world"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T11:00:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Pegasus project has raised new concerns about the Israeli firm, which is a world leader in the niche surveillance market
In 2019, when NSO Group was facing intense scrutiny, new investors in the Israeli surveillance company were on a PR offensive to reassure human rights groups.
In an exchange of public letters in 2019, they told Amnesty International and other activists that they would do “whatever is necessary” to ensure NSO’s weapons-grade software would only be used to fight crime and terrorism.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Stephanie Kirchgaessner</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Atlantis pharmacist feeds hundreds of people weekly]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/atlantis-pharmacists-feeds-hundreds-people-weekly/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/atlantis-pharmacists-feeds-hundreds-people-weekly/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T10:54:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“This is desperation. People are hungry out here. Situations like these are heartbreaking,” says Thahier Alli]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Small traders suffering as a result of Cape Town taxi violence]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/small-traders-hard-hit-cape-town-taxi-violence/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/small-traders-hard-hit-cape-town-taxi-violence/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T10:44:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“When the taxi drivers shoot at each other, we lie on the ground next to our stock”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“Serving from the pot, you pray that the food is enough”]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/serving-from-the-pot-you-pray-that-the-food-is-enough/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/serving-from-the-pot-you-pray-that-the-food-is-enough/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Community soup kitchens say the number of people coming for food has increased in recent months]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech firm hit by giant ransomware hack gets key to unlock victims’ data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/ransomware-attack-kaseya-key-hacking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/ransomware-attack-kaseya-key-hacking"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T23:47:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kaseya’s universal key can free the files of hundreds of organizations, ending the worst of the attack’s fallout
The software company at the center of a huge ransomware attack this month has obtained a universal key to unlock files of the hundreds of businesses and public organizations crippled by the hack.
Nineteen days after the initial attack over the Fourth of July weekend, the Florida-based IT management provider, Kaseya, has received the universal key that can unlock the scrambled data of all the attack’s victims, bringing the worst of the fallout to a close.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Online banking and gaming services hit by internet outage]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/online-banking-and-gaming-services-hit-by-internet-outage</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/online-banking-and-gaming-services-hit-by-internet-outage"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T18:44:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[HSBC, PlayStation and others affected on Thursday in issue possibly related to Akamai Edge DNS 
The websites of HSBC, ITV and Waitrose were among those hit by a widespread outage that briefly caused disruption on Thursday afternoon.
Major online banking services – including Barclays, TSB, the Bank of Scotland, Tesco Bank and Sainsbury’s Bank – were either entirely or partially inaccessible for a short period.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>PA Media</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taxi violence: “It is like organised crime trying to take over the economy of the Western Cape”]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/taxi-violence-it-is-like-organised-crime-trying-to-take-over-the-economy-of-the-western-cape/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/taxi-violence-it-is-like-organised-crime-trying-to-take-over-the-economy-of-the-western-cape/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T15:21:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Negotiations between rival taxi bodies deadlocked]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Star Wars Cantina Bar Creature Project: ‘Hammerhead’]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/22/the-star-wars-cantina-bar-creature-project-hammerhead/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/22/the-star-wars-cantina-bar-creature-project-hammerhead/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T14:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Follow along as Robert creates an iconic sculpture from Star Wars
The post The Star Wars Cantina Bar Creature Project: ‘Hammerhead’ appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sharp increase in deaths places strain on Johannesburg cemeteries]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/sharp-increase-deaths-places-strain-johannesburg-cemeteries/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/sharp-increase-deaths-places-strain-johannesburg-cemeteries/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T12:58:46.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“These numbers are staggering,” says City Parks spokesperson]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Duped and desperate loan seekers bring class action against online scammers]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/duped-and-desperate-loan-seekers-bring-class-action-against-online-scammers/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/duped-and-desperate-loan-seekers-bring-class-action-against-online-scammers/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T10:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Wily confidence tricksters” shut down in action led by Stellenbosch law clinic]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Court fines former Eastern Cape principal R4,000 for lowering learner into pit toilet]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/court-fines-former-eastern-cape-principal-r4000-lowering-learner-pit-toilet/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/court-fines-former-eastern-cape-principal-r4000-lowering-learner-pit-toilet/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T08:09:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lubeko Mgandela pleaded guilty to a charge of child abuse in the Tsolo Magistrates Court on Wednesday]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Revealed: the people who signed up to the Magacoin Trump cryptocurrency]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/magacoin-pro-trump-cryptocurrency-attracts-over-1000-people-to-sign-up</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/magacoin-pro-trump-cryptocurrency-attracts-over-1000-people-to-sign-up"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T06:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It bills itself as the ‘digital currency for the MAGA community’ but data shows most of the magacoin is allocated to its self-styled creator
More than 1,000 people have so far signed up to the pro-Trump cryptocurrency magacoin, including conservative media personalities and Republican figures, the Guardian can reveal.
The news comes after poor security configuration in a website associated with magacoin exposed the email addresses, passwords, cryptocurrency wallet addresses and IP addresses of users who have bought in to what its promoters describe as the “digital currency for the MAGA community”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Wilson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Covid-19 vaccines: Current challenge is not supply but using the available vaccines]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/covid-19-vaccines-our-biggest-problem-not-supply-using-available-vaccines/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/covid-19-vaccines-our-biggest-problem-not-supply-using-available-vaccines/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The government’s plan requires vaccinating one million people per week, but it has only fully vaccinated 1.4 million people in nine weeks.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to photograph the July full moon on your phone or camera, and the best settings to use]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/how-to-photograph-the-full-moon-july-2021-with-phone-tips-buck-thunder-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings-night-sky-tonight</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/how-to-photograph-the-full-moon-july-2021-with-phone-tips-buck-thunder-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings-night-sky-tonight"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T00:54:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Australia picture editor Carly Earl explains the dos and don’ts of taking pictures of the July 2021 full moon, which is also known as the buck or thunder moon.
When a full moon rises, many people will pull out their mobile phones to try and get an Instagram-worthy photograph, but unfortunately the moon is really challenging to get a great photo of.
Two reasons: it is very far away and unless you have a telephoto lens (which makes the moon appear closer than it is) it will always appear as a very small glowing dot in the frame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carly Earl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uber and Lyft drivers join day-long strike over working conditions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/21/uber-lyft-drivers-strike-app-based-work-gig-economy</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/21/uber-lyft-drivers-strike-app-based-work-gig-economy"/>
        <updated>2021-07-21T23:34:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Workers for app companies call for better wages and protections for those seeking to unionize
Hundreds of Uber and Lyft drivers have joined other app-based workers across the US for a day-long strike to protest against poor working conditions and demand the right to organize.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Briton arrested over high-profile Twitter account hacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/21/briton-arrested-over-high-profile-twitter-account-hacks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/21/briton-arrested-over-high-profile-twitter-account-hacks"/>
        <updated>2021-07-21T18:21:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[22-year-old faces multiple charges in connection with attacks on accounts of politicians and celebrities
A 22-year-old British citizen has been arrested in Spain in connection with a July 2020 Twitter hack that compromised the accounts of high-profile politicians and celebrities, the US Justice Department said on Wednesday.
It named the British man as Joseph James O’Connor and said he faced multiple charges. He was also accused in a criminal complaint of computer intrusions related to takeovers of TikTok and Snapchat accounts, including one incident involving sextortion, as well as cyberstalking a 16-year-old juvenile.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Gameboy Runs on Nuclear Power]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/21/this-gameboy-runs-on-nuclear-power/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/21/this-gameboy-runs-on-nuclear-power/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My "Nuclear Powered Gameboy" uses Tritium tubes as the energy source, which produces a mere 1.5 microwatts of power (that's 1.5 millionths of a watt). 
The post This Gameboy Runs on Nuclear Power appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘A systemic failure’: vaccine misinformation remains rampant on Facebook, experts say]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/21/facebook-misinformation-vaccines</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/21/facebook-misinformation-vaccines"/>
        <updated>2021-07-21T10:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Misinformation ‘superspreader’ accounts found still active even as vaccination rates flag and cases rise in US
Facebook is under fire once again over the proliferation of vaccine misinformation on its platform, after Joe Biden said tech giants such as Facebook are “killing people” for failing to tackle the problem.
The White House has also zeroed in on the “disinformation dozen”: accounts that have been shown to be responsible for the bulk of anti-vaccine misinformation on social media platforms.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[African Milk Tree:  How To Grow & Care For A Euphorbia trigona Plant]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=35122</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/african-milk-tree-plant-care/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T18:29:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[African milk trees are beautiful and surprisingly easy to grow and care for. In this post, I’m going to tell you everything you need to know about Euphorbia trigona plant care, and give you tons of tips for keeping yours happy and healthy. Whether you’re into indoor plants, or looking for a stellar addition toContinue Reading
The post African Milk Tree:  How To Grow & Care For A Euphorbia trigona Plant appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US condemns China for ‘malicious’ cyberattacks, including Microsoft hack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/19/microsoft-exchange-hack-us-biden-administration-china</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/19/microsoft-exchange-hack-us-biden-administration-china"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T12:24:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Justice department charged four Chinese nationals with hacking as Washington accused Beijing of threatening national security
The US has led allies in a sharp condemnation of China for “malicious” cyberattacks, including a hack of Microsoft Exchange email server software that compromised tens of thousands of computers around the world earlier this year.
 Related: UK and allies accuse Chinese state-backed group of Microsoft hack 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Smith in Washington and Vincent Ni</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing Broken Machines from the Amazon Return Bin]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/19/fixing-broken-machines-from-the-amazon-return-bin/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/19/fixing-broken-machines-from-the-amazon-return-bin/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T01:00:14.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Debra Daun's superpower is fixing broken machines, such as 3D printers.  She runs the MakerLab at Joliet Junior College in Joliet, Illinois.  She has figured out that she can get used and abused machines that have been returned to Amazon.  She bids for them at auction and then repairs them or adds the odd parts to her boneyard.  She's been able to add more machines that she uses to teach students 3D printing in the makerspace.  The more broken the machine, she says, the happier she is.
The post Fixing Broken Machines from the Amazon Return Bin appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[US stocks plunge amid coronavirus variant fears – as it happened]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jul/19/microsoft-hack-latest-news-china-biden-doj-warning-infrastructure-bill</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2021/jul/19/microsoft-hack-latest-news-china-biden-doj-warning-infrastructure-bill"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T00:17:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Major US stock indexes follow European counterparts with sell-offs
US says Microsoft Exchange hack shows ‘aggressive behavior’ by China
UK and allies accuse Chinese state-backed group of Microsoft hack
Explainer: what is the Microsoft hack?

 1.01am BST 
That’s all from me today. Here’s a rundown of the day’s biggest politics stories: 
 12.49am BST 
Senate majority leader Chuck Schumer will file cloture on a placeholder bill for the bipartisan infrastructure plan tonight, setting up a vote on Wednesday. 
Schumer NOW on Senate floor updates the timing of infrastructure legislation: "Tonight in a few minutes, I will file cloture on a shell bill which will act as the legislative vehicle for the bipartisan infrastructure framework. That vote on cloture will take place on Wednesday." pic.twitter.com/FRGPFkeh8d
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Julia Carrie Wong and Vivian Ho</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK and allies accuse Chinese state-backed group of Microsoft hack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/19/uk-allies-accuse-chinese-state-backed-group-microsoft-hack</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/19/uk-allies-accuse-chinese-state-backed-group-microsoft-hack"/>
        <updated>2021-07-19T14:21:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[British foreign secretary says Beijing will be held to account if it does not stop ‘systematic cyber sabotage’
Britain has joined with the US and other allies in formally accusing Chinese state-based hacking groups of being behind the exploitation of an estimated 250,000 Microsoft Exchange servers worldwide earlier this year.
The UK foreign secretary said the cyber-attack amounted to “a reckless but familiar pattern of behaviour”, in an announcement released on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Sabbagh, Jennifer Rankin and Peter Walker</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What is the Hafnium Microsoft hack and why has the UK linked it to China?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/19/what-is-the-hafnium-microsoft-hack-and-why-has-the-uk-linked-it-to-china</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/19/what-is-the-hafnium-microsoft-hack-and-why-has-the-uk-linked-it-to-china"/>
        <updated>2021-07-19T13:13:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Britain has joined the US and other allies in formally accusing China of being behind the cyber-attack
In March, tens of thousands of organisations around the world discovered their private internal discussions had been cracked open and lain bare by a group of Chinese hackers.
Four previously undiscovered weaknesses in Microsoft’s Exchange software, known as “zero days” because of the amount of time the company had had to fix the flaws before they were exploited, lay behind the mass hack. The vulnerabilities, which affected software released from 2012 onwards, allowed the group to take permanent control of the corporate servers, siphoning emails, calendars, and anything else they desired.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[China’s Tencent agrees to buy UK video games firm Sumo for more than £900m]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/19/china-tencent-uk-video-games-developer-sumo</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/19/china-tencent-uk-video-games-developer-sumo"/>
        <updated>2021-07-19T09:26:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Move expands Chinese tech company’s presence in the global video games market
China’s Tencent has agreed to buy the British video games developer Sumo Group at a valuation of more than £900m, further expanding the tech company’s presence in the global video games market.
Sumo’s board has agreed to Tencent’s offer of 513p a share, valuing the London-listed company at £919m, it announced on Monday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jasper Jolly</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Think, fight, feel: how video game artificial intelligence is evolving]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/19/video-gaming-artificial-intelligence-ai-is-evolving</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/19/video-gaming-artificial-intelligence-ai-is-evolving"/>
        <updated>2021-07-19T08:30:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AI in games has long been geared towards improving computer-controlled opponents. Will it soon create diverse characters we can talk to instead of just shoot?
In May, as part of an otherwise unremarkable corporate strategy meeting, Sony CEO Kenichiro Yoshida made an interesting announcement. The company’s artificial intelligence research division, Sony AI, would be collaborating with PlayStation developers to create intelligent computer-controlled characters. “By leveraging reinforcement learning,” he wrote, “we are developing game AI agents that can be a player’s in-game opponent or collaboration partner.” Reinforcement learning is an area of machine learning in which an AI effectively teaches itself how to act through trial and error. In short, these characters will mimic human players. To some extent, they will think.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Classified details of army’s Challenger tank leaked via video game]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/18/classified-details-of-armys-challenger-tank-leaked-via-video-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2021/jul/18/classified-details-of-armys-challenger-tank-leaked-via-video-game"/>
        <updated>2021-07-18T09:30:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[User uploads secret files to prove how tank was ‘incorrectly’ modelled in game played worldwide
Classified details of the British Army’s main battle tank, Challenger 2, have been leaked online after a player in a tank battle video game disputed its accuracy.
The player, who claimed to have been a real life Challenger 2 tank commander and gunnery instructor, disputed the design of the tank in the popular combat video game “War Thunder”, arguing it needed changing. He claimed game designers had failed to “model it properly”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>David Connett</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Social Warming by Charles Arthur review – a coolly prosecutorial look at social media]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/17/social-warming-by-charles-arthur-review-a-coolly-prosecutorial-look-at-social-media</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/17/social-warming-by-charles-arthur-review-a-coolly-prosecutorial-look-at-social-media"/>
        <updated>2021-07-17T08:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Social media giants contribute to global conflicts and allow misinformation. How have they gained so much control, and what is that doing to our lives?
It’s good to remember that every time Mark Zuckerberg claims that he founded Facebook in order to connect people or build communities, he is somehow forgetting that he first created the site in order to enable himself and his fellow dorm-dwellers to rate Harvard’s young women on their looks. But then, Zuckerberg has never been the sharpest tool in the box. He once said that Facebook wouldn’t interfere with Holocaust-denial on its service, because it was hard to impugn people’s motives for denying the Holocaust, before a couple of years later announcing that his “thinking” on the matter had “evolved” and Holocaust denial was now frowned upon. Well, evolution does work slowly.
But as Charles Arthur’s coolly prosecutorial book shows, social-media algorithms don’t just allow people with nefarious interests to get together: they perform as active matchmakers. “Facebook was hothousing extremism by putting extremists in touch with each other,” concluded Facebook’s own internal investigations in 2016. Not only that, Facebook was “auto-generating terrorist content”: its “machine learning” systems created a “Local Business” page for “al-Qaida in the Arabian peninsula”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Poole</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cairo Celebrates 7 Years of Maker Faire Magic]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/16/cairo-celebrates-7-years-of-maker-faire-magic/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/16/cairo-celebrates-7-years-of-maker-faire-magic/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-16T18:59:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[This week Maker Faire Cairo—the biggest gathering in Egypt for makers, inventors, creatives, and technologists—is back for its 7th year. Typically, DIY enthusiasts of all ages and from all backgrounds gather on the grounds of the American University and put on an amazing show & tell complete with musical performance, battle bots, wild cosplay, and […]
The post Cairo Celebrates 7 Years of Maker Faire Magic appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook says Iran-based hackers used site to target US military personnel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/facebook-iran-based-hackers-us-military-personnel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/facebook-iran-based-hackers-us-military-personnel"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T19:32:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[• Social media company takes down 200 accounts
• ‘Hallmarks of a well-resourced and persistent operation’
Facebook said on Thursday it had taken down about 200 accounts run by a group of hackers in Iran as part of a cyber-spying operation that targeted mostly US military personnel and people working at defense and aerospace companies.
The social media company said the group, dubbed “Tortoiseshell” by security experts, used fake online personas to connect with targets, build trust – sometimes over the course of several months – and drive them to other sites, where they were tricked into clicking malicious links that would infect their devices with spying malware.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The person to ‘weaken’ America: what the Kremlin papers said about Trump]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/15/the-person-to-weaken-america-what-the-kremlin-papers-said-about-trump</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/15/the-person-to-weaken-america-what-the-kremlin-papers-said-about-trump"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T17:05:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Documents appear to show how Russian intelligence worked to install their preferred candidate as president
Papers appear to show Putin’s plot to put Trump in White House
In January 2016, America was coming to terms with what had previously seemed incredible. Barring an unforeseen event, Donald J Trump was on course to become the Republican party’s presidential candidate. Some welcomed this giddy prospect, while others in the Republican establishment recoiled in horror.
The man himself oozed confidence. “I have a feeling it’s going to work out, actually,” he told his rival Ted Cruz, at a Fox News debate. By 22 January, the polls had Trump well ahead, as a snowstorm nudged towards Washington.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Harding and Dan Sabbagh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israeli spyware firm linked to fake Black Lives Matter and Amnesty websites – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/spyware-company-impersonates-activist-groups-black-lives-matter</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/spyware-company-impersonates-activist-groups-black-lives-matter"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T15:18:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers say web domains masquerading as activist, health and media groups are used by governments to hack targets
An Israeli company that sells spyware to governments is linked to fake Black Lives Matter and Amnesty International websites that are used to hack targets, according to a new report.
Researchers from the Citizen Lab at the University of Toronto, who worked with Microsoft, issued a report on Thursday about the potential targets of Candiru, a Tel Aviv-based firm marketing “untraceable” spyware that can infect and monitor computers and phones.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin in Los Angeles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sony WF-1000XM4 review: the best-sounding noise-cancelling earbuds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/sony-wf-1000xm4-review-the-best-sounding-noise-cancelling-earbuds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/sony-wf-1000xm4-review-the-best-sounding-noise-cancelling-earbuds"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T06:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Comfortable and long lasting with good case and brilliant audio but ultimately disposable
Sony’s latest top-of-the-range noise-cancelling earbuds are a cut above the previous generation and the competition.
Costing £250 ($279.99/A$449.99), the WF-1000XM4 are premium true wireless earbuds that go toe to toe with the likes of the Apple AirPods Pro, Jabra Elite 85t and Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No cults, no politics, no ghouls: how China censors the video game world]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jul/15/china-video-game-censorship-tencent-netease-blizzard</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jul/15/china-video-game-censorship-tencent-netease-blizzard"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T05:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[China’s video game market is the world’s biggest. International developers want in on it – but its rules on what is acceptable are growing increasingly harsh. Is it worth the compromise?
In the years after it was founded in 1999, the Swedish video game company Paradox Interactive quietly built a reputation for developing some of the best, and most hardcore, strategy games on the market. “Deep, endless, complex, unyielding games,” is how Shams Jorjani, the company’s chief business development officer, describes Paradox’s offerings. Most of its biggest hits, such as the middle ages-themed Crusader Kings, or Sengoku, in which you play as a 16th-century Japanese noble, were loosely based on history.
But in 2016, Paradox decided to try something a little different. Its new game, Stellaris, was a work of sprawling science fiction, set 200 years in the future. In this virtual universe, players could explore richly detailed galaxies, command their own fusion-powered starship fleets and fight with extraterrestrials to expand their space empires. Gamers could choose to play as the human race, or one of many alien species. (My personal favourite dresses in a lavish golden cape and has a head like an otter’s, with soft reddish-brown fur, dark eyes and a black snout. Another type of alien is a sentient crystal that eats rocks.)
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword HD review – still a cut above]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/14/the-legend-of-zelda-skyward-sword-hd-review-nintendo-switch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/14/the-legend-of-zelda-skyward-sword-hd-review-nintendo-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T13:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch; Nintendo
This remastered game from the Wii-era remains a wildly imaginative and magical experience created by Nintendo’s brainiest puzzle architects
In 2011, when Nintendo reforged The Legend of Zelda around the waggling of a Wii remote in Skyward Sword, there was a sense that the developer had lost sight of the wood for the trees; that in focusing so tightly on gyroscopic sword-waving, the game lost some of the series’ adventurous scope. But now that motion controls are widely accepted, or at least less pressed to argue their case, this HD remake seems more comfortable in its own skin. The hand-swinging sword combat benefits from the Switch controllers’ tighter tracking, and new button controls accommodate players who are reluctant to shift from a horizontal couch position.
Motion control detractors may claim that Nintendo is conceding something here, but this is still a Hyrule built around the drama of a directional slash. Slobbering plants can be sliced along horizontal and vertical jawlines, and the glowing seams on robotic totem poles beckon like the “tear here” line on a family bag of sweets. Swinging one hand to cut and jabbing the other to parry with a shield is powerful play-acting, and nudging the control stick can’t help but feel timid by comparison. It left me wistful for the Wii, the pluck of a bow string transporting me back to Wii Sports Resort; a harp-strum dredging up memories of smiling politely through Wii Music recitals. It’s a shame that Nintendo has dialled back on motion controls just as the technology matured.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Silicon Valley before the silicon: a boy’s own story – in pictures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jul/14/silicon-valley-hawkeye-in-pictures</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/gallery/2021/jul/14/silicon-valley-hawkeye-in-pictures"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T06:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For his eighth birthday in 1959 David Pace was given a Brownie Hawkeye camera. The young boy photographed family, church, work, and school in the region of California that would become the tech giants’ home 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Technology | The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Prune Basil The Right Way]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34566</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/pruning-basil/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T18:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pruning basil is simple, results in a bushier and healthier plant, and will also give you larger yields. In this post I’ll tell you why and when to do it, and then show you step by step exactly how to cut back your basil. The best way to have the maximum production from your basilContinue Reading
The post How To Prune Basil The Right Way appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phil Spencer on the future of Xbox: we still want to take risks with games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/13/phil-spencer-future-of-microsoft-xbox-risks-narrative-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/13/phil-spencer-future-of-microsoft-xbox-risks-narrative-games"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T08:30:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While developing traditional narrative games is harder than it has ever been, Microsoft’s Xbox chief sees an opportunity in using modern platforms and tech to tell new stories
Over the last decade, the concept of “games as a service” has revolutionised the way the interactive entertainment industry works. From the subscriptions introduced by massively multiplayer online adventures such as World of Warcraft to the seasonal battle passes of current online shooters, we’re seeing a huge amount of focus on games that can sustain a lucrative community of players over several years.
But where does that leave more offbeat ideas and concepts that couldn’t support years’ worth of play? Where does it leave the single-player narrative adventure – the blockbusting genre that brought us titles such as Metal Gear Solid, Red Dead Redemption and Mass Effect? It’s a genre Sony has supported through funding the studios that make games such as The Last of Us, Spider-Man and God of War. But Microsoft has focused its efforts on cross-platform, connected games, as symbolised by the mammoth Minecraft industry. Is there still room for traditional forms of narrative games on the Xbox Series X?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What happens at Sun Valley, the secret gathering of unelected billionaire kings? | Hamilton Nolan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/12/what-happens-at-sun-valley-the-secret-gathering-of-unelected-billionaire-kings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/12/what-happens-at-sun-valley-the-secret-gathering-of-unelected-billionaire-kings"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T10:16:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are developing a private class of billionaire kings whose will is omnipotent and untouchable by any democratic force
There comes a moment in every good gangster movie when all of the villains come together in a remote hideaway to make nefarious plans. If the good guys are smart, this is the moment they swoop in and arrest everyone. In real life America, though, we consistently squander these opportunities, opting instead to sit back and gawk at the villains like a bunch of dazed paparazzi. It’s never too late to change that.
 Related: Bernie in Trumpworld: Sanders visits ‘imperative if democracy is to survive’ 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hamilton Nolan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[3D Modeling for Makers]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/08/3d-modeling-for-makers/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/08/3d-modeling-for-makers/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T05:52:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lydia Sloan Cline is the author of Fusion 360 for Makers, which is out in a new second edition. She teaches 3D design and fabrication at Johnson County Community College in Overland Park, Kansas, where she began as a drafting professor with a degree in Architecture. In this episode of Make:cast, Patrick DiJusto, Make: Books […]
The post 3D Modeling for Makers appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Female -vs- Male Squash Flowers: How To Tell The Difference]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34781</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/male-vs-female-squash-blossoms/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T15:11:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Squash plants have both male and female blossoms, and they each play a key role in fruit production. In this post, I’ll talk about the differences between female vs male squash flowers, and show you tons of photos to help you easily and quickly tell them apart. It’s important to be able to tell theContinue Reading
The post Female -vs- Male Squash Flowers: How To Tell The Difference appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Story of Film: A New Generation review – invigorating study of 21st century cinema]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/06/the-story-of-film-a-new-generation-review-invigorating-study-of-21st-century-cinema</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/06/the-story-of-film-a-new-generation-review-invigorating-study-of-21st-century-cinema"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T19:27:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critic and film-maker Mark Cousins offers a new instalment in his monumental Story of Film series, examining what digital technology has brought to the table
Critic and documentary film-maker Mark Cousins has returned to Cannes with another episode of his amazingly ambitious cinephile history The Story of Film, an illuminated patchwork clip-quilt, accompanied by his inimitable incantation-voiceover. It’s another example of his unique approach: Cousins is subjective almost to the point of free-associating or even sleep-talking (maybe appropriate for the dream state of the movies) but also colossally well-informed, bracingly internationalist and genuinely educational. I have never yet watched a Cousins film without learning something and being a bit sheepish about what I didn’t know.
That said, Cousins’s style takes some getting used to – almost like a hyper-innocent form of criticism, wide-eyed with wonder at cinema’s brave new world, a Miranda of the movies. Occasionally Cousins’s commentary verges on the superfluous, simply describing what is on screen, although there is almost always a shrewd insight there: he has a great section on a creepy travelling shot in David Robert Mitchell’s psychological horror It Follows.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Pollinate Squash By Hand For Maximum Production]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34564</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/pollinating-squash/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T16:27:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pollinating squash by hand is easy, will ensure higher yields, and doesn’t take much time. In this post, I will explain why your baby squash keep falling off, and discuss the processes of hand pollinating the flowers step-by-step. One of the biggest struggles that newbies face when growing vegetables for the first time is havingContinue Reading
The post How To Pollinate Squash By Hand For Maximum Production appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Stefan Hermann of CNC Kitchen]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/06/maker-spotlight-stefan-hermann-of-cnc-kitchen/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/06/maker-spotlight-stefan-hermann-of-cnc-kitchen/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First and last name Stefan Hermann Where are you located?  Germany What is your day job?  Metal Additive Manufacturing Research Engineer Youtube Channel | Patreon What kinds of stuff do you make?  3D Printing Stuff, Material Tests and 3D Printing Research How did you get started making stuff?  Bought a book about Arduino, purchased a […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Stefan Hermann of CNC Kitchen appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Venu 2 review: can Garmin make a good smartwatch?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/venu-2-review-can-garmin-make-a-good-smartwatch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/venu-2-review-can-garmin-make-a-good-smartwatch"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T06:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fitness firm’s new Apple Watch-rival looks the part and tracks loads of data but lacks some real smarts
Garmin’s latest device aims to beat the Apple Watch and rivals at their own game, offering longer battery life and better fitness tracking in a more traditional touchscreen smartwatch body.
The Venu 2 comes in either 40mm or 45mm models, costs from £349.99 ($399.99/A$629) and is compatible with both Android and iPhones connecting via Bluetooth.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This space race has its downside… Rocketwoman Wally Funk joins crew for Jeff Bezos’s ego trip]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/04/this-space-race-has-its-downside-rocketwoman-wally-funk-joins-crew-for-jeff-bezoss-ego-trip</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/04/this-space-race-has-its-downside-rocketwoman-wally-funk-joins-crew-for-jeff-bezoss-ego-trip"/>
        <updated>2021-07-04T09:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The veteran US pilot is set to become the oldest woman in space – the only snag is she has to go with the Amazon billionaire 
You have to feel for the American pilot Wally Funk. You would sympathise with anyone with that name, but she has had a particularly mixed week. On one hand, at 82, she is set to finally fulfil her life’s ambition and travel into space. Funk was one of the most promising female candidates for the Mercury 13 programme in the 1960s, but was denied a spot because of her gender. Right stuff, wrong parts. On Thursday, the Amazon founder, Jeff Bezos, announced on Instagram that Wally would become the oldest person in space as one of the four passengers on New Shepard, the rocket being launched by his company Blue Origin on 20 July. “I didn’t think I’d ever get to go up,” Funk said in an interview.
The obvious downside, which she was too polite to mention, is that she has to ride with Bezos, his brother and one other, in a kind of UberPool from hell. She ought to have been more specific to the genie. Midlife does strange things to men, and so does being a billionaire. The combination leads to some odd outcomes. Not content with building his own rockets, Jeff, as he approaches 60, has decided to start riding them as well. Towers and yachts are so passé. Private space travel is the thing. Elon Musk is at it, too, and presumably a load of guys in China.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Cumming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The week in audio: Pieces of Britney; Elon Musk: The Evening Rocket; Human Resources and more]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/03/pieces-of-britney-review-elon-musk-the-evening-rocket-human-resources-the-essay-caribbean-voices-the-kindness-experiment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/03/pieces-of-britney-review-elon-musk-the-evening-rocket-human-resources-the-essay-caribbean-voices-the-kindness-experiment"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T16:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Radio 4 series on Britney Spears’s troubles and Elon Musk’s space ambitions highlight society’s double standards
Pieces of Britney (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Elon Musk: The Evening Rocket (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Human Resources Broccoli Productions | Spotify
The Essay: Caribbean Voices (Radio 3) | BBC Sounds
The Kindness Experiment (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Britney Spears has been in the news a lot over the past few weeks. Her recent court plea to be released from legal conservatorship was horrible and shocking; and also rejected. Judge Brenda Penny ruled last Wednesday that the current situation – where Britney’s father Jamie is a co-conservator, even though he’s ill – should stay in place. Pain, when expressed by a woman, is often disbelieved and ignored.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Sawyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enjoy the restored Night Watch, but don’t ignore the machine behind the Rembrandt]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/commentisfree/2021/jul/03/enjoy-the-restored-night-watch-but-dont-ignore-the-machine-behind-the-rembrandt</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/commentisfree/2021/jul/03/enjoy-the-restored-night-watch-but-dont-ignore-the-machine-behind-the-rembrandt"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T15:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The computer restoration of this masterpiece illustrates both the benefits and the dangers of AI
In the late 1970s I lived and worked briefly in the Netherlands. Often, on Sundays, I would travel to Amsterdam, go to the morning concert in the Spiegelzaal of the Concertgebouw, and afterwards walk over to the Rijksmuseum, Holland’s national gallery, and spend a couple of hours there. The museum is a wonderful storehouse of Dutch art and there was always much to explore. But on nearly every visit I found myself being drawn back to one of Rembrandt’s most famous pictures – The Night Watch – which I guess is to the Rijksmuseum what the Mona Lisa is to the Louvre.
Its official title is Militia Company of District II under the Command of Captain Frans Banninck Cocq. It came to be called The Night Watch because by the end of the 18th century it had darkened considerably through the accumulation of layers of dirt and varnish, leading to the belief that the painted scene had occurred after dusk.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s next for Jeff Bezos? Space, climate and media may all figure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/whats-next-for-jeff-bezos-space-climate-and-media-may-all-figure</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/whats-next-for-jeff-bezos-space-climate-and-media-may-all-figure"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T05:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As he hands over top job at Amazon, Bezos will remain largest shareholder and ‘has never had more energy’
A quarter of a century after he founded Amazon in a Seattle garage, Jeff Bezos is preparing to loosen his grip on his $1.7tn (£1.2tn) company. Few employees in the sphere conservatories at Amazon’s sprawling Seattle campus headquarters reckon Bezos will relinquish that much of his iron grip on the company’s big decisions when Andy Jassy succeeds him as CEO on Monday. After all, Bezos will become executive chairman of Amazon’s board and remains the company’s biggest shareholder. But Bezos, 57, told his 1.3 million employees (whom he refers to as “fellow Amazonians”) that “as much as I still tap dance into the office, I’m excited about this transition”.
“I’ve never had more energy, and this isn’t about retiring,” he said. “I intend to focus my energies and attention on new products and early initiatives … I’m super passionate about the impact I think these organisations can have.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate Wealth correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire HD 10 Plus (2021) review: Amazon’s top budget tablet upgraded]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/fire-hd-10-plus-2021-review-amazons-top-budget-tablet-upgraded</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/fire-hd-10-plus-2021-review-amazons-top-budget-tablet-upgraded"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T06:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Slimmer, better design, long battery life, 10.1in HD screen and speakers makes for a good TV tablet
Amazon’s top 10in Fire OS tablet has had a makeover and now has faster performance, without costing iPad money.
The 2021 Fire HD 10 comes in either a standard version costing £150/US$150 or a “Plus” version, as tested here, costing £180/US$180, with a few more bells and whistles.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emotion and Empathy Are Glue for Makers]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/01/emotion-and-empathy-are-glue-for-makers/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/01/emotion-and-empathy-are-glue-for-makers/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:33:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2020, Dr. Andreea Gorbatai and two co-authors published a research paper in the journal Organization Science titled: “Making Space for Emotions: Empathy, Contagion, and Legitmacy’s Double-Edged Sword.” It’s about the maker movement and what holds it together. It turns out, it’s not skills and tools as much as it is emotions and empathy — […]
The post Emotion and Empathy Are Glue for Makers appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting Brussels Sprouts – Everything You Need To Know]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34562</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/harvesting-brussels-sprouts/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:38:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting brussels sprouts is easier than you might think, and actually kinda fun too! In this post, you’ll learn how to tell when they are ready to pick, plus I’ll show you step by step exactly how to gather them, and even give you tips for using, and storing them for later. Have you everContinue Reading
The post Harvesting Brussels Sprouts – Everything You Need To Know appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting Kohlrabi – Everything You Need To Know]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34560</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/harvesting-kohlrabi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T18:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting kohlrabi may sound intimidating, but it’s actually very easy. In this post, I’ll show how to tell when they are ready, the best way to pick them, and even give you tips for using and storing your garden fresh kohlrabi harvest. Despite how it may sound, the steps for harvesting kohlrabi are actually veryContinue Reading
The post Harvesting Kohlrabi – Everything You Need To Know appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If You’re Into 3D Printing, You Need To Be Watching CNC Kitchen]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/29/if-youre-into-3d-printing-you-need-to-be-watching-cnc-kitchen/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/29/if-youre-into-3d-printing-you-need-to-be-watching-cnc-kitchen/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T15:04:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CNC Kitchen channel, run by Stefan, is a treasure trove of tests and real data surrounding many 3d printing topics
The post If You’re Into 3D Printing, You Need To Be Watching CNC Kitchen appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Making Of ‘Lord of the Rings’ inspired ‘Fellbeast’ Head]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/28/the-making-of-lord-of-the-rings-inspired-fellbeast-head/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/28/the-making-of-lord-of-the-rings-inspired-fellbeast-head/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Follow along as an artist shares the process of recreating the Fell Beast form the Lord Of The Rings
The post The Making Of ‘Lord of the Rings’ inspired ‘Fellbeast’ Head appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>