<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-08-19T00:29:40.764Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-08-19T00:29:40.764Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY Source Measurement Unit Shows All The Details]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=491814</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/08/18/diy-source-measurement-unit-shows-all-the-details/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T23:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[An SMU or Source Measurement Unit works a bit like a power supply, in that it can source current into a load and a bit like an electronic load, in …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dave Rowntree</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Get Rid of Grass Stains]]></title>
        <id>1847512548</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-get-rid-of-grass-stains-1847512548"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grass stains are both tough and annoyingly common. The stains come from a mix of chlorophyll, xanthophylls, and carotenoids that stick to our clothes and are hard to scrub out, but hope isn’t all lost—in this small instance, we can beat nature. Here’s how to get rid of stubborn grass stains for good. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Build an Amphibious Robot Using Pool Noodles for Wheels]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=492011</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/08/18/build-an-amphibious-robot-using-pool-noodles-for-wheels/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T20:00:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you only think of wheels as round, you’re limiting yourself from experiencing the true wider world of whacky designs. [wadevag] has been experimenting with some such concepts, and has …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lewin Day</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Latest T-Mobile Data Breach Affects Everyone, Not Just Customers]]></title>
        <id>1847512002</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-latest-t-mobile-data-breach-effects-everyone-not-j-1847512002"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[T-Mobile confirmed a security breach that leaked over 48 million current, former, and prospective users. T-Mobile says it closed the server vulnerability hackers used to access the files, but the leaked information is now for sale online. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Hesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Can See Way Better Fitness Stats on Your Apple Watch]]></title>
        <id>1847507689</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/you-can-see-way-better-fitness-stats-on-your-apple-watc-1847507689"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’re probably not making the most of your Apple Watch if you aren’t using it for fitness, and while you’re exploring this topic, you should consider tweaking the stats the watch shows you, too.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranay Parab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[9 Reasons You Should Buy a Pixel 5a Over the iPhone SE]]></title>
        <id>1847503320</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/9-reasons-you-should-buy-a-pixel-5a-over-the-iphone-se-1847503320"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T19:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Pixel 5a with 5G (which, let’s be real, we’re all just going to call “the 5a”) is Google’s latest “budget” smartphone. At $449, it isn’t cheap, but it’s far more affordable than other flagship devices. Of course, Apple has a budget phone of its own in the iPhone SE. If you’re in the market for a ~$400 smartphone,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jake Peterson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hey, Where's My Child Tax Credit?]]></title>
        <id>1847510616</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/hey-wheres-my-missing-child-tax-credit-1847510616"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re wondering where your child tax credit payment is for August or July, you’re not alone. Some families are still waiting to receive the monthly checks worth up to $300 per child, although the good news is that for most people, these delays are temporary. Here’s a look at what’s going on.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why a Slowing Metabolism Probably Isn't Causing Your Weight Gain]]></title>
        <id>1847507925</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/why-a-slowing-metabolism-probably-isnt-causing-your-wei-1847507925"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many of us are carrying a little bit more weight now than when we were in our 20s. However, as tempting as it is to blame this weight gain on a slowing metabolism, that may not actually be the case, according to a study released last week in the journal Science.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Fairbank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Powered Standing Desk Rises To New Heights]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=492063</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/08/18/raspberry-pi-powered-standing-desk-rises-to-new-heights/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Like many office workers, [David Kong] found himself the lucky recipient of a motorized sit-stand desk. Also like most office workers with such a desk, he found himself mostly sitting. …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Carlson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Look More Confident During Your Next Job Interview]]></title>
        <id>1847484480</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-look-more-confident-during-your-next-job-intervi-1847484480"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T18:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With corporate offices slowly re-opening post-lockdown, we all may soon be expected to go back to interviewing the old-fashioned way—in person. Where simply wearing a shirt, looking at the webcam, and not audibly farting may have been enough to present yourself as a consummate professional in the Zoom Times, sitting…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Showfety</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Finally Use Your iCloud Passwords on Windows]]></title>
        <id>1847507307</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-finally-use-your-icloud-passwords-on-windows-1847507307"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The iCloud app for Windows lets you access your iCloud photos, mail, calendar, and more on your Windows PC, but one thing that’s been missing is iCloud Keychain. If you mostly use Apple products but have a Windows PC at home for gaming or desktop, this is the one that really stings. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alexei Toliopoulos: the funniest things I have ever seen (on the internet)]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/aug/19/alexei-toliopoulos-the-funniest-things-i-have-ever-seen-on-the-internet</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/aug/19/alexei-toliopoulos-the-funniest-things-i-have-ever-seen-on-the-internet"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T17:30:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We ask funny people about what’s funny online. Comedian Alexei Toliopoulos dives so deep he hasn’t seen the surface in years
My whole life is a deep dive into the mysteries of pop culture. I don’t think I’ve seen the surface in years and likely have a permanent case of the bends. 
Each of these treasures I’ve unearthed in my life’s mission of pop culture exploration and investigation transcends in some way. Whether it’s capturing the rarest and most authentic moments of verisimilitude or the beauty of unintentional chaos. Each of these examples reflects something pure and holds immense amounts of power.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alexei Toliopoulos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Australian watchdog considers regulating Apple and Google to boost app store competition]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/19/australian-watchdog-considers-regulating-apple-and-google-to-boost-app-store-competition</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/19/australian-watchdog-considers-regulating-apple-and-google-to-boost-app-store-competition"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T17:30:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Push comes as Fortnite creator Epic Games fights a global legal battle against the tech giants over in-app payments
As Fortnite creator Epic Games continues its global legal battle against Apple and Google over in-app payments, the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission says “upfront rules and regulations” may be needed to force the tech giants to open their app stores to greater competition.
For Apple iOS platforms, developers must use the App Store, while for Google, apps can be installed on Android devices outside the Play store either through direct download or alternative marketplaces, but uptake of these options is limited.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Josh Taylor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stop Saying These 15 Things to Pregnant People, FFS]]></title>
        <id>1847502467</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/stop-saying-these-15-things-to-pregnant-people-ffs-1847502467"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[At some point during pregnancy, usually as soon you begin to show, mere acquaintances and passersby start saying some seriously inappropriate shit to people who are with child. While many of these comments have become so commonplace that most people assume them harmless, upon further investigation with myriad formerly…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Showfety</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[T-Mobile breach exposes personal information of 40 million US users]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/aug/18/t-mobile-breach-exposes-personal-information-40-million-users</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/aug/18/t-mobile-breach-exposes-personal-information-40-million-users"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T17:21:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Social security numbers, names, phone numbers and account pins were exposed in some cases, according to the company
A security breach against T-Mobile has exposed personal information, including social security numbers (SSN) and pins in some cases, of more than 40 million users, the company said in a statement on Wednesday morning.
The same data for about 7.8 million current T-Mobile post-paid customers appears to be compromised. No phone numbers, account numbers, pins, passwords or financial information from the nearly 50m records and accounts were compromised, it said.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samira Sadeque and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eat Caviar Off the Back of Your Hand]]></title>
        <id>1847510212</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/eat-caviar-off-the-back-of-your-hand-1847510212"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T17:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A few years ago, I embarked on a dream trip to the South of France, where I took cooking lessons at La Pitchoune (Julia Child’s summer home for nearly three decades). I split the cost of the stay and the lessons with five other women, one of whom was clearly accustomed to this kind of life. (Although I had done a…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Golden Rice’s Appearance On Philippine Store Shelves And The Rise Of Biofortification]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=489987</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/08/18/golden-rices-appearance-on-philippine-store-shelves-and-the-rise-of-biofortification/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T17:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After decades in development, the Philippines became the first country on July 21st of this year to formally approve the commercial propagation of so-called golden rice. This is a rice …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Posch</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This Mexican Butterwort Plant Can Help Solve Your Gnat Problem]]></title>
        <id>1847498754</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/this-mexican-butterwort-plant-can-help-solve-your-gnat-1847498754"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gnats and other small flies are annoying to get rid of. A small number of them is bad enough, but an infestation can mean a lot more effort. There are several remedies we’ve covered before, like apple cider vinegar traps, but there’s a plant that can help solve your gnat problems, too.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Keep Amazon From Spoiling Your Surprise Gifts]]></title>
        <id>1847506259</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-keep-amazon-from-spoiling-your-surprise-gifts-1847506259"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When you share a single Amazon account with a partner and/or kids, it’s pretty difficult to keep any shopping a surprise. Amazon tracks your search history (and then serves you ads), orders are easily reviewed, and there are tons of notifications between the time you place an order and the moment it arrives on your…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Long</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Will We Need a COVID Booster Shot, After All?]]></title>
        <id>1847509675</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/will-we-need-a-covid-booster-shot-after-all-1847509675"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T16:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Even though the CDC and FDA said recently that there’s no evidence most people will need booster COVID-19 shots, a group of experts from the U.S. Department of Health and Human Services issued a statement in which they “conclude that a booster shot will be needed to maximize vaccine-induced protection and prolong its…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twelve Minutes review – a tense time-loop thriller]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/18/twelve-minutes-review</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/18/twelve-minutes-review"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T16:00:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Xbox, PC; Luis Antonia/Annapurna Interactive
This stylish, twisted take on movies such as Rear Window and Chinatown marries noir sensibilities with puzzle gameplay
A man comes home to his small apartment, greets his wife and the two make affectionate small talk. But within the next five minutes, a cop will burst in, tie them both up, accuse the woman of murdering her father and finally strangle the man unconscious. At this point, time resets and the husband is mysteriously jolted back to the moment he arrived in the flat. He has 12 minutes to work out what his wife has done and why. And he’ll live those same 12 minutes over and over again until it’s solved.
This is the intriguing premise behind Annapurna Interactive’s compact, tense point-and-click adventure, created by ex-Rockstar and Ubisoft developer Luis Antonio. Clearly inspired by the psychological thrillers of Hitchcock, Kubrick and Verhoeven, Twelve Minutes gives us a top-down chessboard view of a stage limited to just three rooms, with all the space provided by the backstories of the protagonists. Taking the role of the husband, the player must use each new playthrough to discover fresh information, exploring the apartment and working out how an array of seemingly unrelated objects – a mobile phone, a knife, a photo, a jar of sleeping pills – can be utilised or combined to open fresh conversational and deductive pathways.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Stop Apple From Scanning Your iPhone Photos Before iOS 15 Arrives]]></title>
        <id>1847508003</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-stop-apple-from-scanning-your-iphone-photos-befo-1847508003"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Starting with iOS 15 and iPadOS 15, Apple is going to apply a new child-protection policy when it comes to scanning photos that you upload to iCloud. This policy will help Apple report illegal child pornography images to the authorities, and on the surface, it sounds like a good thing that Apple is doing. But there’s…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Figure Out Why Your Dog Is Aggressive—and What to Do About It]]></title>
        <id>1847483569</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-figure-out-why-your-dog-is-aggressive-and-what-t-1847483569"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[American culture is dog-obsessed. Cuddly, fluffy, loyal, and funny, these animals are all over our social media feeds and our homes. But when your dog typically cuddly dog starts acting aggressive, however, it can come as a surprise. The reality of a growling, biting dog doesn’t match up to the adorable balls of floof…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lindsey Ellefson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Design Improvements Make DIY Oxygen Concentrator Even Better]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=491918</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/08/18/design-improvements-make-diy-oxygen-concentrator-even-better/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A lot of projects we feature on these pages are of the “one and done” variety — tactical builds that serve a specific purpose with little need for further development. …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Maloney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Enable Android's New Chat Bubbles]]></title>
        <id>1847502823</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-enable-androids-new-chat-bubbles-1847502823"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Smart phone notifications can be overwhelming. They can also be, well, boring, hidden away as little rectangles at the top of your screen and looking mostly the same. If you want to spice up your notifications a little, consider taking advantage of one of Google’s fun alert features: chat bubbles.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jake Peterson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gqeberha shack dwellers block road, stone cars in protest over electricity and sanitation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gqeberha-shack-dwellers-block-road-stone-cars-protest-over-electricity-and-sanitation/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gqeberha-shack-dwellers-block-road-stone-cars-protest-over-electricity-and-sanitation/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T14:36:12.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[700 households share three taps and three toilets]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook no, Twitter yes: which tech firms let the Taliban post?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/aug/18/how-are-tech-firms-dealing-with-taliban-social-media</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/aug/18/how-are-tech-firms-dealing-with-taliban-social-media"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T14:32:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Analysis: Twitter has faced criticism for allowing members to post, while Facebook has taken harder line

Afghanistan live news: latest updates

As Kabul fell to Taliban forces over the weekend, social networks struggled to cope with the renewed attention brought to the organisation – and its presence on their platforms.
In the US, Republicans expressed outrage that Twitter, which had permanently banned Donald Trump from its platform in January, seemed content to allow named Taliban members access to the social network to promote their narrative. WhatsApp faced criticism for its role in enabling the Taliban to threaten, cajole and bribe local leaders into laying down their arms as they marched across the country. At Google, YouTube’s seeming lack of any substantial policy allowed it to avoid much of the attention, until it became the last network not to have rebuked the organisation.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern Technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's New on Disney+ in September 2021]]></title>
        <id>1847506610</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/whats-new-on-disney-plus-in-september-2021-1847506610"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[For a certain segment of Star Wars fans—a segment of which I am not a part, though I have been cramming my head full of information about the franchise since roughly 1985—nothing is more important than arguing over what’s part of the canon. That is, which of the stories that have been told in this universe over the…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Cunningham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Airdropping Live Fish Is A Thing And It Looks Magnificent]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=489589</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/08/18/airdropping-live-fish-is-a-thing-and-it-looks-magnificent/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T14:01:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Utah is a place that features a wonderful and varied wilderness. Its mountainous terrain is home to many valleys, ponds, and streams. They’re a particular favorite of recreational anglers who …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lewin Day</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What's New on Hulu in September 2021]]></title>
        <id>1847506875</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/whats-new-on-hulu-in-september-2021-1847506875"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hollywood seems to have the comic book movie down, but when it comes to adapting graphic novels as TV series, it’s still very much a mixed bag. For every The Umbrella Academy, there’s a Jupiter’s Legacy. For every Doom Patrol, there’s an Iron Fist. For every The Walking Dead, there’s the later seasons of The Walking…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Cunningham</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Much Cash Should You Ideally Keep in Your Bank Accounts?]]></title>
        <id>1847505289</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-much-cash-should-you-ideally-keep-in-your-bank-acco-1847505289"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While it’s important to have some cash in your bank account, it’s also possible to keep too much cash on hand when you don’t really need it. After all, some of that money could be invested elsewhere, where the interest rates are much more favorable. But how much cash should you have, and how much is too much or too…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[These Cold Meat Recipes Are Just as Good as Hot (or Even Better)]]></title>
        <id>1847501760</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/these-cold-meat-recipes-are-just-as-good-as-hot-or-eve-1847501760"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“It’s too hot to eat” is a sentiment Caribbean folk know too well, especially in August, though admittedly it’s often said but rarely abided by. Yet with continual heat waves sweeping across the US, we must be mindful of our ecological footprints and utilize various strategies for staying cool besides putting the AC…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Vaughn Stafford Gray</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[20 Movie Trailers That Are Better Than the Movie Itself]]></title>
        <id>1847500749</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/20-movie-trailers-that-are-better-than-the-movie-itself-1847500749"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T12:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s an art to the movie trailer, although not everyone who constructs a trailer is an artist. The best tell us a story about the film we’re meant to go see, to tell us precisely why we’re meant to spend our precious movie dollars and run  off to the theater for a couple of hours (and/or throw $30 at Disney+ for an…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ross Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Boat Brings Bathers Beverages]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=491982</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/08/18/boat-brings-bathers-beverages/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Chilling in the pool is great, but what a drag to have to get out to grab a cold brew. [Alister] had his eye on a commercial drink float, but …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Al Williams</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[TechScape: How the UK forced global shift in child safety policies]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/18/uk-governments-child-safety-regulation-leads-to-global-policy-shifts</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/18/uk-governments-child-safety-regulation-leads-to-global-policy-shifts"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T10:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Up for discussion in the Guardian tech newsletter: Instagram, Tik Tok and YouTube implement new rules … CGI CEOs … and unpleasant rightwing ‘lolz’ in Kabul
I bring good news: regulation works.
The last month has brought a flurry of changes to major tech platforms related to child safety online, and specifically to the use and protection of children’s personal data.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Millions of rands in suspicious transactions found in accounts of Limpopo land claimants]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/millions-rands-suspicious-transactions-found-accounts-limpopo-land-claimants/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/millions-rands-suspicious-transactions-found-accounts-limpopo-land-claimants/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T10:19:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Court upholds decision to withdraw state funding for Moletele Community Property Association]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to boost the Covid-19 vaccine rollout]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/how-boost-covid-19-vaccine-rollout/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/how-boost-covid-19-vaccine-rollout/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T10:10:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Government has got a few things right, but there’s so much more it can still do]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t blame Russian trolls for our anti-vaxx problem. Our misinformation is homegrown | Sophie Zhang]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/18/facebook-fazze-russian-trolls-anti-vaxx-misinformation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/18/facebook-fazze-russian-trolls-anti-vaxx-misinformation"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T10:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I blew the whistle on inauthentic behavior at Facebook. But authentic misinformation is the bigger problem in the west
On 18 May 2021, German YouTuber Mirko Drotschmann tweeted an unusual message: a marketing agency was asking him to share allegedly leaked documents on Covid-19 vaccine deaths. Within a week, French YouTuber Léo Grasset shared similar news. News reports followed: Fazze, a London-based marketing firm with ties to Russia, was offering money to influencers to falsely disparage a Covid-19 vaccine.
 Related: Facebook shut down our research into its role in spreading disinformation | Laura Edelson and Damon McCoy 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sophie Zhang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Elderly people in rural Makana struggle to get to vaccine sites]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/elderly-rural-makana-struggling-access-vaccine-sites/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/elderly-rural-makana-struggling-access-vaccine-sites/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T09:17:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[People are paying R60 for transport to Covid vaccination sites in Makhanda, and that’s just for the first jab]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taps keep running dry in Louis Trichardt]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/taps-have-run-dry-louis-trichardt/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/taps-have-run-dry-louis-trichardt/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T08:05:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Residential areas and the town centre have been without reliable water for over a month]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng government takes vaccination drive to informal settlements]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-government-takes-vaccination-drive-informal-settlements/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-government-takes-vaccination-drive-informal-settlements/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T04:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[And Saaberie Chishty Society helps get people vaccinated outside their homes]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Teachers demand KZN education department pay them, fill vacant posts]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/teachers-demand-kzn-education-department-pay-them-fill-vacant-posts/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/teachers-demand-kzn-education-department-pay-them-fill-vacant-posts/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-18T02:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[SADTU: “As we speak more than 1,203 substitute teachers have either not been paid or told not to come back to school”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alexa Chung’s YouTubes haven’t helped my hair – but they have helped me through lockdown]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/aug/18/alexa-chungs-youtubes-havent-helped-my-hair-but-they-have-helped-me-through-lockdown</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/aug/18/alexa-chungs-youtubes-havent-helped-my-hair-but-they-have-helped-me-through-lockdown"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T22:00:36.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sinead Stubbins is the first to admit she might know a bit too much about the British personality. Is it creepy? Maybe. Maybe not? Who knows
• Internet Wormhole is a new column where Guardian Australia writers take you on a tour of their online obsession. Click here for more
Last year, I spent a lot of time staring intently into a computer screen at a person who does not know I exist. Let’s just say if restraining orders were determined by hours spent watching someone’s YouTube channel, British model, designer and TV presenter Alexa Chung would have a pretty decent case against me.
Alexa Chung’s YouTube channel started in 2018 with sporadic videos promoting her clothing label and for the last couple of years has included tutorials (for makeup, skincare and how to dress), field trips to fashion shows and interviews with other glamorous, tousled hair women in which they give advice about dating or sleeping or throwing dinner parties from their tranquil, presumably-Santal 33-scented apartments.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sinéad Stubbins</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Encrypt Your Own Windows and Mac Devices (and Why You Need To)]]></title>
        <id>1847504643</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-encrypt-your-own-windows-and-mac-devices-and-wh-1847504643"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T21:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Data encryption makes it nearly impossible for someone to access a protected file without the proper decryption key or password. Many apps use encryption to keep your data safe, including password managers, VPNs, and even some messaging apps—but you should be encrypting more than just the data you share online.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Hesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Protect Your Ears From Tinnitus, Because the Damage May Have Already Begun]]></title>
        <id>1847483602</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-protect-your-ears-from-tinnitus-because-the-dam-1847483602"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T20:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since the beginning of the pandemic, I’ve stayed fit and (relatively) sane through daily walks around my neighborhood, listening to my favorite true crime podcasts and K-pop songs. One afternoon in the spring of 2020, however, I started to hear a ringing in my right ear. I had developed tinnitus: the perception of…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sara Murphy</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Juggle More Than One Job Offer (and Get What You Want)]]></title>
        <id>1847497028</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-juggle-more-than-one-job-offer-and-get-what-you-1847497028"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While it may seem unlikely as you puff up your LinkedIn profile and go cross-eyed reading job listings on Indeed, it’s actually possible you’ll get multiple offers—or have multiple viable job opportunities on the line—in the same timeframe.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sarah Showfety</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Help People in Afghanistan Right Now]]></title>
        <id>1847503660</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-help-people-in-afghanistan-right-now-1847503660"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[On Sunday, the Taliban took control of Afghanistan’s capital city Kabul following the United States’ withdrawal of troops and the collapse of the country’s military. Many Afghanis are now in danger, including journalists, diplomats, people who have worked for or aided the US, and women and girls. You may have seen…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Propagating Christmas Cactus From Cuttings Or By Division]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34837</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/propagating-christmas-cactus/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T15:53:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Propagating Christmas cactus is simple, and a great way to get more of your favorite plant. In this post, I’ll tell you the different methods you can try. Then I will show you when and how to propagate them by cuttings or division. It may sound like it would be difficult, but propagating your favoriteContinue Reading
The post Propagating Christmas Cactus From Cuttings Or By Division appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips For Making A Large Silicone Mold]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/17/tips-for-making-a-large-silicone-mold/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/17/tips-for-making-a-large-silicone-mold/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[when it comes to making large molds, there's a lot to keep in mind
The post Tips For Making A Large Silicone Mold appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eastern Cape communities want “death trap” road fixed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/communities-sceptical-over-emergency-plan-to-fix-pothole-riddled-road/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/communities-sceptical-over-emergency-plan-to-fix-pothole-riddled-road/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T09:34:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The provincial department of transport has allocated R1.5 million for repairs but admits it is not enough to rehabilitate the R58 road]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[An interview with Hopewell Chin’ono]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/zimbabwean-journalists-live-fear-arrest-telling-truth/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/zimbabwean-journalists-live-fear-arrest-telling-truth/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T09:05:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Journalist says reporters in Zimbabwe live in fear of arrest]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why bitcoin entrepreneurs are flocking to rural Texas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/17/bitcoin-cryptocurrency-mining-texas</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/17/bitcoin-cryptocurrency-mining-texas"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T09:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mining cryptocurrency requires lots of cheap energy and many miners have settled on Texas as their destination
In the middle of rural Texas, a cryptocurrency mine is currently under construction.
Hundreds of machines more powerful than the average computer will soon be housed in this 320-acre mining facility in Dickens county, where they will work day and night to solve a complex series of algorithms. If successful, the reward will be newly minted bitcoin, currently worth about $44,000 each.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lauren Aratani</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Homeless man creates unique lampshades from recycled material]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/zimbabwean-father-creates-unique-light-pendants-recycling-material/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/zimbabwean-father-creates-unique-light-pendants-recycling-material/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T07:52:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ziggi Goredema lost his job and home at the start of lockdown and began making and selling the hanging lampshades]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tapes reveal secret workings of police disciplinary hearings for murder and brutality cases]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/tapes-reveal-secret-workings-police-disciplinary-hearings-murder-and-brutality-cases/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/tapes-reveal-secret-workings-police-disciplinary-hearings-murder-and-brutality-cases/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T03:45:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Police officer found not guilty of the killing of 15-year-old Damian Ahrendse]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Durban parents demand schools close after learner dies of Covid]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/durban-parents-demand-schools-close/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/durban-parents-demand-schools-close/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-17T03:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Protest follows death of 12-year-old Kaitlyn Pillay. Education expert warns of “dire” cost to children of closing schools.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bezos’s Blue Origin sues US over Nasa’s decision to award contract to SpaceX]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/16/blue-origin-sues-nasa-spacex-jeff-bezos-elon-musk-space-contract</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/16/blue-origin-sues-nasa-spacex-jeff-bezos-elon-musk-space-contract"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T16:30:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lawsuit filed after Blue Origin offered Nasa $2bn if it would change its mind on lunar lander contract
Jeff Bezos’s Blue Origin has sued the US government over Nasa’s decision to award a $2.9bn lunar lander contract to Elon Musk’s SpaceX.
 Related: Billionaire space cowboys could become heroes by focusing on the climate crisis 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tesla’s Autopilot faces US investigation after crashes with emergency vehicles]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/16/teslas-autopilot-us-investigation-crashes-emergency-vehicles</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/16/teslas-autopilot-us-investigation-crashes-emergency-vehicles"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T14:56:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[• Investigators to review 765,000 vehicles made since 2014
• NHTSA identifies 11 crashes involving first responder vehicles
The US government has opened a formal investigation into Tesla’s driver-assistance system known as Autopilot after a series of collisions with parked emergency vehicles.
The investigation covers 765,000 vehicles, almost everything that Tesla has sold in the US since the start of the 2014 model year. Of the crashes identified by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) as part of the investigation, 17 people were injured and one was killed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Plan to ban phones from classrooms is out of touch, say UK school leaders]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/aug/16/plan-to-ban-phones-from-classrooms-is-out-of-touch-say-uk-school-leaders</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2021/aug/16/plan-to-ban-phones-from-classrooms-is-out-of-touch-say-uk-school-leaders"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T13:51:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Schools already have pupils’ mobile phone use under control, say leaders in response to government plans
School and college leaders have condemned the government’s plan to ban mobile phones from classrooms as outdated and out of touch, arguing that schools should be allowed to decide on appropriate rules.
Responding to a Department for Education (DfE) consultation on student behaviour, the Association of School and College Leaders said education leaders already had student mobile phone use under control and warned that some students, such as those caring for a relative, may be disadvantaged by a strict approach.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Addo awash in raw sewage for months]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/addo-awash-raw-sewage-months/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/addo-awash-raw-sewage-months/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T12:01:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Municipality says it must upgrade sewer pump station to a water treatment works]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GroundUp journalists win Nat Nakasa award for lottery reporting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/groundup-journalists-win-nat-nakasa-award-lottery-reporting/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/groundup-journalists-win-nat-nakasa-award-lottery-reporting/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T10:15:19.000Z</updated>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phoenix “vigilante killings”: dozens march to police station demanding judicial inquiry]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/dozens-march-phoenix-police-station-demanding-judicial-inquiry/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/dozens-march-phoenix-police-station-demanding-judicial-inquiry/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-16T08:40:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“I saw so much hate in people’s eyes as they beat me up”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘They should be worried’: will Lina Khan take down big tech?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/aug/14/lina-khan-big-tech-ftc-antitrust</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/aug/14/lina-khan-big-tech-ftc-antitrust"/>
        <updated>2021-08-15T16:07:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Within weeks of Khan’s appointment as FTC chair, Facebook and Amazon asked that she be recused from antitrust investigations
Lina Khan has some of the biggest companies in the world shaking in their boots.
The 32-year-old antitrust scholar and law professor in June became the youngest person in history and the most progressive in more than a decade to be appointed as chair of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game (voice)over: actors turn to video game work during pandemic]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/15/actors-turn-to-video-game-work-during-pandemic</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/15/actors-turn-to-video-game-work-during-pandemic"/>
        <updated>2021-08-15T13:25:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Demand for voice actors increases, providing relief for workers whose other sources of income has dried up

Coronavirus – latest updates
See all our coronavirus coverage

It was not only audiences that turned to video games during the pandemic. With theatres closed, and TV and film production on hiatus, British actors chose work they could do from isolation – and the booming gaming industry was ready to fill the gap.
“The minute the pandemic hit, it was just everyone asking me: ‘What mic should I get? How do you set up a home studio?’” says Cassie Layton, an actor and musician from south-west London. “I was lucky in that I had worked doing voice acting for a few years before the pandemic hit. But every single actor, I think, either had the thought or took the action to set up a home studio.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Mass Effect is some of the best sci-fi ever made]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/14/why-mass-effect-is-some-of-the-best-sci-fi-ever-made</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/14/why-mass-effect-is-some-of-the-best-sci-fi-ever-made"/>
        <updated>2021-08-14T10:00:37.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[By turns as cerebral as Star Trek, as hopeful as Asimov and as dramatic as Battlestar Galactica, the video game series deserves a place among the sci-fi greats
Our species will one day end. Whether it’s down to our own hubris, the disastrous effects of unbridled wealth accumulation and social division, war, the climate crisis, plague, a space rock or perhaps unfriendly aliens – we’ll one day be dust caught in cosmic winds, lost to an indifferent universe. On our pale blue dot, the remnants of once-great civilisations and vanished peoples that we unearth already show us that advanced development is no guarantee of perpetuity.
In sci-fi, humanity’s naive yearning to fight on despite this realisation often proves a point of curiosity – and sometimes inspiration – for alien species. This is front and centre of the Mass Effect trilogy of video games, in which our imminent annihilation is given form in the tendrils of creatures called Reapers: ancient, building-sized, alien-robot hybrids that wipe out most life in the Milky Way every 50,000 years.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tauriq Moosa</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Groupon customers could be due cash refunds after UK watchdog warning]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/14/groupon-customers-could-be-due-cash-refunds-after-uk-watchdog-warning</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/14/groupon-customers-could-be-due-cash-refunds-after-uk-watchdog-warning"/>
        <updated>2021-08-14T06:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[CMA says sometimes only credits were offered, and it wants swift change or court action could follow
Customers of the deals website Groupon who were told by the firm they had to accept a credit note could be due cash refunds after the UK’s competition watchdog ordered the company to improve the way it treats users or face legal action.
The Competition and Markets Authority (CMA) said this week it had found evidence that Groupon does not always provide customers with refunds or replacement items when there is a problem with an order. Shoppers have sometimes only been offered Groupon “credits”, potentially breaking consumer law, it says.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miles Brignall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Asunción Virtual Maker Faire Is This Weekend!]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/13/asuncion-virtual-maker-faire-is-this-weekend/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/13/asuncion-virtual-maker-faire-is-this-weekend/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T17:27:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Faire Asuncion is here! join up virtually and enjoy
The post Asunción Virtual Maker Faire Is This Weekend! appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘White hat’ hacker behind $610m crypto heist returns most of money]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/13/white-hat-hacker-behind-610m-crypto-heist-returns-most-of-money</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/13/white-hat-hacker-behind-610m-crypto-heist-returns-most-of-money"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T15:16:59.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Still-unidentified hacker claims attack was carried out ‘for fun’ to ‘expose the vulnerability’ of platform
The hacker responsible for one of the world’s largest digital coin heists has returned nearly all of their more than $610m (£440m) haul, reportedly saying they did it “for fun” and to expose a vulnerability.
The victim, Poly Network, which until Tuesday’s heist was a little known peer-to-peer cryptocurrency platform, said all of the funds except for $33m-worth of the digital coin Tether, which were frozen earlier in the week, had been transferred to a wallet controlled by both the platform and the hacker.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Bryant and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[University Makerspaces 1: Generating Student Buy-in]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/13/university-makerspaces-1-generating-student-buy-in/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/13/university-makerspaces-1-generating-student-buy-in/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Part 1 of a series on growing and running university based makerspaces
The post University Makerspaces 1: Generating Student Buy-in appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[UK security chiefs issue guidance to ministers over hackers on WhatsApp]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/13/uk-security-chiefs-issue-guidance-after-hackers-target-ministers-on-whatsapp</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/13/uk-security-chiefs-issue-guidance-after-hackers-target-ministers-on-whatsapp"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T14:01:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exclusive: civil service chief points to work to improve cybersecurity in response to Labour concerns 
Ministers and civil servants conducting “government by WhatsApp” have been at risk of being targeted by hackers, leading to new advice from security chiefs about how to improve their privacy.
The cabinet secretary, Simon Case, revealed that the Government Security Group had issued fresh guidance across government in a letter to Labour, which had raised questions about ministers using their personal phones to conduct official business.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rowena Mason Deputy political editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 15 greatest video games of the 00s – ranked!]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/13/the-15-greatest-video-games-of-the-00s-ranked</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/13/the-15-greatest-video-games-of-the-00s-ranked"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T08:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The decade that began with the GameCube, PlayStation 2 and Xbox, and ended with the Wii, PlayStation 3 and Xbox 360, saw huge technical advances and remarkable innovations in storytelling and gameplay  – these are the standout games of the noughties
(Valve, 2008)
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald and Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[OnePlus Nord 2 review: near top performance at a mid-range price]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/13/oneplus-nord-2-review-near-top-performance-at-a-mid-range-price</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/13/oneplus-nord-2-review-near-top-performance-at-a-mid-range-price"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T06:00:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New Android phone offers most of what makes the best phones great, but is half the price at £399
The Nord 2 is the latest mid-range smartphone from OnePlus that offers near top-level performance but at half the price of its flagship devices.
Priced from £399, it sits below the £629 OnePlus 9 and £829 9 Pro and follows on from the successful first Nord.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to photograph the moon on your phone or camera, and the best settings to use]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/13/how-to-photograph-the-full-blue-moon-with-phone-tips-seasonal-sturgeon-green-corn-barley-fruit-grain-moon-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings-night-sky</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/13/how-to-photograph-the-full-blue-moon-with-phone-tips-seasonal-sturgeon-green-corn-barley-fruit-grain-moon-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings-night-sky"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T01:54:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Australia picture editor Carly Earl explains the dos and don’ts of taking pictures of the moon
When a full moon rises, many people will pull out their mobile phones to try and get an Instagram-worthy photograph, but unfortunately the moon is really challenging to get a great photo of.
Two reasons: it is very far away and unless you have a telephoto lens (which makes the moon appear closer than it is) it will always appear as a very small glowing dot in the frame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carly Earl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making Customizable Tool Rolls]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/12/making-customizable-tool-rolls/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/12/making-customizable-tool-rolls/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-13T00:13:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Parker Thomas had an idea for a bag that he turned into a handmade prototype. He launched one Kickstarter, then another to create version one, and then two of the product. He had to figure out how to make it first in Oakland, near where he lives and then in Vietnam. Throughout this process, he […]
The post Making Customizable Tool Rolls appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Guide To The Best Fertilizers For Vegetable Gardens]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=35532</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/best-vegetable-garden-fertilizers/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-12T17:21:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Choosing the best fertilizer for your vegetable garden is easy with this detailed guide. Below I will break it all down for you to make it simple to figure out what type of vegetable fertilizer to use. Then I’ll give you a list with tons of options so you can find what will work forContinue Reading
The post Guide To The Best Fertilizers For Vegetable Gardens appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Miguel Angel Espinola Lopez]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/12/maker-spotlight-miguel-angel-espinola-lopez/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/12/maker-spotlight-miguel-angel-espinola-lopez/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-12T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First and last name Miguel Ángel Espinola López Where are you located?  Paraguay What is your day job?  art with recycled materials Do you attend a makerspace/fablab/hackerspace?  Yes, Nano Guaraní Instagram | Facebook What kinds of stuff do you make?  art with recycled materials How did you get started making stuff?  As a kid I […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Miguel Angel Espinola Lopez appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Make Perfect Copies of Objects By Casting Them In Resin]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/11/how-to-make-perfect-copies-of-objects-by-casting-them-in-resin/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/11/how-to-make-perfect-copies-of-objects-by-casting-them-in-resin/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Learn tips and tricks to making resin duplicates of items. 
The post How To Make Perfect Copies of Objects By Casting Them In Resin appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung launches first water-resistant folding phone and Google watch]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/11/samsung-launches-first-water-resistant-folding-phone-and-google-watch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/11/samsung-launches-first-water-resistant-folding-phone-and-google-watch"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T14:00:05.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[New flip phones and phone-tablet hybrids, plus updated earbuds and first Google Wear OS 3 smartwatch
Samsung is taking a big step towards making folding-screen smartphones mainstream with the launch of a pair of the first water-resistant models as part of its big tech event for the second half of 2021.
The new and improved Galaxy Z Flip3 folding-screen flip-phone and Z Fold3 folding phone-tablet hybrid were announced on Wednesday during a livestreamed event, alongside a Google watch co-developed in an attempt to take on the dominant Apple Watch – the Galaxy Watch4.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don’t put on a happy face! Are you using the smiley emoji all wrong?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/11/dont-put-on-a-happy-face-are-you-using-the-smiley-emoji-all-wrong</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/11/dont-put-on-a-happy-face-are-you-using-the-smiley-emoji-all-wrong"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T13:25:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The classic grinning emoji has once more changed its meaning – at least amongst gen Zers. So what is it communicating now – and what should you be using instead?


Name: The smiley face emoji.
Appearance: A bland, benign smile on a yellow background.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Technology | The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Making AI Accessible for Young Learners]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/11/making-ai-accessible-for-young-learners/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/11/making-ai-accessible-for-young-learners/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T13:23:20.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There’s so much opportunity for students to learn AI —  and it doesn’t have to be hard. Learning AI sounds daunting and until recently, it’s been challenging for students to find enough guidance and support to build AI projects. There are great resources to help students learn coding languages, but how do students go from […]
The post Making AI Accessible for Young Learners appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[I’m Your Man review – Dan Stevens is the perfect date in android romance]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/aug/11/im-your-man-review-android-romance-dan-stevens</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/aug/11/im-your-man-review-android-romance-dan-stevens"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T13:00:04.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Near-future tale of a woman who accepts a male ‘companion’ robot played by  Stevens is laboriously told and not really funny enough
Directed by Maria Schrader, this was a crowd-pleasing favourite at the Berlin film festival earlier this year and its star, Maren Eggert, won the festival’s new gender-neutral best leading performance prize. But I was disappointed with a film whose crises and dilemmas seem laborious and essentially predictable; it does not fully work as sci-fi or satire or comedy.
We are in a world of the near-future (and the city of Berlin itself is certainly very plausible as its location). Eggert plays Alma, an archaeologist with an unhappy and frustrating personal life. She is persuaded by her boss to be a guinea-pig for a new hi-tech scheme: she will road-test a male “companion” robot, programmed to be infinitely considerate and obliging, which will attend to all her emotional and indeed physical needs. So Alma sceptically takes home this dashing humanoid geisha: Tom, played with elegant, fluent German by Dan Stevens. And after a rocky, angry start, after duly dismissing this soulless adventure in existential convenience, Alma inevitably comes to think that there could be something to it. In rejecting Tom, is she simply preferring the headache to the aspirin?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Techies think we’re on the cusp of a virtual world called ‘the metaverse’. I’m skeptical | Sean Monahan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/aug/10/techies-think-were-on-the-cusp-of-a-virtual-world-called-the-metaverse-im-skeptical</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/aug/10/techies-think-were-on-the-cusp-of-a-virtual-world-called-the-metaverse-im-skeptical"/>
        <updated>2021-08-11T10:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Silicon Valley has been anticipating virtual reality for more than three decades, and keeps running into the same problem: people mostly like actual reality
Maybe this will be my Paul Krugman moment. The Nobel Prize-winning economist and New York Times columnist was famously the winner of a study to establish which op-ed commentator was most consistently correct. In 1998, he also famously claimed, “By 2005 or so, it will become clear that the Internet’s impact on the economy has been no greater than the fax machine’s.” I am not nearly so storied in accomplishments as Krugman. But I do make my living offering predictions and forecasts. So I might as well say it: I predict that the metaverse won’t happen.
The “metaverse,” for those who don’t know, is a still-mostly-hypothetical virtual world accessed by special virtual reality (VR) and augmented reality (AR) technology. The idea is to create a sort of next-level Internet overlaid on our physical world. People plugged into the metaverse exist in our physical world like everyone else but can see and interact with things that others can’t. Think The Matrix or the Star Trek Holodeck or the Fortnite-esque brandscapes of Ready Player One.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sean Monahan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Call for Makers: Show Your Project at Maker Faire Shenzhen 2021 Virtually]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/10/call-for-makers-show-your-project-at-maker-faire-shenzhen-2021-virtually/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/10/call-for-makers-show-your-project-at-maker-faire-shenzhen-2021-virtually/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T22:40:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[submit your project today!
The post Call for Makers: Show Your Project at Maker Faire Shenzhen 2021 Virtually appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[False Goat’s Beard – How To Grow & Care For Astilbe]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=35531</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/astilbe-false-goats-beard-care/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T15:08:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Growing astilbe (aka false goat’s beard) is easy and they don’t require any special care. In this article, I will tell you everything you need to know, including where to plant them, water, sunlight, soil, fertilizer, and much more! With its airy, leafy foliage and striking flowers, astilbes make a colorful addition to shady perennialContinue Reading
The post False Goat’s Beard – How To Grow & Care For Astilbe appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hacking Garbage Trucks to Bring Broadband to Those in Need]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/10/hacking-garbage-trucks-to-bring-broadband-to-those-in-need/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/10/hacking-garbage-trucks-to-bring-broadband-to-those-in-need/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What if cities collected real-time information that got services to the people who need them most? And what if they could do it faster AND cheaper?
The post Hacking Garbage Trucks to Bring Broadband to Those in Need appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No Man’s Sky: five years of metaphysical adventures]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/10/no-mans-sky-five-years-of-meteors-mining-and-metaphysics</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/10/no-mans-sky-five-years-of-meteors-mining-and-metaphysics"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T13:33:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As it celebrates with a teaser of a new update, the strange, metaphysical space exploration has survived a tricky take-off and retained its vital spirit 
As soon as I set foot on my first planet in No Man’s Sky five years ago, dying almost immediately in the boiling atmosphere of an utterly barren, deserted world, I was hooked. Here at last, was a space game for the rest of us, and by the rest of us I mean kids who grew up watching Silent Running and Solaris, and reading the trippy existential sci-fi of Ray Bradbury, Stanisław Lem and Ursula K le Guin. Here was a space game with no space marines, where making a bad decision on a hostile alien planet or in some distant asteroid belt could have deadly ramifications, and where existence among the stars was about toil and patience and long periods of silent travel.
This wasn’t how everyone felt about the game upon its much-hyped launch in 2016. No Man’s Sky was famously revealed at the 2014 Game Awards, a hugely popular showcase for new mega-budget blockbusters, the gaming equivalent of advertising during the Super Bowl. This high-profile introduction, together with some ludicrously ambitious plans from tiny Guildford developer Hello Games, led to wild expectations – a gigantically detailed massively multiplayer space opera, combining elements of Elite Dangerous, Eve Online and Star Citizen into one giant production.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Beats Studio Buds review: Apple’s Android-loving noise-cancelling earbuds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/10/beats-studio-buds-review-apple-android-loving-noise-cancelling-earbuds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/10/beats-studio-buds-review-apple-android-loving-noise-cancelling-earbuds"/>
        <updated>2021-08-10T06:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Buds have good sound, battery life, compact shape without stalks and work with Android or iPhones
The latest Apple Bluetooth earbuds from its Beats brand offer active noise-cancelling and cross-compatibility that goes beyond its competitors – even for Android users.
The Studio Buds cost £129.99 ($149.99 or A$199.95) and are Beats’ smallest earbuds to date, following on from the sport-oriented PowerBeats Pro and budget Beats Flex.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Forgotten City review: sliding into your diems]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/09/the-forgotten-city-review-sliding-into-your-diems</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/aug/09/the-forgotten-city-review-sliding-into-your-diems"/>
        <updated>2021-08-09T11:31:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[PlayStation 4, PlayStation 5, Xbox One, Xbox Series S/X, PC; Modern Storyteller/Dear Villagers
A time-loop murder mystery set in ancient Rome is enlivened by excellent acting, dialogue, and good old-fashioned skulduggery
The genesis of The Forgotten City can be traced back to the day a stranger decided to punch its writer and creator, Nick Pearce, in the face. This unprovoked attack led him, then a tech lawyer, to pen his first short story. From there, he began to put together the tale that would become this game, a thrilling time-loop mystery that was originally created within the world of 2011’s fantasy epic The Elder Scrolls: Skyrim. When the mod was released in 2015, it racked up more than 3m downloads and netting Pearce an Australian Writers’ Guild award.
Six years on, The Forgotten City has been rebuilt, transplanted from Skyrim’s Nordic fantasy setting to ancient Rome, and expanded to a complete, albeit rather concise, game. After waking up on a riverbank in the present, you’re catapulted back 2,000 years to a city cut off from the rest of Roman society. Its 23 residents ostensibly live in harmony: the community exists under the yoke of a curse, The Golden Rule, that means if any one citizen commits a sin, everybody meets a gruesome death. Someone is about to break this rule, and you are tasked with discovering the culprit before everyone pays the price.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Holland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Instagram’s creatives are angry about its move to video]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/08/instagram-artists-leaving-social-media-tiktok-shopping</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/08/instagram-artists-leaving-social-media-tiktok-shopping"/>
        <updated>2021-08-08T12:00:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The social media platform was once a favourite of artists and photographers, but a shift towards TikTok-type videos and shopping could leave them looking for a new home online
In late July, hobbyist photographer and self-proclaimed “sunrise hunter” Sam Binding conducted an experiment. After visiting Somerset Lavender Farm to catch the sun peeking over the purple blossoms, the 40-year-old from Bristol uploaded the results to both Instagram and Twitter. Two days later, he used the apps’ built-in analytics tools to assess the impact of his shots. On Instagram, a total of 5,595 people saw his post – just over half of his 11,000 followers. On Twitter, his post was seen by 5,611 people, despite the fact he has just 333 followers on the site.
This confirmed Binding’s hunch that although most people believe that Instagram is a place to share photos and Twitter is a place to share words, that may no longer be the case. When it launched in 2010, Instagram courted the artistic community, inviting respected designers to be among its initial users and naming its very first filter X-Pro II, after an analogue photo-developing technique. In her 2020 book No Filter: The Inside Story of Instagram, technology reporter Sarah Frier documents how Instagram co-founder Kevin Systrom wanted Instagram to be an outlet for artists (in a high-school essay, Systrom wrote that he liked how photography could “inspire others to look at the world in a new way”).
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amelia Tait</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Look: Carvera Desktop CNC Prototyping Station]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/08/06/first-look-carvera-desktop-cnc-prototyping-station/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/08/06/first-look-carvera-desktop-cnc-prototyping-station/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[this upcoming desktop mill is packed with features. See it in action.
The post First Look: Carvera Desktop CNC Prototyping Station appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Guy review – Ryan Reynolds bounces through fun videogame existential crisis]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/aug/05/free-guy-review-ryan-reynolds-taika-waititi-jodie-comer-video-game</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/aug/05/free-guy-review-ryan-reynolds-taika-waititi-jodie-comer-video-game"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T16:00:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A non-player character evolves into a sentient AI in a cheerfully silly riff on The Truman Show, with Taika Waititi and Jodie Comer
The great big handsome-goofy face of Ryan Reynolds looms out of the screen in this fantasy comedy from screenwriter Matt Lieberman and director Shawn Levy (of the Night at the Museum franchise). It’s an undemanding and cheerfully silly riff on the themes of virtual reality and artificial intelligence, and what the heck we’re all doing in this big old universe of ours: as if someone took The Truman Show or Inception – or even The Lego Movie – and stripped out every serious satirical ambition, replacing it with M&M-coloured spectacle. The result is not something that’s in any way challenging, but Reynolds is so puppyishly eager to please.
Reynolds plays a normal, boring guy whose name is Guy (amusingly, it is never clear if this is his actual given name, as in Guy Crouchback, or the more generic “guy”). He smiles incessantly, wears a bland, short-sleeved blue shirt and goes to work every day as a bank teller in a serenely marvellous-looking modern city, resembling Vancouver. There, he hangs out with his best friend, Buddy – again: generic or given name? – played by Lil Rel Howery, but his bank is always being hit by heists, which he greets with the same imperturbable smileyness. Gradually, Guy realises that he is an NPC, or non-player character, in a video game: a quirk or flaw in the algorithm means that he has hyperevolved into an AI state of free will and agency, able to question what is going on. This astonishes the game’s evil corporate owner Antoine (Taika Waititi), and also the designers Millie (Jodie Comer) and Keys (Joe Keery) whose concept Antoine ripped off. And Millie realises that she will have to enter the game as a player, befriend Guy and enlist his help in getting back their intellectual property – before, of course, falling in love with this clueless pixelated lunk.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Move over, space. Tech billionaires have a new utopian boondoggle: the ‘metaverse’ | Jessa Crispin]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/aug/05/move-over-space-tech-billionaires-have-a-new-utopian-boondoggle-the-metaverse</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/aug/05/move-over-space-tech-billionaires-have-a-new-utopian-boondoggle-the-metaverse"/>
        <updated>2021-08-05T10:22:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Imagine a massive, invisible world that surrounds you but which you cannot see or engage unless you own the correct – expensive – technology
Look at all of our tech billionaires trying to leave the world to evade responsibility for their malevolent influence on it. Anything to avoid being confronted by the workers they exploit or the victims of the ethnic and religious clashes facilitated by their platforms. Jeff Bezos and Richard Branson are flinging themselves into space; Elon Musk is burrowing into the earth; now Mark Zuckerberg is retreating into a virtual “metaverse”.
 Related:  Revealed: the Facebook loophole that lets world leaders deceive and harass their citizens 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessa Crispin</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rabbit’s Foot Fern: How To Grow & Care For “Davallia fejeensis”]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=35123</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/rabbits-foot-fern-plant-care/"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T15:46:22.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rabbit’s foot fern care is easier than you might think. In this complete guide, I’m going to tell you everything you need to know. I’ll give you tons of tips that will help make you successful growing rabbit’s foot fern either indoors or outside. With its delicate, gauzy leaflets and furry brown feet that giveContinue Reading
The post Rabbit’s Foot Fern: How To Grow & Care For “Davallia fejeensis” appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The lost history of the electric car – and what it tells us about the future of transport]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/03/lost-history-electric-car-future-transport</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/03/lost-history-electric-car-future-transport"/>
        <updated>2021-08-03T05:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To every age dogged with pollution, accidents and congestion, the transport solution for the next generation seems obvious – but the same problems keep coming back
In the 1890s, the biggest cities of the western world faced a mounting problem. Horse-drawn vehicles had been in use for thousands of years, and it was hard to imagine life without them. But as the number of such vehicles increased during the 19th century, the drawbacks of using horses in densely populated cities were becoming ever more apparent.
In particular, the accumulation of horse manure on the streets, and the associated stench, were impossible to miss. By the 1890s, about 300,000 horses were working on the streets of London, and more than 150,000 in New York City. Each of these horses produced an average of 10kg of manure a day, plus about a litre of urine. Collecting and removing thousands of tonnes of waste from stables and streets proved increasingly difficult.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Standage</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pegasus spyware found on journalists’ phones, French intelligence confirms]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/aug/02/pegasus-spyware-found-on-journalists-phones-french-intelligence-confirms</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/aug/02/pegasus-spyware-found-on-journalists-phones-french-intelligence-confirms"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T14:16:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Announcement is first time an independent and official authority has corroborated Pegasus project findings
French intelligence investigators have confirmed that Pegasus spyware has been found on the phones of three journalists, including a senior member of staff at the country’s international television station France 24.
It is the first time an independent and official authority has corroborated the findings of an international investigation by the Pegasus project – a consortium of 17 media outlets, including the Guardian. Forbidden Stories, a Paris-based nonprofit media organisation, and Amnesty International initially had access to a leaked list of 50,000 numbers that, it is believed, have been identified as those of people of interest by clients of Israeli firm NSO Group since 2016, and shared access with their media partners.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kim Willsher in Paris</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why right to repair matters – according to a farmer, a medical worker, a computer store owner]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/02/why-right-to-repair-matters-according-to-a-farmer-a-medical-worker-a-computer-store-owner</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/02/why-right-to-repair-matters-according-to-a-farmer-a-medical-worker-a-computer-store-owner"/>
        <updated>2021-08-02T10:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Biden’s recent executive order makes taking action on the strict rules imposed by manufacturers a priority, affecting workers across several industries
A tractor. A refrigerator. A smartphone. A ventilator. They may not seem to have much in common, but in fact they all share increasingly high tech features. And when they break, they need fixing.
Yet, thanks to strict rules imposed by manufacturers, our ability to do so remains extremely limited. Companies frequently withhold the information and tools needed to repair devices from consumers, with some warranties outright banning third parties from tinkering with products.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘It’s feasible to start a war’: how dangerous are ransomware hackers?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/01/crypto-criminals-hack-the-computer-systems-of-governments-firms-even-hospitals</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/01/crypto-criminals-hack-the-computer-systems-of-governments-firms-even-hospitals"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T09:00:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Secretive gangs are hacking the computers of governments, firms, even hospitals, and demanding huge sums. But if we pay these ransoms, are we  creating a ticking time bomb?
They have the sort of names that only teenage boys or aspiring Bond villains would dream up (REvil, Grief, Wizard Spider, Ragnar), they base themselves in countries that do not cooperate with international law enforcement and they don’t care whether they attack a hospital or a multinational corporation. Ransomware gangs are suddenly everywhere, seemingly unstoppable – and very successful.
In June, meat producer JBS, which supplies over a fifth of all the beef in the US, paid a £7.8m ransom to regain access to its computer systems. The same month, the US’s largest national fuel pipeline, Colonial Pipeline, paid £3.1m to ransomware hackers after they locked the company’s systems, causing days of fuel shortages and paralysing the east coast. “It was the hardest decision I’ve made in my 39 years in the energy industry,” said a deflated-looking Colonial CEO Joseph Blount in an evidence session before Congress. In July, hackers attacked software firm Kaseya, demanding £50m. As a result, hundreds of supermarkets had to close in Sweden, because their cash registers didn’t work.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sirin Kale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Big tech’s big week raises fears of ‘Blade Runner future’ of mega-company rule]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/01/big-techs-big-week-blade-runner-future-amazon-google-apple-microsoft</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/aug/01/big-techs-big-week-blade-runner-future-amazon-google-apple-microsoft"/>
        <updated>2021-08-01T07:00:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon, Google, Apple and Microsoft all reported record-breaking profits amid a pandemic bonanza but recent Biden administration moves suggest US tech’s easy ride is over
Big tech provided the world with some startling numbers this week. In the last three months Amazon’s sales have averaged over $1.2bn a day. It took the company less than four seconds to earn the $52,000 the average American makes in a year. Apple is now sitting on nearly $200bn in cash, more than this year’s expected sales of Covid 19 vaccines.
The coronavirus shook the world economy to its core but for the US tech giants it has proven a bonanza of historic proportions.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dominic Rushe in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[SolarWinds: Russian hackers broke into email accounts at US attorney offices]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/31/solarwinds-russian-hackers-email-accounts-top-us-attorney-offices</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/31/solarwinds-russian-hackers-email-accounts-top-us-attorney-offices"/>
        <updated>2021-07-31T15:16:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Department of Justice says 27 prosecutors’ offices breached
All four New York offices may have lost sensitive material

Russian hackers behind the massive SolarWinds cyber-espionage campaign broke into the email accounts of some of the most prominent US federal prosecutors’ offices last year, the Department of Justice has said.
 Related: The US has suffered a massive cyberbreach. It's hard to overstate how bad it is | Bruce Schneier 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Associated Press in New York</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Samsung Galaxy Book Pro 360 review: flexible laptop with beautiful OLED screen]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/30/samsung-galaxy-book-pro-360-review-flexible-laptop-oled-screen</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/30/samsung-galaxy-book-pro-360-review-flexible-laptop-oled-screen"/>
        <updated>2021-07-30T06:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Latest thin, light and adaptable Windows 10 machine looks great, is fast and has a nine-hour battery
Samsung’s latest Galaxy Book Pro is a fast and versatile Windows 10 laptop that has a gorgeous-looking OLED screen.
Available as a standard laptop costing from £1,099 ($999) or one with a screen that folds back on itself called the Galaxy Book Pro 360 for an extra £100 ($200). It is the successor to 2020’s Galaxy Book Flex and follows a similar theme: good 13.3in screen, 360-degree folding hinge and thin metal body available in a distinctive royal blue colour.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How & When To Harvest Sage Fresh From Your Garden]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=18167</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/harvesting-sage/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-27T17:02:18.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting sage fresh from your garden is quick and easy, and there are a few ways you can to it. In this post, I’ll show you exactly when and how to pick, pluck, or snip sage for the biggest and best harvest. It might sound intimidating to new gardeners, but harvesting sage is actually prettyContinue Reading
The post How & When To Harvest Sage Fresh From Your Garden appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[12 Bytes by Jeanette Winterson review – how we got here and where we might go next]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/23/12-bytes-by-jeanette-winterson-review-how-we-got-here-and-where-we-might-go-next</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2021/jul/23/12-bytes-by-jeanette-winterson-review-how-we-got-here-and-where-we-might-go-next"/>
        <updated>2021-07-23T08:00:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Twelve essays drawing on years of research into artificial intelligence ask challenging questions about humanity, art, religion and the way we live and love
In Mary Shelley’s 1818 novel Frankenstein, a scientist creates life and is horrified by what he has done. Two centuries on, synthetic life, albeit in a far simpler form, has been created in a dish. What Shelley imagined has only now become possible. But as Jeanette Winterson points out in this essay collection, the achievements of science and technology always start out as fiction. Not everything that can be imagined can be realised, but nothing can be realised if it hasn’t been imagined first.
Take artificial intelligence. For now AI is a tool that we train to address specific tasks such as predicting the next Covid wave, but plenty of people have imagined that it could be something categorically different: a multitasking problem-solver whose capacity to understand and learn is equal or superior to ours. Many labs are working on this concept, which is called artificial general intelligence (AGI), and it could be a reality within decades. That’s how far imagination in technology has brought us. What can the artistic imagination add?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Laura Spinney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech firm hit by giant ransomware hack gets key to unlock victims’ data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/ransomware-attack-kaseya-key-hacking</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/22/ransomware-attack-kaseya-key-hacking"/>
        <updated>2021-07-22T23:47:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kaseya’s universal key can free the files of hundreds of organizations, ending the worst of the attack’s fallout
The software company at the center of a huge ransomware attack this month has obtained a universal key to unlock files of the hundreds of businesses and public organizations crippled by the hack.
Nineteen days after the initial attack over the Fourth of July weekend, the Florida-based IT management provider, Kaseya, has received the universal key that can unlock the scrambled data of all the attack’s victims, bringing the worst of the fallout to a close.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Briton arrested over high-profile Twitter account hacks]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/21/briton-arrested-over-high-profile-twitter-account-hacks</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/21/briton-arrested-over-high-profile-twitter-account-hacks"/>
        <updated>2021-07-21T18:21:16.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[22-year-old faces multiple charges in connection with attacks on accounts of politicians and celebrities
A 22-year-old British citizen has been arrested in Spain in connection with a July 2020 Twitter hack that compromised the accounts of high-profile politicians and celebrities, the US Justice Department said on Wednesday.
It named the British man as Joseph James O’Connor and said he faced multiple charges. He was also accused in a criminal complaint of computer intrusions related to takeovers of TikTok and Snapchat accounts, including one incident involving sextortion, as well as cyberstalking a 16-year-old juvenile.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters in Washington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[African Milk Tree:  How To Grow & Care For A Euphorbia trigona Plant]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=35122</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/african-milk-tree-plant-care/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-20T18:29:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[African milk trees are beautiful and surprisingly easy to grow and care for. In this post, I’m going to tell you everything you need to know about Euphorbia trigona plant care, and give you tons of tips for keeping yours happy and healthy. Whether you’re into indoor plants, or looking for a stellar addition toContinue Reading
The post African Milk Tree:  How To Grow & Care For A Euphorbia trigona Plant appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>