<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>urn:2021-07-16T00:33:58.279Z</id>
    <title>osmos::feed</title>
    <updated>2021-07-16T00:33:58.279Z</updated>
    <generator>osmosfeed 1.11.0</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="index.html"/>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Google Maps suggests ‘potentially fatal’ routes up Ben Nevis, say mountain charities]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/16/google-maps-suggests-potentially-fatal-routes-up-ben-nevis-say-mountain-charities</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/16/google-maps-suggests-potentially-fatal-routes-up-ben-nevis-say-mountain-charities"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T23:28:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Organisations in Scotland say they have tried to contact Google about the dangers but received no reply  
Scottish mountaineering charities have criticised Google for suggesting routes up Ben Nevis and other mountains they say are “potentially fatal” and direct people over a cliff.
The John Muir Trust, which looks after the upper reaches of the UK’s highest mountain, said attempts to contact the company over the issue had been met with silence.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Press Association</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overdriving Vacuum Tubes and Releasing the Magic Light Within]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=486707</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/15/overdriving-vacuum-tubes-and-releasing-the-magic-light-within/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T23:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’ve all seen electronic components that have been coaxed into releasing their small amount of Magic Smoke, which of course is what makes the thing work in the first place. …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Maloney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Winner who paid $30m for space flight with Bezos won’t go due to ‘scheduling conflicts’]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/jeff-bezos-space-flight-guest-new-shepard</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/jeff-bezos-space-flight-guest-new-shepard"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T21:31:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anonymous person will be replaced by 18-year-old recent high school graduate on New Shepard spacecraft
The anonymous winner of a ticket to join billionaire Jeff Bezos in space next week will no longer board the New Shepard spacecraft due to “scheduling conflicts”, Bezos’s Blue Origin company announced on Thursday.
The winner, who paid $29.7m to join one of the world’s richest men in space, will instead be replaced by Oliver Daemen, a recent high school graduate. The 18-year-old took a gap year in 2020 to obtain his private pilot’s license and plans to study physics and innovation management at the Netherlands-based University of Utrecht in September.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Maya Yang</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Foam F-35 Learns to Hover]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=486982</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/15/foam-f-35-learns-to-hover/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T20:00:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With cheap RC hardware, powerful motors, and high-capacity battery packs, getting something to fly has never been easier. It also helps that, whether you’re into fixed-wing craft or multirotors, there’s …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Tom Nardi</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make Your iPhone or iPad Faster by Clearing Its Browser Caches]]></title>
        <id>1847301581</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-make-your-iphone-or-ipad-faster-by-clearing-its-1847301581"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If your iPhone or iPad has been running slower than normal, all it might need is a clearing the device’s browser cache for a quick performance boost. Every browser app stores a cache of website data like cookies, saved login info, images, and more. This helps pages load faster the next time you visit, and it lets you…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Hesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Facebook says Iran-based hackers used site to target US military personnel]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/facebook-iran-based-hackers-us-military-personnel</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/facebook-iran-based-hackers-us-military-personnel"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T19:32:58.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[• Social media company takes down 200 accounts
• ‘Hallmarks of a well-resourced and persistent operation’
Facebook said on Thursday it had taken down about 200 accounts run by a group of hackers in Iran as part of a cyber-spying operation that targeted mostly US military personnel and people working at defense and aerospace companies.
The social media company said the group, dubbed “Tortoiseshell” by security experts, used fake online personas to connect with targets, build trust – sometimes over the course of several months – and drive them to other sites, where they were tricked into clicking malicious links that would infect their devices with spying malware.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Stretch the Waistline of Your Pants for a Little Extra Room]]></title>
        <id>1847301129</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-stretch-the-waistline-of-your-pants-for-a-little-1847301129"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After we shared how to unshrink your clothes, we were asked if it was possible with pants—so, naturally, we went to find out. Adjusting your pants’ waistline is especially helpful if you’re someone like me, whose waist tends to sit right in between most factory-grade sizes. Of course, you can work with a tailor to get…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[16 Things Every Beginner Runner Should Know, According to Reddit]]></title>
        <id>1847298471</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/16-things-every-beginner-runner-should-know-according-1847298471"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Running can be as simple as putting one foot in front of the other, but if you do a lot of running you’ll discover things about yourself and your sport that you wouldn’t have guessed at the beginning. Recently a redditor asked for a shortcut to some of that secret knowledge: “Experienced runners: what’s something you…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Replace Your Mindless Scrolling With Something That'll At Least Pay You a Little]]></title>
        <id>1847299965</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/replace-your-mindless-scrolling-with-something-thatll-a-1847299965"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[You can make easy money taking online surveys, but they typically don’t pay more than a few bucks an hour, way less than you’d get with a part-time job paying minimum wage. Still, as a diversion, it pays better than scrolling through Twitter, especially if you’re stuck waiting somewhere like the airport or DMV. 
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[DIY PECS Board Uses Pictures to Communicate]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=486230</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/15/diy-pecs-board-uses-pictures-to-communicate/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[One way of communicating with autistic and non-verbal people is through the use of a Picture Exchange Communication System or PECS board, which they can use to point out what …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kristina Panos</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[18 Movies That Are Basically 'IP Orgies']]></title>
        <id>1847289994</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/18-movies-that-are-basically-ip-orgies-1847289994"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[To our 2021 eyes, the original Space Jam was pretty modest in its ambitions: Reinvent the Looney Tunes and Merrie Melodies characters by teaming them up with fictionalized versions of real NBA stars like Michael Jordan. That, of course, was before Warner Brothers owned about 33% of everything  ever conceived of by…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ross Johnson</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get The Most Out of Your Vacuum Cleaner With These Tricks]]></title>
        <id>1837217175</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/get-the-most-out-of-your-vacuum-cleaner-with-these-tric-1837217175"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Vacuums suck! Or rather, problems arise when they stop sucking.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Joel Kahn</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The person to ‘weaken’ America: what the Kremlin papers said about Trump]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/15/the-person-to-weaken-america-what-the-kremlin-papers-said-about-trump</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/15/the-person-to-weaken-america-what-the-kremlin-papers-said-about-trump"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T17:05:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Documents appear to show how Russian intelligence worked to install their preferred candidate as president
Papers appear to show Putin’s plot to put Trump in White House
In January 2016, America was coming to terms with what had previously seemed incredible. Barring an unforeseen event, Donald J Trump was on course to become the Republican party’s presidential candidate. Some welcomed this giddy prospect, while others in the Republican establishment recoiled in horror.
The man himself oozed confidence. “I have a feeling it’s going to work out, actually,” he told his rival Ted Cruz, at a Fox News debate. By 22 January, the polls had Trump well ahead, as a snowstorm nudged towards Washington.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Luke Harding and Dan Sabbagh</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Should Air Fry Some Salmon]]></title>
        <id>1847299642</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/you-should-air-fry-some-salmon-1847299642"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Coming from a catfish-eating family, I never had much use for salmon until I moved to the Pacific Northwest. The two fishes couldn’t be more different in texture, flavor, or styles of preparation, but finally, at nearly 35 years of age, I figured out my favorite way to make salmon, and it involves the air fryer.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Recycling Will Be Key To The Electric Vehicle Future]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=485040</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/15/recycling-will-be-key-to-the-electric-vehicle-future/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Electric vehicles have become a mainstay in the global automotive marketplace, taking on their gasoline rivals and steadily chewing out their own slice of market share, year after year. Government …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Lewin Day</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Cut Tile Without a Wet Saw]]></title>
        <id>1847298509</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-cut-tile-without-a-wet-saw-1847298509"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A small tile project like a backsplash can be a DIY project—as long as you have the right tools. However, tiling jobs—including that backsplash project—often call for a wet saw to accurately (and safely) cut the tile. A wet saw provides a steady stream of water over the blade to create smooth cuts and reduce the level…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Video Series: Learning Antenna Basics with Karen Rucker]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=486117</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/15/new-video-series-learning-antenna-basics-with-karen-rucker/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T16:01:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We don’t normally embrace the supernatural here at Hackaday, but when the topic turns to the radio frequency world, Arthur C. Clarke’s maxim about sufficiently advanced technology being akin to …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Maloney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Throw Away These Recalled Sunscreens That Contain a Carcinogen]]></title>
        <id>1847297801</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/throw-away-these-recalled-sunscreens-that-contain-a-car-1847297801"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Temperatures across the country continue to climb, and people are spending more time outdoors—so naturally, there’s a recall of sunscreen products from pharma giant Johnson & Johnson. Specifically, it’s for five of the company’s aerosol sunscreens from their Neutrogena and Aveeno brands, the Food and Drug…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Elizabeth Yuko</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Features in Firefox 90 Worth Knowing About]]></title>
        <id>1847296742</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-best-features-in-firefox-90-worth-knowing-about-1847296742"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After the design overhaul of Firefox 89, the version 90 update is comparatively timid. But it focuses on two important things—privacy and tracker blocking. If you’re a fan of Firefox and its continued mission of protecting your privacy and automatically blocking trackers, you’ll like this update.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Perfect Clock For Any Hacker’s Ohm]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=486847</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/15/a-perfect-clock-for-any-hackers-ohm/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The vast majority of us are satisfied with a standard, base ten display for representing time. Fewer of us like to be a bit old-fashioned and use a dial with …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Adam Zeloof</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israeli spyware firm linked to fake Black Lives Matter and Amnesty websites – report]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/spyware-company-impersonates-activist-groups-black-lives-matter</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/spyware-company-impersonates-activist-groups-black-lives-matter"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T15:18:23.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers say web domains masquerading as activist, health and media groups are used by governments to hack targets
An Israeli company that sells spyware to governments is linked to fake Black Lives Matter and Amnesty International websites that are used to hack targets, according to a new report.
Researchers from the Citizen Lab at the University of Toronto, who worked with Microsoft, issued a report on Thursday about the potential targets of Candiru, a Tel Aviv-based firm marketing “untraceable” spyware that can infect and monitor computers and phones.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Levin in Los Angeles</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[11 Clever Google Maps Settings Everyone Should Be Using]]></title>
        <id>1847297662</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/11-clever-google-maps-settings-everyone-should-be-using-1847297662"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Every time you head out to a new location, there’s a good chance you instinctively pull up Google Maps to help guide you there—there’s no better tool out there for navigation and traffic updates. But even if you use it practically every day, there’s a good chance that you haven’t made the most of some of its better …
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranay Parab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Save Yourself From 'Dead Butt Syndrome']]></title>
        <id>1847296126</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/save-yourself-from-dead-butt-syndrome-1847296126"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T14:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In the past year, as more people have been working from home, physical therapists have been seeing an increase in patients with “dead butt syndrome,” or DBS for short, which is pain, numbness, and tingling in the butt, which can often extend to the lower back and legs. If you’ve ever stood up after sitting for a while…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Fairbank</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Black Starts: How the Grid Gets Restarted]]></title>
        <id>https://hackaday.com/?p=484504</id>
        <link href="https://hackaday.com/2021/07/15/black-starts-how-the-grid-gets-restarted/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T14:01:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gripped as we are at the time of this writing by a historic heatwave, it’s hard for those of us in the western United States to picture a time when …read more]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Dan Maloney</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Those Email Confidentiality 'Disclaimers' Really Mean Anything?]]></title>
        <id>1847294009</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/do-those-email-confidentiality-disclaimers-really-mean-1847294009"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T14:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’ve ever received an email from your bank, accountant, lawyer, or doctor (or any number of other professionals), you’ve also likely seen a disclaimer at the bottom of the message regarding confidentiality. It may have read something like this:
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Emily Long</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Should Negotiate Your Real Estate Agent's Commission in a Hot Market]]></title>
        <id>1847294373</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/why-you-should-negotiate-your-real-estate-agents-commis-1847294373"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T13:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With the real estate market superheated right now, some homes are selling within days, with cash offers well over the asking price. What that means, though—if you’re looking to sell and you think your house will sell quickly—is that you have a better chance negotiating a lower commission with your real estate agent.…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You've Probably Been Pitting Peaches Wrong This Whole Time]]></title>
        <id>1847295033</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/youve-probably-been-pitting-peaches-wrong-this-whole-ti-1847295033"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T13:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[I love peaches—I could eat a peach for hours!—but I do not love removing the stubborn, literally clinging stone from the center of the fruit. Fortunately, I follow some very smart people on social media, and those people often have solutions to everyday annoyances such as these. (I honestly hate to be all “You’ve been…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aladdin Bahrani obituary]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/aladdin-bahrani-obituary</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/aladdin-bahrani-obituary"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T10:57:03.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[My father, Aladdin Bahrani, who has died aged 91, spent many years working as a senior engineer in his birthplace, Iraq, before becoming professor of manufacturing engineering at Queen’s University in Belfast, where he had trained just after the second world war.
The eldest of 10 children, he was born in Baghdad, to Mohammed Saleem Bahrani, a landowner and farmer, and Bahija Abdul Hussan Al Shamma, a housewife. Once he had finished his schooling at Baghdad College, he left Iraq on a government scholarship to study engineering at Queen’s University from 1948 to 1953, graduating with a science master’s and meeting a young Belfast woman, Margaret Sawrey, who became his wife in 1952.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Linda McClelland</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brakpan community members protect immigrant-owned spaza shops]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/community-members-protect-immigrant-owned-spaza-shops-brakpan/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/community-members-protect-immigrant-owned-spaza-shops-brakpan/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T10:29:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[What will our children eat if this looting does not stop? asks resident]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Durban volunteers and workers clean up en masse]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/durban-volunteers-take-back-their-community-mass-clean-ups/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/durban-volunteers-take-back-their-community-mass-clean-ups/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T09:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“People are here knowing there is nothing to gain personally. They are doing it for the Umlazi community”]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Transport department to shut down “problematic” ranks and routes if taxi violence continues]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/transport-department-to-shutdown-problematic-ranks-and-routes-should-taxi-violence-continue/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/transport-department-to-shutdown-problematic-ranks-and-routes-should-taxi-violence-continue/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T09:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[More people killed and several others injured this week in ongoing feud over taxi routes]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Garbage collection resumes in Khayelitsha after weeks of rubbish piling up]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/city-resumes-garbage-collection-khayelitsha-after-weeks-rubbish-piling/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/city-resumes-garbage-collection-khayelitsha-after-weeks-rubbish-piling/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T08:57:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A tender appeal interrupted garbage collection for over two weeks]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Declaring a State of Emergency explained]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/declaring-state-emergency-explained/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/declaring-state-emergency-explained/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T08:27:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some people have been calling for a State of Emergency to be declared because of civil unrest in the country]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sony WF-1000XM4 review: the best-sounding noise-cancelling earbuds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/sony-wf-1000xm4-review-the-best-sounding-noise-cancelling-earbuds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/15/sony-wf-1000xm4-review-the-best-sounding-noise-cancelling-earbuds"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T06:00:34.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Comfortable and long lasting with good case and brilliant audio but ultimately disposable
Sony’s latest top-of-the-range noise-cancelling earbuds are a cut above the previous generation and the competition.
Costing £250 ($279.99/A$449.99), the WF-1000XM4 are premium true wireless earbuds that go toe to toe with the likes of the Apple AirPods Pro, Jabra Elite 85t and Samsung Galaxy Buds Pro.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[No cults, no politics, no ghouls: how China censors the video game world]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jul/15/china-video-game-censorship-tencent-netease-blizzard</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/news/2021/jul/15/china-video-game-censorship-tencent-netease-blizzard"/>
        <updated>2021-07-15T05:00:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[China’s video game market is the world’s biggest. International developers want in on it – but its rules on what is acceptable are growing increasingly harsh. Is it worth the compromise?
In the years after it was founded in 1999, the Swedish video game company Paradox Interactive quietly built a reputation for developing some of the best, and most hardcore, strategy games on the market. “Deep, endless, complex, unyielding games,” is how Shams Jorjani, the company’s chief business development officer, describes Paradox’s offerings. Most of its biggest hits, such as the middle ages-themed Crusader Kings, or Sengoku, in which you play as a 16th-century Japanese noble, were loosely based on history.
But in 2016, Paradox decided to try something a little different. Its new game, Stellaris, was a work of sprawling science fiction, set 200 years in the future. In this virtual universe, players could explore richly detailed galaxies, command their own fusion-powered starship fleets and fight with extraterrestrials to expand their space empires. Gamers could choose to play as the human race, or one of many alien species. (My personal favourite dresses in a lavish golden cape and has a head like an otter’s, with soft reddish-brown fur, dark eyes and a black snout. Another type of alien is a sentient crystal that eats rocks.)
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Oliver Holmes</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Finally Fix Your Drifting Nintendo Joy-Con on Your Own]]></title>
        <id>1847293340</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-finally-fix-your-drifting-nintendo-joy-con-on-yo-1847293340"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T20:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After years of annoying Joy-Con drift issues plaguing Nintendo Switch consoles, there may finally be a permanent fix.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Brendan Hesse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Sheet Mulch Your Lawn Without Digging Up Your Grass]]></title>
        <id>1847293115</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-sheet-mulch-your-lawn-without-digging-up-your-gr-1847293115"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T20:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Switching up your yard usually means ripping up the grass, tilling, and fertilizing the soil to prep for new vegetation, but why not just cover it up? Sheet mulching uses a simple form of composting to repurpose your lawn by revitalizing the soil and building nutrients for new plants. Using cardboard, green compost,…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Aisha Jordan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hip Dips Are the Latest Body Insecurity (and You Can't Fill Them In)]]></title>
        <id>1847290054</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/hip-dips-are-the-latest-bullshit-body-insecurity-and-y-1847290054"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T19:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this article, I will not tell you how to get rid of your hip dips. However, if you are here because you want to get rid of your hip dips, this is essential reading. Because hip dips, as a bodily flaw, are 100% bullshit.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Beth Skwarecki</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Try "Slow Dating" If You're Sick of Puddle-Deep Partners]]></title>
        <id>1847291231</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/try-slow-dating-if-youre-sick-of-puddle-deep-partners-1847291231"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T19:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you’re accustomed to swiping through a sea of profiles on Tinder, Hinge, Bumble, or any of the major dating apps, the process of searching for a decent match can be exhausting. But while an app’s instant affirmation might be encouraging, it might be better to slow things down once you do meet someone you like.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sam Blum</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where to Get Free Ice Cream for National Ice Cream Day]]></title>
        <id>1847291823</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/where-to-get-free-ice-cream-for-national-ice-cream-day-1847291823"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T18:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Any excuse to eat ice cream is as good as any other, so why not take advantage of National Ice Cream Day this Sunday, July 18? Here’s a look at who’s offering discounts or free ice cream this weekend.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Mike Winters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[9 of the Best Podcasts Every Dad Should Listen To]]></title>
        <id>1847283825</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/9-of-the-best-podcasts-that-every-dad-should-listen-to-1847283825"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T18:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dads are catching up to moms in their hunger for advice on being successful in both the workplace and within their family roles. And with a wide variety of podcasts more readily available these days, fathers (or dads-to-be) have plenty of options for shows about how to better step up and make the most of fatherhood.
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jason Keil</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Can Make Instagram Less Addicting, If You Want]]></title>
        <id>1847288680</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/you-can-make-instagram-less-addicting-if-you-want-1847288680"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T17:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s not easy to quit Instagram—and you probably don’t even want to completely quit the app. The memes, updates, and reels are important to you, after all. But many of us could do with spending a little less time on Instagram.

Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Reason to Keep Whipped Cream in Your Fridge at All Times (Besides That One, You Pervert)]]></title>
        <id>1847291151</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/the-best-reason-to-keep-whipped-cream-in-your-fridge-at-1847291151"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T17:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Whipping your own cream is not a hard task, but it does require a certain amount of equipment, and that equipment requires washing, which makes whipping cream mildly inconvenient in the middle of the day or after a big dinner—the two moments I happen to crave espresso con panna (espresso topped with whipped cream).
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Claire Lower</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Hide Nudes, Personal Data, and Pictures of Your Ex on an iPhone or iPad]]></title>
        <id>1847288475</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/how-to-hide-nudes-personal-data-and-pictures-of-your-1847288475"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T16:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s possible you have a few photos on your iPhone or iPad that you’d rather not stumble upon—or have anyone else stumble upon, such as a picture of your ex, a troubling memory, or other, uh, unmentionables. If you’re not ready to delete or offload them, but you don’t want them seen by the wrong eyes, you can hide…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Khamosh Pathak</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delete Your Duplicate Google Contacts, Because It's Easier Than You Think]]></title>
        <id>1847288364</id>
        <link href="https://lifehacker.com/delete-your-duplicate-google-contacts-because-its-easi-1847288364"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T16:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not everyone has organized address books, mostly because we end up saving someone’s email address in one contact and their phone number in another. If you recently realized that yours is a mess and preventing you from finding what you need quickly, you can use Google Contacts’ Merge & Fix tool to bring some order to…
Read more...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Pranay Parab</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Food supply to 675,000 people cut off after Durban food bank ransacked]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/food-supply-675000-people-cut-after-durban-food-bank-looted/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/food-supply-675000-people-cut-after-durban-food-bank-looted/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T14:44:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[FoodForward SA closes branches nationwide because of insecurity]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fears that some SASSA beneficiaries will not get paid next month]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/many-stores-and-atms-destroyed-during-looting-kzn-and-gatueng-its-unclear-how-sassa-beneficiaries-will-be-paid-next-month/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/many-stores-and-atms-destroyed-during-looting-kzn-and-gatueng-its-unclear-how-sassa-beneficiaries-will-be-paid-next-month/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T14:38:21.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cash paypoints across the country have been closed due to the unrest]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[27,000 people join project to rebuild after looting]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/27000-people-rush-join-volunteer-group-after-looting/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/27000-people-rush-join-volunteer-group-after-looting/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T13:47:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The RebuildSA Facebook group was created on Tuesday]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“If you loot, you will meet the long arm of the law after we catch you” warn taxi operators]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/if-you-loot-you-will-meet-the-long-arm-of-the-law-after-we-catch-you-warns-taxi-operators/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/if-you-loot-you-will-meet-the-long-arm-of-the-law-after-we-catch-you-warns-taxi-operators/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T13:15:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[A convoy of taxis made its way through several townships in Kariega on Wednesday, urging people to refrain from looting]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Legend of Zelda: Skyward Sword HD review – still a cut above]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/14/the-legend-of-zelda-skyward-sword-hd-review-nintendo-switch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/14/the-legend-of-zelda-skyward-sword-hd-review-nintendo-switch"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T13:00:13.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nintendo Switch; Nintendo
This remastered game from the Wii-era remains a wildly imaginative and magical experience created by Nintendo’s brainiest puzzle architects
In 2011, when Nintendo reforged The Legend of Zelda around the waggling of a Wii remote in Skyward Sword, there was a sense that the developer had lost sight of the wood for the trees; that in focusing so tightly on gyroscopic sword-waving, the game lost some of the series’ adventurous scope. But now that motion controls are widely accepted, or at least less pressed to argue their case, this HD remake seems more comfortable in its own skin. The hand-swinging sword combat benefits from the Switch controllers’ tighter tracking, and new button controls accommodate players who are reluctant to shift from a horizontal couch position.
Motion control detractors may claim that Nintendo is conceding something here, but this is still a Hyrule built around the drama of a directional slash. Slobbering plants can be sliced along horizontal and vertical jawlines, and the glowing seams on robotic totem poles beckon like the “tear here” line on a family bag of sweets. Swinging one hand to cut and jabbing the other to parry with a shield is powerful play-acting, and nudging the control stick can’t help but feel timid by comparison. It left me wistful for the Wii, the pluck of a bow string transporting me back to Wii Sports Resort; a harp-strum dredging up memories of smiling politely through Wii Music recitals. It’s a shame that Nintendo has dialled back on motion controls just as the technology matured.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Matthew Castle</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s artificial intelligence best at? Stealing human ideas]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/14/welcome-to-guardian-techscape-will-ai-make-centaurs-of-us-all</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/14/welcome-to-guardian-techscape-will-ai-make-centaurs-of-us-all"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T10:50:10.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Up for discussion in the first Guardian tech newsletter: can artificial intelligence enhance rather than replace us … internet age verification … plus Google’s €500m French fine
Hello and welcome to the debut issue of TechScape, the Guardian’s newsletter on all things tech, and sometimes things not-tech if they’re interesting enough. I can’t tell you how excited I am to have you here with me, and I hope between us we can build not just a newsletter, but a news community.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Alex Hern</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[“It’s hunger, my sister,” says Brakpan looter]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/stealing-wrong-hungry-people-can-do-anything-says-brakpan-resident/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/stealing-wrong-hungry-people-can-do-anything-says-brakpan-resident/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T09:11:44.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Most Tsakane shops have been gutted]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Zealand Uber drivers launch class action against ride share company]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/14/new-zealand-uber-drivers-launch-class-action-against-ride-share-company</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/14/new-zealand-uber-drivers-launch-class-action-against-ride-share-company"/>
        <updated>2021-07-14T08:16:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Legal fight hopes to override previous ruling that drivers are not employees
New Zealand Uber drivers are taking the global ride-share company to court, in the hopes of being legally determined as employees instead of contractors.
It is the latest in a string of cases taken against the company and other ride-share apps, and the second such case in New Zealand.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Eva Corlett in Wellington</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Prune Basil The Right Way]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34566</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/pruning-basil/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T18:59:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pruning basil is simple, results in a bushier and healthier plant, and will also give you larger yields. In this post I’ll tell you why and when to do it, and then show you step by step exactly how to cut back your basil. The best way to have the maximum production from your basilContinue Reading
The post How To Prune Basil The Right Way appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ransomware gang REvil's websites become unreachable]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/13/ransomware-gang-revils-websites-become-unreachable</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/13/ransomware-gang-revils-websites-become-unreachable"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T17:51:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Outage means victims of Russia-linked cybercrime ring cannot pay ransom and can remain unnamed
Websites run by the ransomware gang REvil suddenly became unreachable on Tuesday.
Ransomware gang websites can be unreliable, and it was unclear whether the site’s disappearance was a momentary fluke or whether the hackers had been taken offline.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Gauteng clinics looted and destroyed]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-clinics-looted-and-destroyed/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/gauteng-clinics-looted-and-destroyed/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T15:12:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[“What was not taken, was broken,” says doctor]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eastern Cape taxi bosses vow to stop looters]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/eastern-cape-citizenry-come-out-against-attempts-stoke-pro-zuma-unrest/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/eastern-cape-citizenry-come-out-against-attempts-stoke-pro-zuma-unrest/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T14:30:35.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gqeberha residents mobilise to protect shopping mall]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tech chiefs called in to No 10 over racist posts to England players]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/13/tech-chiefs-called-in-to-no-10-over-racist-posts-to-black-england-players</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/13/tech-chiefs-called-in-to-no-10-over-racist-posts-to-black-england-players"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T13:58:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Boris Johnson to demand that tech firms do more to tackle online abuse
Boris Johnson has summoned tech companies to Downing Street to order them to do more to tackle online abuse, amid mounting criticism of the government after black England players were deluged with racist posts in the aftermath of their Euro 2020 defeat.
The England footballer Tyrone Mings has criticised the home secretary, Priti Patel, for her condemnation of the racist abuse faced by his teammates, after she called players taking the knee “gesture politics”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Jessica Elgot, Rowena Mason and Nazia Parveen</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[KZN unrest: Old age homes running out of food]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/kzn-unrest-old-age-homes-running-out-food/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/kzn-unrest-old-age-homes-running-out-food/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T13:42:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Facilities for the elderly in Durban are battling with staff shortages and are not getting food deliveries as looting continues]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Refugees frustrated by Home Affairs online renewal system]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/refugees-frustrated-home-affairs-online-renewal-system/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/refugees-frustrated-home-affairs-online-renewal-system/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T11:52:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Officials accused of exploiting asylum seekers’ desperation at the Pretoria refugee centre]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why are companies always experiencing higher-than-normal call volumes?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/13/why-are-companies-always-experiencing-higher-than-normal-call-volumes</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2021/jul/13/why-are-companies-always-experiencing-higher-than-normal-call-volumes"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T11:00:41.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The long-running series in which readers answer other readers’ questions on subjects ranging from trivial flights of fancy to profound scientific and philosophical concepts
Does anyone still believe that any of the companies they call or email are labouring under higher-than-normal call volumes – especially given that that they all seem to have it “higher than normal” all of the time. Does anyone know how long ago the baseline “normal” might have been? Robert Cullen, Härryda, Sweden
Post your answers (and new questions) below or send them to nq@theguardian.com. A selection will be published on Sunday.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Technology | The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shack dwellers under Potsdam Bridge play cat and mouse with City]]></title>
        <id>https://www.groundup.org.za/article/housing-crisis-lead-shacks-being-erected-along-road-and-under-bridge/</id>
        <link href="https://www.groundup.org.za/article/housing-crisis-lead-shacks-being-erected-along-road-and-under-bridge/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T09:25:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Municipality puts in rocks, families remove them]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>GroundUp News</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phil Spencer on the future of Xbox: we still want to take risks with games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/13/phil-spencer-future-of-microsoft-xbox-risks-narrative-games</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/13/phil-spencer-future-of-microsoft-xbox-risks-narrative-games"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T08:30:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[While developing traditional narrative games is harder than it has ever been, Microsoft’s Xbox chief sees an opportunity in using modern platforms and tech to tell new stories
Over the last decade, the concept of “games as a service” has revolutionised the way the interactive entertainment industry works. From the subscriptions introduced by massively multiplayer online adventures such as World of Warcraft to the seasonal battle passes of current online shooters, we’re seeing a huge amount of focus on games that can sustain a lucrative community of players over several years.
But where does that leave more offbeat ideas and concepts that couldn’t support years’ worth of play? Where does it leave the single-player narrative adventure – the blockbusting genre that brought us titles such as Metal Gear Solid, Red Dead Redemption and Mass Effect? It’s a genre Sony has supported through funding the studios that make games such as The Last of Us, Spider-Man and God of War. But Microsoft has focused its efforts on cross-platform, connected games, as symbolised by the mammoth Minecraft industry. Is there still room for traditional forms of narrative games on the Xbox Series X?
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keith Stuart</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to photograph the moon on your phone or camera, and the best settings to use]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/13/how-to-photograph-the-full-moon-with-phone-tips-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings-night-sky-tonight</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/13/how-to-photograph-the-full-moon-with-phone-tips-take-picture-photography-smartphone-camera-dslr-iphone-best-settings-night-sky-tonight"/>
        <updated>2021-07-13T02:58:47.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Guardian Australia picture editor Carly Earl explains the dos and don’ts of taking pictures of the moon and night sky

How to see the conjunction of Venus and Mars tonight in Australia

When a full moon rises, many people will pull out their mobile phones to try and get an Instagram-worthy photograph, but unfortunately the moon is really challenging to get a great photo of.
Two reasons: it is very far away and unless you have a telephoto lens (which makes the moon appear closer than it is) it will always appear as a very small glowing dot in the frame.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Carly Earl</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[To obscurity and beyond: did Richard Branson really make it into space?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/12/to-obscurity-and-beyond-did-richard-branson-really-make-it-into-space</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2021/jul/12/to-obscurity-and-beyond-did-richard-branson-really-make-it-into-space"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T17:26:39.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[After his rocket plane reached 53 miles above Earth on Sunday, the founder of Virgin Galactic is now officially an astronaut. But not everyone’s convinced
Name: Richard Branson.
Age: 70.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Technology | The Guardian</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mint condition Super Mario 64 game sells for record $1.5m]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/12/mint-condition-super-mario-64-game-sold-for-record-1-5m</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/12/mint-condition-super-mario-64-game-sold-for-record-1-5m"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T13:30:25.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sealed cartridge dating from 1996 is described as one of fewer than five copies in such condition
A sealed, mint condition copy of the video game Super Mario 64 has sold at auction for more than $1.5m (£1.1m), making it the most expensive video game ever sold. 
The game cartridge, dating from 1996, was in high demand at US auction house Heritage Auctions for its “historical significance, rarity and condition” since there are “fewer than five copies” in such good condition.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rachel Hall</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What happens at Sun Valley, the secret gathering of unelected billionaire kings? | Hamilton Nolan]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/12/what-happens-at-sun-valley-the-secret-gathering-of-unelected-billionaire-kings</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jul/12/what-happens-at-sun-valley-the-secret-gathering-of-unelected-billionaire-kings"/>
        <updated>2021-07-12T10:16:11.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[We are developing a private class of billionaire kings whose will is omnipotent and untouchable by any democratic force
There comes a moment in every good gangster movie when all of the villains come together in a remote hideaway to make nefarious plans. If the good guys are smart, this is the moment they swoop in and arrest everyone. In real life America, though, we consistently squander these opportunities, opting instead to sit back and gawk at the villains like a bunch of dazed paparazzi. It’s never too late to change that.
 Related: Bernie in Trumpworld: Sanders visits ‘imperative if democracy is to survive’ 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Hamilton Nolan</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Gonna be a trainwreck’: can an Asian diaspora Facebook group be good TV?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/12/gonna-be-a-trainwreck-can-an-asian-diaspora-facebook-group-be-good-tv</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/12/gonna-be-a-trainwreck-can-an-asian-diaspora-facebook-group-be-good-tv"/>
        <updated>2021-07-11T17:30:52.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Subtle Asian Traits series faces the challenge of adapting an internet phenomenon and questions of cultural representation
When the moderators of Subtle Asian Traits announced in June that the Facebook group would be spun into an American TV series, the news was met with a flurry of cynical comments by its members.
The private group, with nearly 2 million members, labels itself as “a community that celebrates the similarities and differences within the subtle traits of Asian culture and sub-cultures”.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Donna Lu</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Cyber-attack’ hits Iran’s transport ministry and railways]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/11/cyber-attack-hits-irans-transport-ministry-and-railways</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2021/jul/11/cyber-attack-hits-irans-transport-ministry-and-railways"/>
        <updated>2021-07-11T00:51:38.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Message boards in train stations show cancellations though rail operator denies disruptions
Websites of Iran’s transport and urbanisation ministry went out of service on Saturday after a “cyber-disruption” in computer systems, the official IRNA news agency reported.
On Friday, Iran’s railways also appeared to come under cyber-attack, with messages about alleged train delays or cancellations posted on display boards at stations across the country. Electronic tracking of trains across Iran reportedly failed.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[‘We expect them to act’: Biden presses Putin on ransomware groups, hints at retaliation]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/10/we-expect-them-to-act-biden-presses-putin-on-ransomware-groups-hints-at-retaliation</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/10/we-expect-them-to-act-biden-presses-putin-on-ransomware-groups-hints-at-retaliation"/>
        <updated>2021-07-10T02:59:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Joe Biden’s hour-long phone call with the Russian leader suggests growing impatience over attacks disrupting US sectors
Joe Biden has increased pressure on Vladimir Putin to move against ransomware groups operating from Russia, warning the United States is prepared to respond if cyberhacks are not stopped.
The two leaders held an hour-long phone call on Friday, their first since they discussed ransomware attacks at a summit in Geneva on 16 June. Biden’s message to Putin in the call was direct, suggesting a growing impatience over attacks that have disrupted key US sectors.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[From Cuphead to Super Meat Boy: 10 of the most fiendishly difficult games]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jul/09/difficult-games-super-meat-boy-spelunky-dark-souls-returnal-cuphead-sekiro</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/culture/2021/jul/09/difficult-games-super-meat-boy-spelunky-dark-souls-returnal-cuphead-sekiro"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T08:00:42.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Roguelike shooters, punishing platformers and brutal, sword-heavy RPGs … not all great games have to be a walk in the park

Modern Toss on twiddling their thumbs

If you want to try and enjoy beautiful 1930s-style animation while being so frustrated that you nearly throw your controller at the wall, Cuphead is your game. It’s a run-and-gun cartoon caper that looks non-threatening but is actually evil. I had nightmares about one of its bosses (the transforming wedding-cake castle), but when I beat it I felt like an actual god.
Consoles, Mac, PC
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Keza MacDonald</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[3D Modeling for Makers]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/08/3d-modeling-for-makers/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/08/3d-modeling-for-makers/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-09T05:52:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lydia Sloan Cline is the author of Fusion 360 for Makers, which is out in a new second edition. She teaches 3D design and fabrication at Johnson County Community College in Overland Park, Kansas, where she began as a drafting professor with a degree in Architecture. In this episode of Make:cast, Patrick DiJusto, Make: Books […]
The post 3D Modeling for Makers appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Female -vs- Male Squash Flowers: How To Tell The Difference]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34781</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/male-vs-female-squash-blossoms/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-08T15:11:33.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Squash plants have both male and female blossoms, and they each play a key role in fruit production. In this post, I’ll talk about the differences between female vs male squash flowers, and show you tons of photos to help you easily and quickly tell them apart. It’s important to be able to tell theContinue Reading
The post Female -vs- Male Squash Flowers: How To Tell The Difference appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spin machines: the curious history of video games on vinyl]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/07/video-games-on-vinyl-flexi-discs-zx-spectrum</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/games/2021/jul/07/video-games-on-vinyl-flexi-discs-zx-spectrum"/>
        <updated>2021-07-07T08:45:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[During the early 80s home computing boom, flexi discs full of data were briefly all the rage, and Frank Sidebottom, the Thompson Twins and the Stranglers made their way to the ZX Spectrum
It’s almost unthinkable now, but from the 1970s until the early 1980s, vinyl records were explored as a means of storing computer data – including video games. Some magazines of the time tucked code-packed flexi disc inserts into their pages: paper-thin plastic records that could be fed into home computers from an ordinary turntable, magically manifesting a game on screen. Long before Travis Scott was attracting 12 million players to a gig hosted in Fortnite, there was a coming together of a British game developer, a magazine and a pop act that marked the beginning of the intersection between the music and games industries.
The Thompson Twins Adventure Game came cover-mounted on a 1984 issue of the beloved magazine Computer & Video Games, the first UK magazine devoted to games. Almost everyone involved in the project – a promotional item linked to the release of the single Doctor Doctor – admits the game was imperfect. It was a weird text adventure garnished with incidental visuals, in which the members of the Thompson Twins had to locate the ingredients of a potion to be made by the song’s eponymous medic. The idea was that readers could load the disc from a turntable linked directly to a Spectrum, or copy the audio on to a cassette, which could then be used to load the game on a Spectrum or Commodore. Getting the recording level right could take multiple attempts, as users experimented with audio settings, and some of the disks got damaged as they dangled exposed on the cover.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Will Freeman</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who’s behind the Kaseya ransomware attack – and why is it so dangerous?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/06/kaseya-ransomware-attack-explained-russia-hackers</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/06/kaseya-ransomware-attack-explained-russia-hackers"/>
        <updated>2021-07-07T05:00:24.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The breach has affected hundreds of businesses around the world, and experts fear the worst is yet to come
Hackers last week infiltrated a Florida-based information technology firm and deployed a ransomware attack, seizing troves of data and demanding $70m in payment for its return.
The hack of the Kaseya firm, which is already being called “the biggest ransomware attack on record”, has affected hundreds of businesses globally, including supermarkets in Sweden and schools in New Zealand.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul in San Francisco</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Republican National Committee denies Russian hackers accessed data]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/06/republican-national-committee-denies-hack-synnex</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/jul/06/republican-national-committee-denies-hack-synnex"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T23:24:07.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Report says RNC computers were breached by Cozy Bear hackers, accused of DNC hack in 2016
The US Republican National Committee has denied that Russian hackers accessed data during a breach of third-party provider last week.
The hackers were part of APT29 or Cozy Bear, according to Bloomberg, citing two unnamed people familiar with the matter. The group is linked with Russia’s foreign intelligence service, the SVR, and was previously accused of hacking the Democratic National Committee in 2016, as well as carrying out the historic cybersecurity breach against SolarWinds, which affected about 100 US companies and nine federal agencies.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Story of Film: A New Generation review – invigorating study of 21st century cinema]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/06/the-story-of-film-a-new-generation-review-invigorating-study-of-21st-century-cinema</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jul/06/the-story-of-film-a-new-generation-review-invigorating-study-of-21st-century-cinema"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T19:27:40.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Critic and film-maker Mark Cousins offers a new instalment in his monumental Story of Film series, examining what digital technology has brought to the table
Critic and documentary film-maker Mark Cousins has returned to Cannes with another episode of his amazingly ambitious cinephile history The Story of Film, an illuminated patchwork clip-quilt, accompanied by his inimitable incantation-voiceover. It’s another example of his unique approach: Cousins is subjective almost to the point of free-associating or even sleep-talking (maybe appropriate for the dream state of the movies) but also colossally well-informed, bracingly internationalist and genuinely educational. I have never yet watched a Cousins film without learning something and being a bit sheepish about what I didn’t know.
That said, Cousins’s style takes some getting used to – almost like a hyper-innocent form of criticism, wide-eyed with wonder at cinema’s brave new world, a Miranda of the movies. Occasionally Cousins’s commentary verges on the superfluous, simply describing what is on screen, although there is almost always a shrewd insight there: he has a great section on a creepy travelling shot in David Robert Mitchell’s psychological horror It Follows.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Pollinate Squash By Hand For Maximum Production]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34564</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/pollinating-squash/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T16:27:55.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pollinating squash by hand is easy, will ensure higher yields, and doesn’t take much time. In this post, I will explain why your baby squash keep falling off, and discuss the processes of hand pollinating the flowers step-by-step. One of the biggest struggles that newbies face when growing vegetables for the first time is havingContinue Reading
The post How To Pollinate Squash By Hand For Maximum Production appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Stefan Hermann of CNC Kitchen]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/06/maker-spotlight-stefan-hermann-of-cnc-kitchen/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/06/maker-spotlight-stefan-hermann-of-cnc-kitchen/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First and last name Stefan Hermann Where are you located?  Germany What is your day job?  Metal Additive Manufacturing Research Engineer Youtube Channel | Patreon What kinds of stuff do you make?  3D Printing Stuff, Material Tests and 3D Printing Research How did you get started making stuff?  Bought a book about Arduino, purchased a […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Stefan Hermann of CNC Kitchen appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ransomware hackers demand $70m after attack on US software firm Kaseya]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/06/kaseya-ransomware-hackers-attack</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/06/kaseya-ransomware-hackers-attack"/>
        <updated>2021-07-06T14:11:06.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Between 800 and 1,500 businesses around the world, including supermarkets and dentists’ offices, affected by attack
Between 800 and 1,500 businesses around the world have been affected by a ransomware attack centered on the US information technology firm Kaseya, its chief executive said on Monday.
 Related: Republicans’ effort to deny the Capitol attack is working – and it’s dangerous 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Reuters</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Venu 2 review: can Garmin make a good smartwatch?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/venu-2-review-can-garmin-make-a-good-smartwatch</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/05/venu-2-review-can-garmin-make-a-good-smartwatch"/>
        <updated>2021-07-05T06:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fitness firm’s new Apple Watch-rival looks the part and tracks loads of data but lacks some real smarts
Garmin’s latest device aims to beat the Apple Watch and rivals at their own game, offering longer battery life and better fitness tracking in a more traditional touchscreen smartwatch body.
The Venu 2 comes in either 40mm or 45mm models, costs from £349.99 ($399.99/A$629) and is compatible with both Android and iPhones connecting via Bluetooth.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[This space race has its downside… Rocketwoman Wally Funk joins crew for Jeff Bezos’s ego trip]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/04/this-space-race-has-its-downside-rocketwoman-wally-funk-joins-crew-for-jeff-bezoss-ego-trip</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/04/this-space-race-has-its-downside-rocketwoman-wally-funk-joins-crew-for-jeff-bezoss-ego-trip"/>
        <updated>2021-07-04T09:00:17.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The veteran US pilot is set to become the oldest woman in space – the only snag is she has to go with the Amazon billionaire 
You have to feel for the American pilot Wally Funk. You would sympathise with anyone with that name, but she has had a particularly mixed week. On one hand, at 82, she is set to finally fulfil her life’s ambition and travel into space. Funk was one of the most promising female candidates for the Mercury 13 programme in the 1960s, but was denied a spot because of her gender. Right stuff, wrong parts. On Thursday, the Amazon founder, Jeff Bezos, announced on Instagram that Wally would become the oldest person in space as one of the four passengers on New Shepard, the rocket being launched by his company Blue Origin on 20 July. “I didn’t think I’d ever get to go up,” Funk said in an interview.
The obvious downside, which she was too polite to mention, is that she has to ride with Bezos, his brother and one other, in a kind of UberPool from hell. She ought to have been more specific to the genie. Midlife does strange things to men, and so does being a billionaire. The combination leads to some odd outcomes. Not content with building his own rockets, Jeff, as he approaches 60, has decided to start riding them as well. Towers and yachts are so passé. Private space travel is the thing. Elon Musk is at it, too, and presumably a load of guys in China.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Ed Cumming</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Biden announces investigation into international ransomware attack]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/kaseya-ransomware-attack-us-sweden</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/kaseya-ransomware-attack-us-sweden"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T21:43:15.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[President addresses hack of Kaseya software that has affected hundreds of US businesses and shut down Swedish shops
Joe Biden said on Saturday he had directed US intelligence agencies to investigate a sophisticated ransomware attack that hit hundreds of American businesses as the Fourth of July holiday weekend began and aroused suspicions of Russian gang involvement.
 Related: Joe Biden cherry-picks audience to promote bipartisan infrastructure deal 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Guardian staff and agencies</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The week in audio: Pieces of Britney; Elon Musk: The Evening Rocket; Human Resources and more]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/03/pieces-of-britney-review-elon-musk-the-evening-rocket-human-resources-the-essay-caribbean-voices-the-kindness-experiment</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/tv-and-radio/2021/jul/03/pieces-of-britney-review-elon-musk-the-evening-rocket-human-resources-the-essay-caribbean-voices-the-kindness-experiment"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T16:00:57.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Radio 4 series on Britney Spears’s troubles and Elon Musk’s space ambitions highlight society’s double standards
Pieces of Britney (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Elon Musk: The Evening Rocket (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Human Resources Broccoli Productions | Spotify
The Essay: Caribbean Voices (Radio 3) | BBC Sounds
The Kindness Experiment (Radio 4) | BBC Sounds
Britney Spears has been in the news a lot over the past few weeks. Her recent court plea to be released from legal conservatorship was horrible and shocking; and also rejected. Judge Brenda Penny ruled last Wednesday that the current situation – where Britney’s father Jamie is a co-conservator, even though he’s ill – should stay in place. Pain, when expressed by a woman, is often disbelieved and ignored.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Miranda Sawyer</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enjoy the restored Night Watch, but don’t ignore the machine behind the Rembrandt]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/commentisfree/2021/jul/03/enjoy-the-restored-night-watch-but-dont-ignore-the-machine-behind-the-rembrandt</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/commentisfree/2021/jul/03/enjoy-the-restored-night-watch-but-dont-ignore-the-machine-behind-the-rembrandt"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T15:00:56.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The computer restoration of this masterpiece illustrates both the benefits and the dangers of AI
In the late 1970s I lived and worked briefly in the Netherlands. Often, on Sundays, I would travel to Amsterdam, go to the morning concert in the Spiegelzaal of the Concertgebouw, and afterwards walk over to the Rijksmuseum, Holland’s national gallery, and spend a couple of hours there. The museum is a wonderful storehouse of Dutch art and there was always much to explore. But on nearly every visit I found myself being drawn back to one of Rembrandt’s most famous pictures – The Night Watch – which I guess is to the Rijksmuseum what the Mona Lisa is to the Louvre.
Its official title is Militia Company of District II under the Command of Captain Frans Banninck Cocq. It came to be called The Night Watch because by the end of the 18th century it had darkened considerably through the accumulation of layers of dirt and varnish, leading to the belief that the painted scene had occurred after dusk.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[What’s next for Jeff Bezos? Space, climate and media may all figure]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/whats-next-for-jeff-bezos-space-climate-and-media-may-all-figure</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/03/whats-next-for-jeff-bezos-space-climate-and-media-may-all-figure"/>
        <updated>2021-07-03T05:00:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[As he hands over top job at Amazon, Bezos will remain largest shareholder and ‘has never had more energy’
A quarter of a century after he founded Amazon in a Seattle garage, Jeff Bezos is preparing to loosen his grip on his $1.7tn (£1.2tn) company. Few employees in the sphere conservatories at Amazon’s sprawling Seattle campus headquarters reckon Bezos will relinquish that much of his iron grip on the company’s big decisions when Andy Jassy succeeds him as CEO on Monday. After all, Bezos will become executive chairman of Amazon’s board and remains the company’s biggest shareholder. But Bezos, 57, told his 1.3 million employees (whom he refers to as “fellow Amazonians”) that “as much as I still tap dance into the office, I’m excited about this transition”.
“I’ve never had more energy, and this isn’t about retiring,” he said. “I intend to focus my energies and attention on new products and early initiatives … I’m super passionate about the impact I think these organisations can have.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Rupert Neate Wealth correspondent</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fire HD 10 Plus (2021) review: Amazon’s top budget tablet upgraded]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/fire-hd-10-plus-2021-review-amazons-top-budget-tablet-upgraded</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jul/02/fire-hd-10-plus-2021-review-amazons-top-budget-tablet-upgraded"/>
        <updated>2021-07-02T06:00:30.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Slimmer, better design, long battery life, 10.1in HD screen and speakers makes for a good TV tablet
Amazon’s top 10in Fire OS tablet has had a makeover and now has faster performance, without costing iPad money.
The 2021 Fire HD 10 comes in either a standard version costing £150/US$150 or a “Plus” version, as tested here, costing £180/US$180, with a few more bells and whistles.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Emotion and Empathy Are Glue for Makers]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/07/01/emotion-and-empathy-are-glue-for-makers/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/07/01/emotion-and-empathy-are-glue-for-makers/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T18:33:51.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In 2020, Dr. Andreea Gorbatai and two co-authors published a research paper in the journal Organization Science titled: “Making Space for Emotions: Empathy, Contagion, and Legitmacy’s Double-Edged Sword.” It’s about the maker movement and what holds it together. It turns out, it’s not skills and tools as much as it is emotions and empathy — […]
The post Emotion and Empathy Are Glue for Makers appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting Brussels Sprouts – Everything You Need To Know]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34562</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/harvesting-brussels-sprouts/"/>
        <updated>2021-07-01T15:38:43.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting brussels sprouts is easier than you might think, and actually kinda fun too! In this post, you’ll learn how to tell when they are ready to pick, plus I’ll show you step by step exactly how to gather them, and even give you tips for using, and storing them for later. Have you everContinue Reading
The post Harvesting Brussels Sprouts – Everything You Need To Know appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting Kohlrabi – Everything You Need To Know]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34560</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/harvesting-kohlrabi/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T18:13:50.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Harvesting kohlrabi may sound intimidating, but it’s actually very easy. In this post, I’ll show how to tell when they are ready, the best way to pick them, and even give you tips for using and storing your garden fresh kohlrabi harvest. Despite how it may sound, the steps for harvesting kohlrabi are actually veryContinue Reading
The post Harvesting Kohlrabi – Everything You Need To Know appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[If You’re Into 3D Printing, You Need To Be Watching CNC Kitchen]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/29/if-youre-into-3d-printing-you-need-to-be-watching-cnc-kitchen/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/29/if-youre-into-3d-printing-you-need-to-be-watching-cnc-kitchen/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-29T15:04:49.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The CNC Kitchen channel, run by Stefan, is a treasure trove of tests and real data surrounding many 3d printing topics
The post If You’re Into 3D Printing, You Need To Be Watching CNC Kitchen appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Making Of ‘Lord of the Rings’ inspired ‘Fellbeast’ Head]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/28/the-making-of-lord-of-the-rings-inspired-fellbeast-head/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/28/the-making-of-lord-of-the-rings-inspired-fellbeast-head/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-28T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Follow along as an artist shares the process of recreating the Fell Beast form the Lord Of The Rings
The post The Making Of ‘Lord of the Rings’ inspired ‘Fellbeast’ Head appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Memo to corporate leaders post-Covid: the disruption to businesses has only just begun | John Naughton]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/memo-to-corporate-leaders-post-covid-the-disruption-to-businesses-has-only-just-begun</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2021/jun/26/memo-to-corporate-leaders-post-covid-the-disruption-to-businesses-has-only-just-begun"/>
        <updated>2021-06-26T15:00:02.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Managerial hierarchies must learn the true lessons of the pandemic if they are to survive and thrive
Pandemics, the historian Yuval Noah Harari has observed, have a way of accelerating history. Just ask the founders of Zoom. Only two years ago, we were all thinking that it would take at least another decade before video-conferencing became an integral part of the way we work in organisations. Then along comes Covid and in three weeks we’re all happily Zooming (or unhappily in the case of Handforth parish council). And now we’re more or less acclimatised or, at any rate, resigned to the idea that remote meetings might be here to stay.
The problem with having had the fast-forward button suddenly propel us into an unexpected place, though, is that we find ourselves unmoored. We start wondering about what lies ahead as the immediate threat of the virus recedes. What will our post-pandemic future be like? In relation to work, three main possibilities are currently taking up all the airtime: continuing to work from home (WFH); a hybrid mode in which we spend some time in the office but also two or three days WFH; and a return to ye olde days commuting to the office to gather round the water cooler and pretend to be doing something useful.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>John Naughton</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Tickets Now For The Make: Education Forum]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/24/get-tickets-now-for-the-make-education-forum/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/24/get-tickets-now-for-the-make-education-forum/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T18:18:26.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The growth of makerspaces in education was interrupted by the shutdown of schools, libraries, and museums over the last year.  Now, as students return to in-person learning, there is an even greater need for maker educators who can provide hands-on making and project-based learning experiences. In addition, making is a practice that can be learned […]
The post Get Tickets Now For The Make: Education Forum appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Amazon crushed the Alabama union drive – can the Teamsters do better?]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/amazon-alabama-union-drive-teamsters</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/24/amazon-alabama-union-drive-teamsters"/>
        <updated>2021-06-24T09:00:53.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Teamsters union is rich, strong, and experienced – and it’s ready to help workers and give Amazon a headache  
The announcement that the Teamsters – one of America’s most powerful unions – is going to mount an ambitious campaign to unionize Amazon warehouses across the US presents the e-retailing colossus with a far bigger threat than the recent effort to unionize an Amazon warehouse in Alabama ever did.
 Related: Amazon fired him – now he’s trying to unionize 5,000 workers in New York 
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Steven Greenhouse</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Announcing The Winners Of Our “May The 4th” Cosplay and Droid Contest]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/23/announcing-the-winners-of-our-may-the-4th-cosplay-and-droid-contest/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/23/announcing-the-winners-of-our-may-the-4th-cosplay-and-droid-contest/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T14:46:29.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[When we announced our Star Wars themed contest, along with NVIDIA, we knew we were going to be in for a difficult time deciding on a winner. There are so many great projects out there with incredible documentation and stunning results! We were not let down by the entries. If you haven’t checked them out […]
The post Announcing The Winners Of Our “May The 4th” Cosplay and Droid Contest appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweat review – the loneliness of the social media influencer]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/23/sweat-review-the-loneliness-of-the-social-media-influencer-magdalena-kolesnik</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/film/2021/jun/23/sweat-review-the-loneliness-of-the-social-media-influencer-magdalena-kolesnik"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T13:00:28.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Magnus von Horn’s contrived Polish drama about a fitness guru promises more in shock and character than it delivers
In theory, it should be possible to create a drama about a social media influencer and motivational fitness celebrity that isn’t all about the hidden loneliness and shame of her shallow existence. It should be possible to show such a person being a huge hit in public and perfectly content in private. But this movie from Poland-based Swedish director Magnus von Horn pretty much goes for route one, and despite some interesting touches, it promises much more in terms of shock and character insight than it ever really delivers, with some contrived and unconvincing plot transitions.
Sylwia (Magdalena Koleśnik) has 600,000 followers for the Instagram account on which she obsessively posts, detailing every aspect of her day as a successful single woman, running colossally popular fitness events with her beefcake male assistant Klaudiusz (Julian Świeżewski). He clearly has a major thing for her, though at one crucial moment he shows a very implausible kind of restraint. She is living in a sleek apartment with her adorable dog, Jackson; there’s a new fitness DVD out and everything seems to be going well.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Peter Bradshaw</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[NFTs and me: meet the people trying to sell their memes for millions]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/23/nfts-and-me-meet-the-people-trying-to-sell-their-memes-for-millions</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/23/nfts-and-me-meet-the-people-trying-to-sell-their-memes-for-millions"/>
        <updated>2021-06-23T05:00:19.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Once, people who owned viral photos made little money from them. Now, the ‘original’ can potentially sell for an enormous sum. But are buyers savvy investors – or unwitting dupes?
The photographer Jeff McCurry’s favourite Harambe memes are the ones where the dead gorilla is in heaven, Photoshopped alongside Diana, Princess of Wales, Tupac and Muhammad Ali. “It’s like: wow,” says McCurry. “What greater spot can you be placed in? Harambe’s at the top of the hill, waiting to meet you there.”
McCurry took the photograph of the 17-year-old western lowland gorilla that went on to become a meme. In it, Harambe kneels, projecting a fearsome aura of strength, nobility and calm. A former volunteer photographer at Cincinnati zoo, McCurry was there on 28 May 2016, the fateful day a three-year-old boy climbed into the gorilla’s enclosure, forcing zookeepers to shoot Harambe dead. “It didn’t seem real at first,” says McCurry, who was a regular visitor to the zoo. “When any of your friends die, it’s hard to process. I was in shock.”
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Sirin Kale</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[17 Top Container Garden Flowers For Stunning Summer Pots]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34374</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/container-flowers/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-22T18:02:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Container gardening flowers are a must for outdoor summer planters. Whether you’re looking to fill hanging baskets, window boxes, small, or a large pots, you’ll find tons of options on this list of the best flowers for container gardening. One of the most fun things to do in the spring is picking out flowers forContinue Reading
The post 17 Top Container Garden Flowers For Stunning Summer Pots appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Open Source Hardware Certifications for May 2021]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/21/open-source-hardware-certifications-for-may-2021/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/21/open-source-hardware-certifications-for-may-2021/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T15:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[In May 2021 the Open Source Hardware Association (OSHWA) certified a wide variety of hardware as open source.  we will have a certified variety collection of Open Source Hardwares, Let’s take a look! (And remember, certification is a free and easy way to show that your hardware complies with the open source hardware definition.) First, […]
The post Open Source Hardware Certifications for May 2021 appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pixel Buds A-Series review: Google’s cheaper but good earbuds]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/21/pixel-buds-a-series-review-google-cheaper-but-good-earbuds"/>
        <updated>2021-06-21T06:00:45.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[AirPods rivals have top sound, battery and translation features but cost significantly less
Google’s latest AirPods competitors, the Pixel Buds A-Series, get a big price cut and a slightly more comfortable design.
The new Bluetooth earbuds take a cue from Google’s cheaper but great A-Series phones, cutting a few features to cost £100 (US$99) – a full £80 cheaper than their predecessors.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Samuel Gibbs Consumer technology editor</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maker Spotlight: Michael Albert]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/18/maker-spotlight-michael-albert/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/18/maker-spotlight-michael-albert/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-18T15:30:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[First and last name Michael Albert Where are you located?  White Plains, New York What is your day job?  Pop Artist/Owner of Sir Real brand of Natural Foods Do you attend a makerspace/fablab/hackerspace?  Not usually, but I’m looking forward to the Mead Library’s Maker Faire Sheboygan this weekend. Website | Pinterest | Art site What […]
The post Maker Spotlight: Michael Albert appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[17 Best Ground Cover Plants That Grow Well In The Shade]]></title>
        <id>https://getbusygardening.com/?p=34012</id>
        <link href="https://getbusygardening.com/shade-ground-covers/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T17:36:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shade ground covers make an excellent addition to low light areas. Whether you’re looking for something that can take light foot traffic, or simply want to cover the soil in your shade garden, you’ll find lots of options in this list. Ground cover plants are a simple way to add beauty to your shade garden.Continue Reading
The post 17 Best Ground Cover Plants That Grow Well In The Shade appeared first on Get Busy Gardening.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Amy Andrychowicz</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Where to Get Started in Digital Sculpting for 3D Printing]]></title>
        <id>https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/where-to-get-started-in-digital-sculpting-for-3d-printing/</id>
        <link href="https://makezine.com/2021/06/17/where-to-get-started-in-digital-sculpting-for-3d-printing/"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T15:44:08.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Digital sculpting isn’t as hard as it looks. At least, getting started isn’t that hard. You’ll still have to put in some serious time to get GOOD, but don’t let that scare you off. You may be surprised by how easily you can get something to be proud of, even as an absolute beginner. There […]
The post Where to Get Started in Digital Sculpting for 3D Printing appeared first on Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers.]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Make: DIY Projects and Ideas for Makers</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[How remote work opened the floodgates to ransomware]]></title>
        <id>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/17/ransomware-working-from-home-russia</id>
        <link href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2021/jun/17/ransomware-working-from-home-russia"/>
        <updated>2021-06-17T10:00:31.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[With workers outside the ‘castle walls’ of their companies, criminals have it easier – and cryptocurrency hasn’t helped
Ransomware has roared into the headlines in recent weeks after criminal hacking networks, tentatively linked to Russia, launched attacks on the major US meat packing plant JBS and the nation’s largest fuel pipeline. 
Joe Biden and his administration are scrambling to address the growing threat, pressing Vladimir Putin in a highly anticipated meeting on Wednesday to take action against the rise of ransomware attacks. Biden said he gave Putin a list of 16 areas – mostly in critical infrastructure - that are “off limits” for cyber-attacks.
 Continue reading...]]></summary>
        <author>
            <name>Kari Paul</name>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>